<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>vrmmo on Samuel Hinton</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tags/vrmmo/</link><description>Recent content in vrmmo on Samuel Hinton</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tags/vrmmo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A review of K.T. Hanna's 'Somnia Online'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/somnia/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/somnia/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m writing this review as of reading the first three books. I&amp;rsquo;ll update it when I finish the series at a later date.
Somnia Online follows the journey of Wren, her best friend Harlow, and their guild, Fable. The premise, at the start, is simple. Wren&amp;rsquo;s mother is the lead designer for a massive vrmmo game, which offers unparalleled immersive via a headset which reads your brainwaves. Except, of course, the game is really just a test bed for the development for the games AI and the headset technology, which is funded by the military.</description></item><item><title>A Review of Travis Bagwell's Awaken Online. A necromancer MC games the system as much as he can.</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/awaken_online/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/awaken_online/</guid><description>Disclaimer: the thoughts in this review come from reading the first seven books of the series. The series is ongoing.
To kick things off, if you like overpowered main characters and don&amp;rsquo;t mind game systems or balances that blatantly favour the protagonist, you&amp;rsquo;ll enjoy this series a lot.
If you&amp;rsquo;re on the fence, I&amp;rsquo;d highly recommend reading at least the first book. It&amp;rsquo;s definitely the best of the ones that I&amp;rsquo;ve read so far.</description></item></channel></rss>