<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Samuel Hinton</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/</link><description>Recent content on Samuel Hinton</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cosmiccoding.com.au/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Review of Will Wight's Cradle Series: The King of Progression Fantasy</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/cradle/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/cradle/</guid><description>Cradle is going to be tough to write a review for, because I don&amp;rsquo;t want to sound too biased, despite my love for the series.
I&amp;rsquo;ll focus upon the first few books here (Unsouled, Soulsmith, Blackflame) and try to keep spoilers for the rest of the series locked away in my heart.
The story follows a young man hailing from one of the clans of Sacred Valley. This is Lindon. He is, shall we say, unfairly treated by the clan, who believes he has no aptitude for the spiritual arts.</description></item><item><title>A Review of nobody13's Mother of Learning. Time loops with a smart protagonist, done so very, very right.</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/mother_of_learning/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/mother_of_learning/</guid><description>I grew up on the Belgariad, graduated through Harry Potter to the Wheel of Time, conquered Malazan, was crushed by the Farseer Trilogy, and generally docked my ship at every fantasy port I could find.
Then I was recommended to read Mother of Learning. It was my first serial novel. And despite its 800k words, I read it in a week.
And then I read it again.
So many books I&amp;rsquo;ve read fumble the ending or the rising tension.</description></item><item><title>A Review of Bryce O'Connor's Iron Prince. Scifi progression on actual digital steroids."</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/iron_prince/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/iron_prince/</guid><description>I normally approach scifi with skepticism. I studied astrophysics, and physics is a harsh mistress that is all to easy to try and abuse in works of science fiction. There&amp;rsquo;s one surefire way around this - magical tech. Or in this case, alien tech that is so advanced it might as well be magic. And with the soft scifi setting established, this allows Bryce to draw the best from fantasy, the best from LitRPG levelling, and combine them to make one of the best progression fantasy stories I have read in years.</description></item><item><title>A Review of Andrew Rowe's Arcane Ascension Series: hard magic done right</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/arcane_ascension/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/arcane_ascension/</guid><description>My rating is for the series as a whole as of writing. It&amp;rsquo;s amazing. I&amp;rsquo;ll make sure this review focuses on Book One: Sufficiently Advanced Magic.
Corin Cadence is one of my favourite main characters in all of fantasy. He is, as I image many of us think, how we would approach being a person in a magical world. Analytically. Carefully. Exploitively.
So here&amp;rsquo;s the plot - you get powers (attunements) ostensibly from the goddess, via blessings you receive in the spires.</description></item><item><title>Reflections on my own 'Soul Relic'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/soul_relic/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/soul_relic/</guid><description>Born with an enormous well of power but no way to regenerate it, Raysha will risk anything to fix herself, even if it means venturing into the unknown with nothing but her brother, an enchanted water bottle, and a stubborn attitude.
Without the ability to cultivate aeon from the world, Raysha has been treated like an outcast her whole life. While she has to ration her power drop-by-drop, others use it as commonly as breathing.</description></item><item><title>A Review of Phil Tucker's Bastion. It's great.</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/bastion/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/bastion/</guid><description>Many progression fantasy series start with a similar pattern. An unfortunate, downtrodden, or unlucky individual is wronged, usually in an academic or sect environment, and then they claw their way through the classes, pushing themselves into excellence.
Bastion opens similarly, and I was preparing myself for a bit of &amp;lsquo;more of the same&amp;rsquo;. When the Chancellor starts explaining a points system for Academic progression through the Gauntlet (aka dungeon / spire / magical testing realm) a spark of worry lit inside me.</description></item><item><title>A Review of John Bierce's Mage Errant Series. A fun ride with a likeable cast.</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/mage_errant/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/mage_errant/</guid><description>This review focuses on first volume. As of writing I&amp;rsquo;ve read all five released books and those flavour my opinion.
Hugh of Emblin is both a horrific and talented student at Skyhold Academy.
He is anxious, I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure he is depressed, and ultimately he is just not vibing about the state of the world and his own abilities.
Luckily, he has some great friends to help pick him up and support him.</description></item><item><title>A review of J.M. Clarke's 'Mark of the Fool'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/mark_of_the_fool/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/mark_of_the_fool/</guid><description>As of writing this review, I have read the KU release and up to chapter 200, which is about half-way through the available chapters.
So here&amp;rsquo;s the premise: Alex Roth is one of five chosen Heroes that need to defeat a reoccurring villain: The Ravener. Alex, however, is the Fool. His Mark, instead of making him a combat savant, powerful spellcaster, etc, makes him really great at learning things that are outside of combat and spellcasting&amp;hellip; but will actively interfere with his abilities if they are not.</description></item><item><title>A review of Naomi Novik's Scholomance Series</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/scholomance/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/scholomance/</guid><description>I didn&amp;rsquo;t expect to read a book from the perspective of an emotional teenage girl and love every page.
And yet, here we are.
So, premise time. In this world, there are magical people, and not magical people (they&amp;rsquo;re not called muggles though). Raising a magical kid is hard, because there are a whole host of creatures, called maleficaria (or mals) which love that sweet mana inside the kids, and will eat them all up.</description></item><item><title>A Review of Matt Dinniman's Dungeon Crawler Carl. Officially my favourite LitRPG.</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/dungeon_crawler_carl/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/dungeon_crawler_carl/</guid><description>Dungeon Crawler Carl opens with something reminiscent of Hitchhiker&amp;rsquo;s Guide to the Galaxy. Earth is being mined for minerals, and those that survived the initial population purge become participants in the universe&amp;rsquo;s most popular show, as they progress through a deadly dungeon run by an insane AI to either try and survive or beat the dungeon and win back their planet.
Now that is a fun premise.
Carl enters the dungeon with Princess Donut, a prize-winning cat.</description></item><item><title>A review of Sarah Lin's 'The Weirkey Chronicles'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/weirkey/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/weirkey/</guid><description>As of writing this, I have read all five released books, and will be picking up the next whenever it comes out!
Our MC, Theo, has spent decades searching for a way back into the magical realms of the Nine Worlds. After a bitter life with no success, he eventually finds his way back, only to confront the fact that the ideals of his younger self are only a distant memory to the man he now is.</description></item><item><title>A review of Rob J. Hayes' 'Titan Hoppers'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/titan_hoppers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/titan_hoppers/</guid><description>Blurb Courage Iro will shatter the Gates of Power to protect his fleet.
Born talentless, Iro has all but resigned himself to a life of drudgery, watching his sister hop across to the massive space titan for supplies. But when the titan explodes and his sister is killed, Iro finds a new determination to take her place. He’s not about to let weakness prevent him.
When the fleet encounters a new titan, filled with powerful monsters, deadly traps, and mysterious cloaked figures, Iro is the first to spontaneously manifest a new talent.</description></item><item><title>A review of J.R. Mathews's 'Portal to Nova Roma'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/nova_roma/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/nova_roma/</guid><description>Blurb To find peace, Alexander must first embrace war.
After tragically losing the only person he ever cared about, Alexander, a rogue artificial intelligence, opens a portal to an alternate dimension to escape his grief.
Scanning trillions of different dimensions, Alexander finally finds a world that is reminiscent of the only time he was ever happy, back when he could play virtual reality games with his only friend. He doesn&amp;rsquo;t know why, or how, such a world exists, but he doesn&amp;rsquo;t care.</description></item><item><title>A Review of CasualFarmer's Cultivation novel 'Beware of Chicken'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/beware_of_chicken/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/beware_of_chicken/</guid><description>As of writing this review, I have read all 212 published chapters on Royal Road.
I saw this series recommended a few times on various groups and subreddits, but I always put it off because the name of the series didn&amp;rsquo;t exactly give me details about what it was about. The tidal wave of support for the work pushed me over the edge, so I picked it up&amp;hellip; and it turns out that was a great decision.</description></item><item><title>A Review of J. R. Mathews's 'Jakes Magical Market', a fun LitRPG apocalypse romb with a card based system.</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/jakes_magical_market/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/jakes_magical_market/</guid><description>Before I picked up this book, I must have seen Jake&amp;rsquo;s Magical Market recommended a dozen times on the /r/ProgressionFantasy subreddit. It even got a shoutout from Bryce O&amp;rsquo;Connor, and then, after about ten more people told me to read it, I pulled the trigger, added it to my Kindle, and then I read the entire thing&amp;mdash;all eight hundred pages&amp;mdash;in a single weekend.
So yeah, I thought it was pretty good.</description></item><item><title>A review of Rhaegar's 'Azarinth Healer'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/azarinth_healer/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/azarinth_healer/</guid><description>Blurb Ilea likes punching things. And eating.
Unfortunately, there aren’t too many career options for hungry brawlers. Instead, the plan is to quit her crappy fast-food job, go to college, and become a fully functioning member of society. Essentially - a fate worse than death.
So maybe it&amp;rsquo;s lucky that she wakes up one day in a strange world where a bunch of fantasy monsters are trying to kill her&amp;hellip;?</description></item><item><title>A review of Striker's 'Virtuous Sons'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/virtuous_sons/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/virtuous_sons/</guid><description>Blurb Lio Aetos is the Young Aristocrat and heir apparent to a legendary Greek sect, a prodigious talent born and bred for glory.
Solus is a slave, a disgraced patrician from the fallen city of Rome with nothing to his name.
They&amp;rsquo;re as different as the East is from the West. Yet both of them hunger—to cast off the threads of Fate they’ve been given. To reach for a higher purpose.</description></item><item><title>A review of RavensDagger's 'Cinnamon Bun'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/cinnamon_bun/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/cinnamon_bun/</guid><description>As readers of this genre know, LitRPG worlds can be a depressing, harrowing, and cut-throat place. Half of the MC&amp;rsquo;s I&amp;rsquo;ve read in other works get ahead because this suits them just fine. They&amp;rsquo;re happy to fight, happy to get their hands dirty, happy to shake the system up. In many ways, that&amp;rsquo;s part of the escapism. Having power.
Cinnamon Bun has a slightly different take. The world is less apocalyptic in fashion, and our main character, Broccoli Bunch, just wants to go on cool adventures and make friends.</description></item><item><title>A review of Alec Huston's 'Umbral Storm'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/umbral_storm/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/umbral_storm/</guid><description>Blurb A thousand years ago the Heart of the World was shattered, its fragments scattered across the lands. In the chaos that followed, martial orders arose to gather these shards, for it was found that great powers were granted when these pieces were bonded to the flesh of the chosen. These are the Sharded Few, warriors imbued with the divine energies that once coursed through the Heart, and driven to absorb enough fragments to claim godhood.</description></item><item><title>A review of Harmon Cooper's 'The World According to Dragons'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/the_world_according_to_dragons/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/the_world_according_to_dragons/</guid><description>Blurb An infamous relic hunter. A legendary dragon. The journey of a lifetime.
Twillo lies bleeding out in a volcanic desert. Towering over him is a snarling red wolf, death only seconds away.
Right as his vision is going black, a mysterious voice offers Twillo a chance at survival.
Do you agree to bind souls?
It is the voice of a dragon, one that hasn&amp;rsquo;t been seen for hundreds of years.</description></item><item><title>A review of Davis Ashura's 'The Eternal Ephemera'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/eternal_ephemera/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/eternal_ephemera/</guid><description>As of writing this review, I have read Blood of a Novice, and received a copy as an ARC reader.
Blurb Cam Folde will shake the very fabric of creation&amp;hellip; or see all his hopes turn to ash.
The son of the town drunk, Cam never figured on letting his family name hold him down. He always strove to dream bigger, to fight for something better, to achieve more than what everyone else expected of him.</description></item><item><title>A Review of Tobias Begley's progression fantasy work 'The Enchanter'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/enchanter/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/enchanter/</guid><description>Let&amp;rsquo;s get the obvious out the way and let me expand on the description above. If you&amp;rsquo;ve read the Arcane Ascension series and loved Corin&amp;rsquo;s approach to life, just save yourself some time, click the amazon link above, and go and get this book. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t, but you&amp;rsquo;ve read Mother of Learning and appreciated Zorian there, same comment.
Alright, let&amp;rsquo;s start with a spoiler-free summary. Our MC, Evander Tailor, is gifted.</description></item><item><title>A Review of Andrew Rowes's How to Defeat a Demon King in Ten Easy Steps. Hilarious love letter to Zelda.</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/how_to_defeat_a_demon_king_in_ten_easy_steps/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/how_to_defeat_a_demon_king_in_ten_easy_steps/</guid><description>Let&amp;rsquo;s preface this real quick: this book is a short and fun read. It is not a sweeping fantasy series, it is not a classic zero-to-hero progression fantasy. It is a love letter to Zelda and other games, making fun of many video game tropes by highlighting just how ridiculous and obvious many are.
The main character finds a way to inventively use their class (A Bag Mage) to break various game systems.</description></item><item><title>A review of T.J. Reynold's 'Seventh Bridge to the Heavens'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/seventh_bridge_to_the_heavens/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/seventh_bridge_to_the_heavens/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m writing this review after reading book one, I&amp;rsquo;ll grab book two once it&amp;rsquo;s out and update this page.
For those wanting to get straight into action and cultivation, don&amp;rsquo;t skip over this book. The first small arc sets up the main character, the world, and the cultures in it wonderfully.
The story follows the Quiet Luca, a soldier whose core didn&amp;rsquo;t awaken, who served in the squad of stone-bending cultivators.</description></item><item><title>A review of Maxime J. Durand's 'The Perfect Run'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/perfect_run/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/perfect_run/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a quite a few years since the Alchemist distributed Elixirs into the world, each which grant a unique super power. Since then, modern civilisation has collapsed, because giving some people phenomenal power tends to go badly a lot of the time. Quicksave begins the book searching for his childhood friend, Len, and determined to go through every chapter in his life with a perfect run. Which, as you might have guessed from the hero name, is possible thanks to his ability to set a checkpoint in time he can revert to on death.</description></item><item><title>A Review of Dakota Krout's Completionist Chronicles and Ritualist from a grumpy LitRPG reader</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/completionist_chronicles/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/completionist_chronicles/</guid><description>Completionist Chronicles is set in the same universe as Divine Dungeon. Or more so, it&amp;rsquo;s set inside the Dungeon, with a weird tie into modern-day Earth. I&amp;rsquo;ll focus this write-up on the first book, Ritualist.
Let&amp;rsquo;s get that out of the way - the book has a weird opening. It&amp;rsquo;s the end of the world, and President Elon [Musk] encourages everyone to start a new life in a new world before vanishing into thin air (transported into the dungeon&amp;rsquo;s constructed LitRPG world).</description></item><item><title>A review of J.L. Mullins' 'Millenium Mage'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/millenium_mage/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/millenium_mage/</guid><description>As of writing this review, I&amp;rsquo;ve read all 224 published chapters.
Blurb The world is wild, untamed. Humanity thrives, but only in isolated, well defended cities, ever shrinking as the wilds slowly reclaim all that was taken. The most capable magic users are raised up as Mages to serve mankind, further their cause, and defend them over the course of millennia.
Tala is freshly graduated from the magic academy and determined to make her own way in the world.</description></item><item><title>A review of Michael G. Manning's 'Art of the Adept'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/art_of_the_adept/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/art_of_the_adept/</guid><description>What a roller coaster this read was. Our plot follows Will, who awakens his magic when healing a young boys infection. He is sent to live with his grandfather (of sorts), who becomes a slow and painful magical tutelage, laced with acerbic dialogue and insults around every corner. The dynamic between the two is a joy to read. Eventually, the plot moves on, Will has to spread his wings. As to why, and when, and how, I won&amp;rsquo;t say, because it all falls under spoiler territory.</description></item><item><title>A Review of C. Mantis' 'The Path of Ascension', a sci-fi wuxia novel with a staggering range of powers and power divides.</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/path_ascension/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/path_ascension/</guid><description>This was another read courtesy of recommendations from /r/ProgressionFantasy. It&amp;rsquo;s only on Royal Road (at the time of writing), but I hope it reaches a wider audience soon when the author has a chance to go back and package it all up nicely.
The Path of Ascension follows the journey of our tragically orphaned MC, Matt. Matt&amp;rsquo;s parents were killed in a rift break. If you&amp;rsquo;ve read Solo Levelling or many other rift/portal/dunegon based novels, this is fairly standard.</description></item><item><title>A review of KamikazePotato's 'An Outcast In Another World'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/outcast_in_another_world/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/outcast_in_another_world/</guid><description>This review was written after I had read all three published books. I&amp;rsquo;m waiting on the Kindle version instead of reading on RR so I can give the author my money.
If you liked HWFWM, Defiance of the Fall, Primal Hunter, or Randidly, you&amp;rsquo;ll like this series.
Initially, I was worried when the starting chapters felt very close to both DoT and Primal Hunter. Young white man in a forest with dangerous beasts&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;ve read that few too many times for it to still hold the magic it originally held with me.</description></item><item><title>A review of Momo's 'Martial Peak'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/martial_peak/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/martial_peak/</guid><description>As of writing this review, I have read &amp;gt;1500 chapters of the manhua.
Blurb The journey to the martial peak is a lonely, solitary and long one. In the face of adversity, you must survive and remain unyielding. Only then can you break through and continue on your journey to become the strongest. Sky Tower tests its disciples in the harshest ways to prepare them for this journey. One day the lowly sweeper Yang Kai managed to obtain a black book, setting him on the road to the peak of the martial world.</description></item><item><title>A review of Zamil Akhtar's Lightblade</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/lightblade/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/lightblade/</guid><description>Disclosure: I received this book in advance and without cost in exchange for an honest review. Counter-disclosure: I already pay for KU, so I would have been able to read it for &amp;lsquo;free&amp;rsquo; anyway.
Initially, the premise of this book seemed super intense. Lightblades obviously give you some Star Wars vibes, the magic system is focused around different wavelengths of light, which gives me Lightbringer vibes, and then the focus on dreams, time-dilation, and the existential question &amp;ldquo;Is this the real world&amp;rdquo; combine Inception and the Matrix.</description></item><item><title>A review of K.T. Hanna's 'Somnia Online'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/somnia/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/somnia/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m writing this review as of reading the first three books. I&amp;rsquo;ll update it when I finish the series at a later date.
Somnia Online follows the journey of Wren, her best friend Harlow, and their guild, Fable. The premise, at the start, is simple. Wren&amp;rsquo;s mother is the lead designer for a massive vrmmo game, which offers unparalleled immersive via a headset which reads your brainwaves. Except, of course, the game is really just a test bed for the development for the games AI and the headset technology, which is funded by the military.</description></item><item><title>A Review of Noret Flood's 'The Legend of Randidly Ghosthound', a great take on system takeover LitRPG.</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/randidly_ghosthound/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/randidly_ghosthound/</guid><description>Note: I&amp;rsquo;ve read the Amazon Book One, and then Royal Road chapters up to around Chapter 300 (ie many books worth). This review uses all of the content I&amp;rsquo;ve read, but I&amp;rsquo;ll make sure to separate book vs royal road if you&amp;rsquo;re thinking of buying. Actually, scrap that, just buy the first book, its great, and then continue on RR if you want.
So let&amp;rsquo;s begin with the basic premise. Earth is taken over by the System, and it becomes an effective post-apocalypse LitRPG adventure, which is fairly normal for the genre.</description></item><item><title>A Review of Chris Fox's Shattered Gods series. A great new entry into progression fantasy.</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/shattered_gods/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/shattered_gods/</guid><description>In the book, you follow the adventures of Xal. Xal is a child of the dims, an oppressed group of people feared by the ruling class and used as cannon fodder. Xal gets conscripted and sent to tie in the trash legion, and the adventures of this legion, plus the Academy afterwards, show him progressing in power and being inducted into the wider political landscape, wherein he has very few friends and a great many enemies.</description></item><item><title>A Review of Dakota Krout's Divine Dungeon Series.</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/divine_dungeon/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/divine_dungeon/</guid><description>This is another series I&amp;rsquo;ve read which I got instantly hooked on with a great premise, only to feel a bit let down at the conclusion many books later.
That said, I&amp;rsquo;ve read this series more than once, so it must be doing something right!
The Divine Dungeon series was my introduction to dungeon-core novels, and for that, I thank you, Dakota Krout. What this means is you follow the development of a sentient dungeon rather than a human character for most of the series.</description></item><item><title>A review of J. McCoy's 'RE: Monarch'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/remonarch/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/remonarch/</guid><description>Blurb To save the kingdom, he&amp;rsquo;ll have to stop his own murder&amp;hellip;
It’s hard to be a drunken idiot when the world keeps burning down around you. Cairn, the charming-yet-utterly-irresponsible heir to the Uskarrion throne, is all too happy to toss the crown aside. But an invasion, conspiracy, and rise of a terrifying villain result in his untimely death.
Then, Cairn reawakens. It&amp;rsquo;s a decade earlier and he&amp;rsquo;s in his childhood body.</description></item><item><title>A Review of Jame A. Hunter's Rogue Dungeon. Light-hearted fun.</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/rogue_dungeon/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/rogue_dungeon/</guid><description>Review based on reading the first three books: Rogue Dungeon, Civil War, and Troll Nation.
Roark von Graf lives in a fantasy world, trying to overthrow a tyrant. By weird magic, he is teleported into an Earth video game into a troll&amp;rsquo;s body, and his goal is to get back to his world with enough power to overthrow the tyrant.
It&amp;rsquo;s a weird premise, having the MC not be a normal Earthman, but still having them inhabit an Earth video game where player characters are regular people.</description></item><item><title>A Review of Travis Bagwell's Awaken Online. A necromancer MC games the system as much as he can.</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/awaken_online/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/awaken_online/</guid><description>Disclaimer: the thoughts in this review come from reading the first seven books of the series. The series is ongoing.
To kick things off, if you like overpowered main characters and don&amp;rsquo;t mind game systems or balances that blatantly favour the protagonist, you&amp;rsquo;ll enjoy this series a lot.
If you&amp;rsquo;re on the fence, I&amp;rsquo;d highly recommend reading at least the first book. It&amp;rsquo;s definitely the best of the ones that I&amp;rsquo;ve read so far.</description></item><item><title>A Review of Shirtaloon's He Who Fights With Monsters, a great LitRPG with an opinionated protagonist.</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/hwfwm/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/hwfwm/</guid><description>Jason, our MC, is simultaneously this series greatest strengths and greatest weakness.
Transported to a magical world, Jason is thrown into some truly unfortunate circumstances right off the bat. Weirdly there&amp;rsquo;s very little detail given about Jason and his past life, apart from a few vague comments about it not exactly being ideal (I mean, he was Australian, just like me, so points for that), but there&amp;rsquo;s no time to dwell on that as Jason struggles to survive against a host of organisations, beasts, and eventually eldritch horrors.</description></item><item><title>A Review of Zogarth's LitRPG 'The Primal Hunter'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/primal_hunter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/primal_hunter/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m just going to come out and say it. If you&amp;rsquo;ve read Defiance of the Fall and enjoyed it, you will love The Primal Hunter. It has a similar premise, similar (minimal) base-building and progression, but with better characters and less deus ex machina.
Now, to be fair, the author gets away with a lot on the social side of characterisation by making the main character incredibly anti-social, and then befriending a pair of (sentient) birds.</description></item><item><title>A review of Benjamin Kerei's 'Oh Great! I was Reincarnated as a Farmer'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/reincarnated_as_a_farmer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/reincarnated_as_a_farmer/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m writing this review after reading book one, I&amp;rsquo;ll grab book two once it&amp;rsquo;s out and update this page.
The premise of the book is fairly simple. Through some unfortunate accident, the MC (Arnold) is taken from Earth and his job as a semi-pro gamer, and reincarnated in the body of a farmer. The world has levels and a class based system (without it being a &amp;lsquo;capital S&amp;rsquo; system), and classes can&amp;rsquo;t be changed.</description></item><item><title>A Review of Sarah Lin's The Brightest Shadow - great subversion of a genre trope.</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/brightest_shadow/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/brightest_shadow/</guid><description>Disclaimer: the thoughts in this review come from reading only the first book of the series. I have not read &amp;lsquo;A Hollow Mountain&amp;rsquo;, yet.
I enjoyed the read of The Brightest Shadow a few weeks ago during my end of year holiday. I&amp;rsquo;d been slowly making my way through the novel for a month or so before that, as I initially struggled with the slower pacing of the work. In that way, it reminds me a lot of A Thousand Li (in that I struggled with the slice-of-life plodding along).</description></item><item><title>A Review of Andrew Seiple's Threadbare. Adorable, unique, and fascinating.</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/threadbare/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/threadbare/</guid><description>This review focuses on the trilogy as a whole, not subsequent entries.
I will admit to some skepticism when I read the original premise - the main character is a stuffed bear.
But, in a fit of whimsy, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d give it a shot.
This was, as it turns out, a wonderful decision.
Threadbare follows the journey of the eponymous bear&amp;rsquo;s quest to try and find and save the daughter of his creator and his best friend - Cecelia Gearheart.</description></item><item><title>A Review of Yrsillar's Forge of Destiny</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/forge_of_destiny/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/forge_of_destiny/</guid><description>Forge of Destiny starts like many cultivation novels. Plucky young girl from the streets, Ling Qi, has the talent and joins the Sect of Argent Peak. She then struggles to rise up in the inner rankings of the Sect. It has your normal progression systems, spiritual pills, removing impurities, it has moves and techniques, a vide cast of characters, but at the end of the day I wasn&amp;rsquo;t drawn in.</description></item><item><title>A Review of 'Defiance of the Fall', a system-apocalypse LitRPG / cultivation hybrid.</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/defiance_of_the_fall/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/defiance_of_the_fall/</guid><description>As of the time of writing this review, I have read all four books on KU, and a further 200 chapters on RR, up to and including the time skip.
So Defiance of the Fall did hook me in, and the author is great at leaving each chapter with a teaser, cliffhanger, or something to get you thinking &amp;ldquo;Okay, just one more.&amp;rdquo; It had the same vibes as when I&amp;rsquo;m playing Civilisation, and it&amp;rsquo;s why I ended up reading several million words before I put the story down.</description></item><item><title>A review of Michael Nwanolue's 'The Tower Unbroken'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/tower_unbroken/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/tower_unbroken/</guid><description>I do like me a good cultivation story, and so when I asked for some recommendations and someone pointed out that there is a little-known work featuring African-inspired cultivation, I put it to the top of my list.
And here we are!
The Tower Unbroken follows Somadina&amp;rsquo;s journey from his village out into the wider world. He starts off as the lowliest rank of cultivator, or dibias as they are called in this setting.</description></item><item><title>A physicist reviews Dominic Stal's 'The Last Physicist'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/last_physicist/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/last_physicist/</guid><description>For those coming here from reddit or similar, I&amp;rsquo;ll come clean. I had high expectations for this book. As a physicist myself, a book about a physicist using the scientific method to put some hard rules to magic and delve into the mechanics had me almost giddy with excitement. So I dove into this book, and, I&amp;rsquo;ll be frank, came away disappointed.
The book follows the MC, Will. In another fun coincidence, Will works at Fermilab in Chicago.</description></item><item><title>A review of Samer Rabadi's 'Eight'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/eight/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/eight/</guid><description>Blurb Life’s tough when you’re trapped in an eight-year-old body on another world.
His name is Eight. Not really, but that’s what the System decided after a slip of the tongue. One moment, he was stepping out the office door on the way home, and the next waking up on a hillside below a town wall. Oh, and the gate guard drove him off, because he thought Eight was a monster.</description></item><item><title>Tao Wong's A Thousand Li - classical cultivation doled out sparingly</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/thousand_li/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/thousand_li/</guid><description>Disclaimer: Due to Tao Wong filing infringement notices against LitRPG authors for using &amp;ldquo;System&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Apocalypse&amp;rdquo;, I&amp;rsquo;m not continuing with this series. There are plenty of authors who add positively to this community that I can support instead of someone who tries to tear it down.
I had heard great things about this series, and A Thousand Li is a staple on the cultivation and progression fantasy reading lists. So take this review with a grain of salt, that obviously my take here may not be reflective of the wider community.</description></item><item><title>A Review of Chugong's Solo Levelling - an engaging take on the genre.</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/solo_levelling/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/solo_levelling/</guid><description>Note: this review is based off the novel. I have heard the manhua doesn&amp;rsquo;t have many of the issues I&amp;rsquo;ve pointed out and recommend reading that instead.
Here&amp;rsquo;s the rough premise of Solo Levelling. The world was all normal, but now dungeon gates open, and teams of hunters have to enter, clear the dungeon and kill its boss. This will ensure the gates close. If they don&amp;rsquo;t close it in a week, the dungeon monsters can escape.</description></item><item><title>A Review of Brent Weeks' Lightbringer Series. Such a promising beginning with such an awful ending.</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/lightbringer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/lightbringer/</guid><description>This review will have some light spoilers.
The first three books of this series were amazing. Watching Kip, our main character, be bought from his destroyed village to the Chromeria, train with the Blackguard, develop his chromaturgy fantastic. Watching Gavin* build the Brightwater Wall in the face of the oncoming army of the Color Prince, gripping. Koios White Oak and her growth out of the Blackguard, superb.
The world-building was unique, deep enough to engage, but simple enough to grasp quickly.</description></item><item><title>A Review of Aleron Kong's Chaos Seeds Series: A tale of the luckiest man in the world</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/chaos_seeds/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/chaos_seeds/</guid><description>Is the Chaos Seeds series a fun read?
For sure.
Is it sensible? Is it serious? Is it consistent?
No.
If you don&amp;rsquo;t care about that and just want a light-hearted, fun read, maybe this series is for you.
Me, I thought that I don&amp;rsquo;t need anything series. Damn, I finished Malazan and I need a multi-year palate cleanser to get over the cauldron of tragedy in that series. However, I almost put down this series a few times.</description></item><item><title>A Review of Andries Louws' The Dao of Magic. A strange blend of pop references and ridiculously overpowered protagonists</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/dao_magic/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/dao_magic/</guid><description>I link to the Amazon publication, however, I read the Royal Road version. If there have been future substantial changes to the series since I read it, this review may not be accurate.
Drew, originally from Earth, has spent a thousand years or so cultivating on another world. He goes to ascend, but, oh no, something goes wrong, and he is send to a different world instead, to start from scratch.</description></item><item><title>DataFrame filtering with chaining</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tutorials/filter_chaining/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tutorials/filter_chaining/</guid><description>If you&amp;rsquo;re like me, breaking a nice method chain to do filtering is annoying.
You might have a nice long list of operations, and then interupt it like so:
df = ( df_raw.set_index(&amp;#34;A&amp;#34;) .sort_index() .unstack() .groupby(&amp;#34;B&amp;#34;) .mean() ) df = df[df[&amp;#34;C&amp;#34;] == &amp;#34;some_value&amp;#34;] df = df.join(df2).reset_index() I&amp;rsquo;m a simple man, and I just want everything in a single chain!
Yes, in the trivial example above, you could just move the indexor into the chain, but what if you need to filter based a value in the dataframe at that instant, not in the raw dataframe?</description></item><item><title>Scion of Storms Art</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/darian_nexus/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/darian_nexus/</guid><description>I commissioned a settings piece from the amazing Richard Lay and I cannot stress how amazing it is.
Hosting it here so you can grab a higher resolution version if you want it than will be in the Kindle publication.</description></item><item><title>Cover Animations</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/cover_animations/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/cover_animations/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve wanted to animate my book cover for a while, but unsure about the best way to go about it. Some websites claim to do it for you using AI, but you have to pay for access, and are they good? Others offer it as a service, but prices range from $10USD into the hundreds, so would an expensive animation be worth the investment? Is there any real difference in what you&amp;rsquo;d get?</description></item><item><title>RoyalRoad Data Infographic</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tutorials/royalroad/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tutorials/royalroad/</guid><description>For those reading this, I assume you know what Royal Road is. For those may have misclicked: it&amp;rsquo;s a website where authors publish web serials, generally a chapter at a time, and generally at a freakishly fast pace (like one chapter a day). It&amp;rsquo;s home to many greats in the Progression Fantasy / LitRPG genre, and I have spent hundreds of hours as a consumer of these serials.
So I decided to try and extract some insights from Royal Road data about how page count, followers, ratings, etc, impact the serials success and patreon conversion.</description></item><item><title>Scion of Storms Prologue</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/scion_of_storms_prologue/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/scion_of_storms_prologue/</guid><description>Manifestation, Book Two, is now in editing! To celebrate, I&amp;rsquo;m posting the prologue for all!
The Stormwall raged.
Lightning boomed from the black clouds above and thundered down into the gaping mouth of the maelstrom. An exposed claw of glass rising from the exposed seabed exploded as the strike connected.
Applicant Theolatos sat hidden on the floor of the ocean in a bubble of air held up solely by his will, undisturbed by the massive whirlpool only a stone&amp;rsquo;s throw away.</description></item><item><title>Lessons Learnt from Self Publishing</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/publishing_a_novel/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/publishing_a_novel/</guid><description>While writing up Soul Relic, I reached out to a lot of authors for their advice in getting the novel off the ground.
Thanks to John Bierce, Bryce O&amp;rsquo;Connor, Phil Tucker, J.R. Mathews, Tobias Begley, Travis M. Riddle, and everyone I&amp;rsquo;ve also pestered on reddit.
Some of this is obvious, others not as much. Here&amp;rsquo;s a rough timeline of how I would go about things if I had to start over.</description></item><item><title>Finding the best Wordle opening</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tutorials/wordle/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tutorials/wordle/</guid><description>Recently, I&amp;mdash;like many others&amp;mdash;have indulged in the Wordle competitions with friends. Which raised the question of how to open and ensure that I crushed all my mates with my vastly superior score.
So here we are. About to do an unneccessary but fun deep dive into Wordle words.
TL;DR If you care both about getting letters, and getting them in the right location, start with &amp;ldquo;lares&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;tares&amp;rdquo;.
If you try &amp;ldquo;lares&amp;rdquo; and get nothing, try &amp;ldquo;tonic&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;point&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Soul Relic Prologue</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/soul_relic_prologue/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/soul_relic_prologue/</guid><description>Set on the continent of Rhodus, the Soul Relic series follows Raysha as she grapples with her broken soul and inability to effectively channel the spiritual force of aeon. In a world where those who advance in the spiritual arts enough are regarded as gods, living without this ability means living at the bottom of society.
Not a place Raysha wants to remain.
Atareus looked down at the god weeping piteously by his feet.</description></item><item><title>The Continent of Rhodus</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/rhodus/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/rhodus/</guid><description>The continent of Rhodus is the main setting for my work Soul Relic.
The story begins in Hayet village in the nation of Darius, which you can find in the lower-left corner of the map. This is still a work in progress, and I might tweak or change things as times go on.
The resolution is quite high, so feel free to zoom in if you have the touchscreen for it.</description></item><item><title>A weekend in Scotland</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/scotland/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/scotland/</guid><description>After many, many months in lockdown, Kirrilee and I managed to finally get away for a short break.
Given that country borders are still closed (and at this point we&amp;rsquo;re still waiting for a vaccine) the options were fairly limited. However, Scotland has been on both of our lists for a long time, so we decided to head up North and visit the Isle of Skye.
After a long train to Edinburg we picked up a rental car and start the rush to our AirBnB before it got completely dark.</description></item><item><title>Merging dicts with the union operator</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tutorials/union_operators/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tutorials/union_operators/</guid><description>Merging two python dictionaries is a very common question on StackOverflow. Some of the better responses have been updated for later versions of Python, but I&amp;rsquo;ve seen this crop up a few times now to write it up here.
In Python 3.9+, merging two dictionaries is now staggeringly easy.
# New in Python 3.9 x = {&amp;#34;hello&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;there&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;general&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;kenobi&amp;#34;} y = {&amp;#34;general&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;potato&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;a&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;b&amp;#34;} z = x | y # z = {&amp;#39;hello&amp;#39;: &amp;#39;there&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;general&amp;#39;: &amp;#39;potato&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;a&amp;#39;: &amp;#39;b&amp;#39;} Notice that the order of preference is right to left.</description></item><item><title>Simple Multiprocessing in Python</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tutorials/multiprocessing/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tutorials/multiprocessing/</guid><description>In this short writeup I&amp;rsquo;ll give examples of various multiprocessing libraries, how to use them with minimal setup, and what their strengths are.
If you want a TL;DR - I recommend trying out loky for single machine tasks, check out Ray for larger tasks.
# Loky, great for single machine parallelism from loky import get_reusable_executor executor = get_reusable_executor() results = list(executor.map(fn, jobs)) # Ray, great for distributing over machines import ray ray.</description></item><item><title>Low Poly Art</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tutorials/lowpoly/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tutorials/lowpoly/</guid><description>So this is the goal for this tutorial - to turn a beautiful wallpaper (or three) into beautiful low poly art.
The approach we are going to take to get to this is fairly simple.
Load our image in Manipulate the image to highlight edges and areas of detail Draw potential vertices from those areas Calculate triangles from vertices Determine the colour of the triangles Plot the image Lets get our imports out of the way and then power through each section:</description></item><item><title>Genetic Algorithms 2: Painting Vermeer</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tutorials/genetic_part_two/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tutorials/genetic_part_two/</guid><description>This is what we&amp;rsquo;re going to make in this tutorial. Building on from the previous discussion in part one, we now add population and genetic mixing into the algorithm.
In the prior article we evolved a painting by the process of having a single organism that we mutated over time. We aim to improve this algorithm in this step by adding multiple different organisms into the population, and allowing those organisms to mate and produce offspring.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tutorials/genetic_part_one/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tutorials/genetic_part_one/</guid><description>This is what we&amp;rsquo;re going to make in this tutorial. It may not look like much, but then again, this is but the first step into genetic algorithms. If you&amp;rsquo;ve guessed that this is the Starry Night (or bothered to read the title, description or anything else), fantastic.
The idea behind Genetic Algorithms is simple - each algorithm can be evaluated to get its fitness, and algorithms are mutated, bred and culled, according to their performance.</description></item><item><title>Linear Regression Regularization Explained</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tutorials/linear_regression_regularisation/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tutorials/linear_regression_regularisation/</guid><description>In this small write up, I&amp;rsquo;ll be trying to fill a bit of a void I&amp;rsquo;ve seen online. That is, there are plenty of definitions of lasso, ridge, and elastic regularization, but most of them aren&amp;rsquo;t accompanied by useful examples showing when these terms become critically important! To address this, we&amp;rsquo;re going to look at regularization using three different use cases:
A perfect dataset! White noise on top of a direct linear relationship.</description></item><item><title>An Introduction to Gaussian Processes</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tutorials/gaussian_processes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tutorials/gaussian_processes/</guid><description>In this little write up, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore, construct and utilise Gaussian Processes for some simple interpolation models. The goal is - at the end - to know how they work under the hood, how they are trained, and how you can use them in weird and wonderful ways.
I&amp;rsquo;ll go through some basic interpolation, covariance and correlation concepts first. If they&amp;rsquo;re all familiar to you, scroll down the Gaussian Process section.</description></item><item><title>Principle Component Analaysis Explained</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tutorials/pca/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tutorials/pca/</guid><description>In this small write up, we&amp;rsquo;ll cover Principal Component Analysis from its mathematical routes, visual explanations and how to effectively utilise PCA using the sklearn library. We&amp;rsquo;ll show PCA works by doing it manually in python without losing ourself in the mathematics!
What is PCA? PCA is a way of taking a dataset (a collection of points in some parameter/feature space) and determining what are the &amp;ldquo;principal components&amp;rdquo;. These principal components represent vectors that encapsulate the information in your dataset.</description></item><item><title>Fuzzy String Matching</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tutorials/fuzzy_string_matching/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tutorials/fuzzy_string_matching/</guid><description>In this tweet, Steven Rich pointed out that Philadelphia is spelled at least 57 different ways in the PPP load data, and that this represents both a challenge to fix on the back-end, and a perfect example of why you should do as much work on the front-end to get better input.
In this write up, we&amp;rsquo;ll figure out an easy way of fixing up these spelling issues to produce a far better dataset to work on using the python library FuzzyWuzzy.</description></item><item><title>Visualising Patient Contributions for the CCCC</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tutorials/cccc_institutions/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tutorials/cccc_institutions/</guid><description>The COVID-19 Critical Care Consortium is an international collaboration of hundreds of hospital sites from dozens of countries around the world. Our sites have been slowly but steadily gathering data for critical cases of COVID-19 since earlier in the year, and we thought it would be good to show just how international the collaboration is.
To that end, in my role as one of the technical leads (responsible for the data pipeline and ingestion), I created out a simple (and no-risk) data product simply containing a list of our participant sites, and how many patients they have enrolled in our study at a given date.</description></item><item><title>Training a Neural Network Embedding Layer with Keras</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tutorials/encoding_colours/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tutorials/encoding_colours/</guid><description>This little write is designed to try and explain what embeddings are, and how we can train a naive version of an embedding to understand and visualise the process. We&amp;rsquo;ll do this using a colour dataset, Keras and good old-fashioned matplotlib.
Introduction Let&amp;rsquo;s start simple: What is an embedding?
An embedding is a way to represent some categorical feature (like a word), as a dense parameter. Specifically, this is normally a unit vector in a high dimensional hypersphere.</description></item><item><title>Gource - Visualisating Code Contributions</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tutorials/gource/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tutorials/gource/</guid><description>What is Gource? Gource is a way of visualising your git log, showing users and their contributions creating, modifying and deleting files. When run on my repository that was published under the name &amp;ldquo;Steve&amp;rdquo; (a Hierarchical Bayesian model for supernova cosmology&amp;quot;) and then piped through ffmpeg, this is what we get:
Using gource Its super easy, head to the gource website here and download the version for your operating system.</description></item><item><title>PR vs ROC Curves - Which to Use?</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tutorials/pr_vs_roc_curves/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tutorials/pr_vs_roc_curves/</guid><description>PR curves and ROC diagrams are presented everywhere in the machine learning sphere, and are often used relatively interchangably. In many cases, this is fine, because they are both providing information on the general question &amp;ldquo;How good is my classifier?&amp;rdquo;. But like many things which are often fine to do, there are cases where we&amp;rsquo;d want to specifically show either a PR or ROC curve.
So in the next few sections, we&amp;rsquo;ll generate a mock dataset, generate PR and ROC curves for them for two different classifiers, go into the definition of both of PR and ROC curves (both the intuition and mathematics), and then we&amp;rsquo;ll go how they subtly differ with another code example.</description></item><item><title>An Introduction to Logistic Regression</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tutorials/logistic_regression/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tutorials/logistic_regression/</guid><description>In this small write up, we&amp;rsquo;ll cover logistic functions, probabilities vs odds, logit functions, and how to perform logistic regression in Python.
Logistic regression is a method of calculating the probability that an event will pass or fail. That is, we utilise it for dichotomous results - 0 and 1, pass or fail. Is this patient going to survive or not? Is this email spam or not? This is specifically called binary logistic regression, and is important to note because we can do logistic regression in other contexts.</description></item><item><title>Introduction to Naive Bayes</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tutorials/naivebayes/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tutorials/naivebayes/</guid><description>Naive Bayes is a simple, extraordinarily fast, and incredibly useful categorical classification tool. The underlying crux of Naive Bayes is that we assume feature independence, plug it into Bayes theorem, and the math that falls out is incredibly simple.
The background math Let&amp;rsquo;s start with the famous Bayes Theorem:
$$ P(Y|X) = \frac{P(X|Y)P(Y)}{P(X)} $$
On the left hand side, we have the posterior: the probability of the output given the input.</description></item><item><title>Evolution of US COVID-19 cases</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tutorials/us_covid_evolution/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tutorials/us_covid_evolution/</guid><description>This plot was first inspired by this absolute masterpiece of a visualisation. I was chatting with David Morton about how much work it must have taken (coding up textures, exporting to blender, creating the model, rendering, compositing, loading back into code, annotating, so much work). David then went and created a python only version of the plot, and I decided I&amp;rsquo;d give it a crack too. We&amp;rsquo;ve used the same data, but the transformations, plotting and output are all different.</description></item><item><title>Which Big City has the best Weather?</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tutorials/us_weather/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tutorials/us_weather/</guid><description>Like many people, I might one day be moving to the United States for work. However, I would like to know where I should move too. Where is too hot? Where is it too wet? Where is my little slice of paradise??
This is what we&amp;rsquo;ll be making:
So using the NOAA Global Summary of the Day and the top 25 most populated cities in the US, we&amp;rsquo;ve got enough to make a plot.</description></item><item><title>Plotting US COVID-19 Incidence</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tutorials/us_covid19_growth/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tutorials/us_covid19_growth/</guid><description>One of my favourite subreddits is /r/dataisbeautiful. Today I saw a plot from that sub that was, on first glimpse, beautiful! And full credit to the author for getting the data and presenting it beautifully. However, I had some small issues with it. The first was that it was smoothing over a cumulative window (instead of showing what I think people expect, which is how many people caught COVID-19 on those dates).</description></item><item><title>Getting started with Boost, Python, and Numpy</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tutorials/boost/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tutorials/boost/</guid><description>As much as we might want all code that we work with to be professional-quality packages in the same language we are working in, it simply won&amp;rsquo;t be the case for the vast majority of us.
Recently, I was investigating how we could replace some perl wrappers that executed C code with something more pythonic. I came across boost - a package designed to try and make exposing C/C++ interfaces a bit simpler to python programs.</description></item><item><title>Monte-Carlo Integration made easy</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tutorials/monte_carlo_integration/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tutorials/monte_carlo_integration/</guid><description>Integrating a function is tricky. A lot of the time, the math is beyond us. Or beyond me, at the very least, and so I turn to my computer, placing the burden on its silent, silicon shoulders. And yet this isn&amp;rsquo;t the end of it, because there are a host of ways to perform numerical integration.
Do we want the simple rectangle rule? The superior trapezoidal rule? Simpson&amp;rsquo;s rule? Do we want to adaptively sample?</description></item><item><title>Datascience Pipelines</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/dsgo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/dsgo/</guid><description>Due to COVID-19 lots of conferences have moved online in 2020. DatascienceGo is one of those conferences, and I was invited to give a workshop on datascience pipelines. This invite comes off the back of some discussions and media about my role in the COVID-19 Critical Care Consortium and creating their data processing pipeline, which has been a challenging project.
For the workshop, I thought it best to try and generalise the content slightly, and instead of talking about all the different things you can do to data and the headaches we&amp;rsquo;ve had to deal with, to instead talk about machine learning and how you can add tracking and logging to your processes super simply using the amazing mlflow library.</description></item><item><title>A visual tutorial of Inversion Sampling</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tutorials/inversion_sampling/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tutorials/inversion_sampling/</guid><description>Inversion sampling is a simple and very efficient way to generate samples of some arbitrary probability function. Unlike rejection sampling, there are no rejected samples, and by leveraing common python libraries, we don&amp;rsquo;t even have to do any tricky integrals or function inversion.
$$ P(x) = 2 x $$
between 0 and 1. It just happens this does integrate to 1, what luck! Now, the CDF (cumulative distribution function) is the integral of the probability density function (what you see above), integrated from the lower bound - in our case the bounds are 0 to 1, so the CDF is</description></item><item><title>Handy Python Decorators</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tutorials/handy_python_decorators/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tutorials/handy_python_decorators/</guid><description>Decorators are something that are criminally underused in the analysis codes I have seen in academia. So, give me a few seconds to try and espouse their virtues. First, if you are new to decorators, how they work is simple: they are a function that returns a function which has wrapped another function. Simple!
It&amp;rsquo;s easier to explain in code.
def decorator(fn): def wrapper(*args, **kwargs): print(&amp;#34;Look, I&amp;#39;ve added something here!&amp;#34;) return fn(*args, **kwargs) return wrapper @decorator def add(a, b): return a + b add(1, 2) Look, I've added something here!</description></item><item><title>One Line Python Singletons</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tutorials/simple_singletons/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tutorials/simple_singletons/</guid><description>Singletons are the idea that you want to get an instance of a class, but you only ever want there to be a single instance of that class instantiated. A nice example might be a configuration class, or a coordinator class that is used by various pieces of you code, and you want to make sure that they&amp;rsquo;re all pointing to the same instance without having to pass the object around in eery invocation!</description></item><item><title>Removing Empty Columns</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tutorials/removing_empty_data/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tutorials/removing_empty_data/</guid><description>The sad reality of life as a data scientist is we spend too much time cleaning and processing data. And a lot of the time, our data contains some features which simply need to go in the bin. A column of 1000 values with only 2 entries is probably not going to be useful, after all. Let&amp;rsquo;s make some data to illustrate this:
import pandas as pd import numpy as np data = np.</description></item><item><title>Trivial One Hot Encoding in Python</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tutorials/one_hot_encoding/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tutorials/one_hot_encoding/</guid><description>One hot encoding is something we do very commonly in machine learning, where we want to turn a categorical feature into a vector of ones and zeros that algorithms can make much easier sense of.
For example, take this toy example dataframe of people and their favourite food. At the moment, it&amp;rsquo;s useless to us.
import pandas as pd df = pd.DataFrame({ &amp;#34;Person&amp;#34;: [&amp;#34;Sam&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;Ali&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;Jane&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;John&amp;#34;], &amp;#34;FavFood&amp;#34;: [&amp;#34;Pizza&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;Vegetables&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;Cake&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;Happiness&amp;#34;] }).</description></item><item><title>A visual tutorial of Rejection Sampling</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tutorials/rejection_sampling/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tutorials/rejection_sampling/</guid><description>Rejection sampling is the conceptually simplest way to generate samples of some arbitrary probability function without having to do any transformations. No integration, no trickery, you simply trade computational efficiency away to keep everything as simple as possible.
Let&amp;rsquo;s pick a super simple example: let&amp;rsquo;s say you want to sample from the function
$$ f(x) = 1.2 - x^4 $$
between 0 and 1. It just happens this does integrate to 1, what luck!</description></item><item><title>SDS Podcast - Pipelines</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/sds_pipelines/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/sds_pipelines/</guid><description>Shifting away from astrophysics briefly, I talk about my experience as a lead data analyst for the COVID-19 Critical Care Consortium, and my role with them to create a data pipeline to unify, standardise and merge data from a billion different forms across multiple research projects into something that actually has value for statistical analysis and machine learning.
Listen to the entire chat here, or grab the summary on pipelines from the (yet another) super pretty infographic below from the SDS team!</description></item><item><title>Science Friction</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/sciencefriction/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/sciencefriction/</guid><description>During the early days of the COVID-19 outburst I was recruited into the COVID-19 Critical Care Consortium (then called ECMOCARD) as the lead data analyst, responsible for setting up a data reduction and cleaning pipeline for the consortium, in addition to producing reports, graphs and dashboards for clinical staff and consortium members.
I had a chat with Natasha Mitchell about how this all came about, its relations to astronomy and more in an episode of Science Friction.</description></item><item><title>Forward Modelling for Supernova Cosmology</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tutorials/forwardmodelling/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tutorials/forwardmodelling/</guid><description>So in this example, I&amp;rsquo;m simply trying to demonstrate the viability of forward models with supernova cosmology. In this, I&amp;rsquo;ll be simplifying a lot, and in this case, ignoring proper treatment of uncertainty contributions from Monte-Carlo uncertainty. We&amp;rsquo;ll start with a simple model in which simulated supernova have redshift, magnitude and colour, apply selection effects, and ensure that we can recover input cosmology without having to resimulate by exploiting the fact that our selection effects operate in the observer frame of reference.</description></item><item><title>Barry: BAO Model Comparison</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/barry/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/barry/</guid><description>BAO models are a dime a dozen these days. With multiple theroetical frameworks to start from (standard perturbation theory, Lagranian perturbation theory, effective field theory, etc), and with different models implemented to account for different physical effects, the phase space of viable BAO models is huge.
And this poses a problem for those of us wanting to utilise BAO models. How do we effectively compare them and their performance on a robust set of numerical simulations?</description></item><item><title>A/B Test Significance in Python</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tutorials/abtests/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tutorials/abtests/</guid><description>Recently I was asked to talk about A/B tests for my Python for Statistical Analysis course. Given my travel schedule, leaving me bereft of my microphone, I thought it would be better to condense down A/B tests into a tutorial or two.
In this little write up, we&amp;rsquo;ll cover what an A/B test is, run through it in first principles with frequentist hypothesis testing, apply some existing scipy tests to speed the process up, and then at the end we&amp;rsquo;ll approach the problem in a Bayesian framework.</description></item><item><title>SDS Podcast - Hypothesis Testing</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/sds_hypothesis/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/sds_hypothesis/</guid><description>I like to rant about a lot of things. Many of those things include abuses of statistics, p-hacking, improper hypotheses and sensationalist media. Listen to the entire rant here, or grab the summary of how to formulate a proper hypothesis from the pretty infographic below!</description></item><item><title>Visualising with Basemap</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tutorials/desinstitutions/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tutorials/desinstitutions/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m scheduled to give a talk for the Dark Energy Survey - a massive collection of researchers, engineers and institutions working together to try and constrain the nature of Dark Energy. To help give my presentations some pizzaz, I thought it would be nice to visualise the spread of institutions around the world that makes DES the wonderful organisation that it is.
Wheres the data Unfortunately&amp;hellip; I had to collect it by hand.</description></item><item><title>Propagating (non-gaussian) uncertainty</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tutorials/propagating/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tutorials/propagating/</guid><description>You&amp;rsquo;ve fit a model to some data. You have some mean, covariance or samples characterising that fit, but now how can you clearly show the $1$ and $2\sigma$ confidence regions of this fit back onto your model. In other words, how do you get this sort of image back at the end:
Let&amp;rsquo;s run through a bunch of different ways, depending on how you&amp;rsquo;ve fit your model to the data. Firstly, let&amp;rsquo;s generate a model and some fake data to fit it with.</description></item><item><title>Space Birthdays</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/spacebirthdays/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/spacebirthdays/</guid><description>Click here to demo it. The Python in Astronomy 2019 conference was I think the best I&amp;rsquo;ve ever been to. Not because of the food or location, but because of the &amp;lsquo;unconference&amp;rsquo; sessions and the hacking that we get to do.
I wandered around during a lot of the hacks, spread between the code review hack, the MCMC exploration hack, attempting to get PRISM to run, and then also working with a group on getting a website to look at your space birthdays.</description></item><item><title>Bayesian Sample Selection Effects</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tutorials/sampleselectionbias/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tutorials/sampleselectionbias/</guid><description>In a perfect world our experiments would capture all the data that exists. This is not a perfect world, and we miss a lot of data. Let&amp;rsquo;s consider one method of accounting for this in a Bayesian formalism - integrating it out.
Let&amp;rsquo;s begin with a motivational dataset.
So it looks like for our example data, we&amp;rsquo;ve got some gaussian-like distribution of $x$ observations, but at some point it seems like our instrument is unable to pick up the observations.</description></item><item><title>Bayesian Linear Regression in Python</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tutorials/bayesianlinearregression/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tutorials/bayesianlinearregression/</guid><description>Bayesian linear regression is a common topic, but allow me to put my own spin on it. We&amp;rsquo;ll start at generating some data, defining a model, fitting it and plotting the results. It shouldn&amp;rsquo;t take long.
Generating Data Let&amp;rsquo;s start by generating some experimental data. For simplicity, let us assume some underlying process generates samples $f(x) = mx + c$ and our observations have some given Gaussian error $\sigma$.
import matplotlib.</description></item><item><title>LINO19</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/lindau/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/lindau/</guid><description>In the winter of 2019 I was one of the lucky students chosen to represent Australia and participate in the 2019 Lindau Nobel Laureates Meeting. The topics of the year were awesome - cosmology, gravitational waves and laser physics. What a lineup.
So here is the Australian contingent, in a very sunny lineup outside the meeting venue. We requested slight cloud cover. It was not supplied.
Inside, the hall was amazing.</description></item><item><title>SIEF Berlin</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/siefberlin/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/siefberlin/</guid><description>After the Lindau Nobel Laureate Meeting all the Australian delegates packed up shop, jumped on a train and headed to Berlin. It was time for our industry tour, courtesy of the Science and Industry Endowment Fund in Australia.
There&amp;rsquo;s one main takeaway here, its that actually providing proper funding to research has some amazing benefits.
I digress. I don&amp;rsquo;t have too much to say in here apart from how great it was to see so many labs in so many areas, all working towards scientific and technological progress.</description></item><item><title>Europe Strikes Back</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/europe2019/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/europe2019/</guid><description>The Zurich Introduction In a move which will surprise noone, we begin in Zurich. Unbeknown to us, it turns out that the very day we arrived in Zurich was the day they were hosting a gay pride march. Predictably, we found out about this at 5pm. After the march. Sigh.
But of course, once the official march ends, the real party begins, and there were concerts, a drag show, tons of food and general revelry.</description></item><item><title>Coding@Home</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/codingathome/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/codingathome/</guid><description>During the school shutdown during the COVID-19 outbreak in Australia, Education Queensland partnered with Channel 10 to produce the Coding@Home series - a series of episodes available for free on TenPlay about introducing code, concepts and all the ways you can use coding in your life.
I reached out about my experiences with coding in astrophysics, and we recorded a short segment focused on machine learning, and how it has improved the lives of the average astronomer by a huge amount.</description></item><item><title>Neural Style Transfer</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/ducky/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/ducky/</guid><description>I normally suck at giving presents. Horrifically. Probably because I&amp;rsquo;m a nightmare to buy for - I hate useless gifts. Ornaments, decorations&amp;hellip; &amp;ldquo;things&amp;rdquo; which aren&amp;rsquo;t functional.
It&amp;rsquo;s all clutter.
And because I don&amp;rsquo;t like receiving it, I don&amp;rsquo;t give it. Which means the struggle is always for a functional gift. But not this time! My sister has a cat called Ducky. Now, Ducky may not like me very much (breaks my heart), but Ali sure likes Ducky.</description></item><item><title>Pint of Science 2019</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/pint19/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/pint19/</guid><description>I did Pint of Science originally in 2017 and had a blast. For 2018, I was stranded on a beach in Fiji and unable to participate. But for 2019, I was all in!
And because the original talk seemed to go down so well, I decided to try and challenge myself a bit more by picking a topic far harder for a general audience to visualise. I decided to talk about Baryon Acoustic Oscillations - frozen sound waves in space.</description></item><item><title>Return to Cradle Mountain</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/tasmania_2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/tasmania_2/</guid><description>The last time I went to Tasmania I did the Overland track.
And I was not prepared. No water-proof gear, no thick jackets, just my stubbornness. Which, as it turns out, cannot keep you warm.
So this time I cam prepared. Totally waterproof jacket. A down jacket. A merinio wool jacket! All the stops. And it was worth it. From Hobart we drove to Wineglass bay, whic was a series of ups and down designed to swell your thighs to impressive sizes.</description></item><item><title>Steve: A model for supernova cosmology</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/steve/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/steve/</guid><description>As surveys discover greater numbers of supernova, our analyses become limited by systematics rather than data. Hierarchical Bayesian models are perfect for incorporating subtle effects into our model, and so I made one to do just that.
Supernova cosmology works because Type Ia supernova represent standardisable candles. That is, with a few factors taken into account, they are essentially all the same brightness. Which means, if we see two supernovae, and one is four times dimmer than the other, it must be twice as far away.</description></item><item><title>Cosmology on Safari</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/southafrica/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/southafrica/</guid><description>Every two years the amazing Cosmology on Safari conference is held.
And in 2019 I was lucky enough to not only go, but present a topic clear to my heart. My own research!
Not to miss out on the opportunity to see a bit more of Africa given I was flying over anyway, I also did a small camping trip through South Africa. And Botswana. And Zimbabwe. Only dipped my toes into Namibia though.</description></item><item><title>Probably Science Podcast</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/probablyscience/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/probablyscience/</guid><description>It turns out when you throw three comedians together on stage its super hard to keep up with the banter! I was the guest scientist invite on the amazing Probably Science podcast.
The episode should be live right now, so give it a listen, especially if you have a love for koalas.</description></item><item><title>BrisScience Lecture</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/brissicence/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/brissicence/</guid><description>In November I gave one of the monthly public lectures for UQ&amp;rsquo;s BrisScience event. We had a good little chat for the hour, first going over the history of the universe.
Fourteen minutes for fourteen billion years of cosmic history, sounds doable, right? Well, you need context to appreciate the second half of the talk.
That second half was then a very short introduction to dark energy and dark matter. What they might be, why we believe so strongly that they exist</description></item><item><title>Astronomy at Gumdale</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/gumdale/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/gumdale/</guid><description>Astronomy is great fun. So is coding. At least to me. But, I was invited to talk at Gumdale State School, I decided that it would be good to spread the good message out there and drum up some enthusiasm for space, science and STEM in general.
I think the trick with younger students is to constantly ask questions and get input, because talking for an hour at them will either put them to sleep or make them so restless you might as well not be talking, so that&amp;rsquo;s what I did.</description></item><item><title>Setting up a scientific python environment</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/anaconda/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/anaconda/</guid><description>This writeup is primarily for the students of PHYS3080 at UQ, however it should be generally applicable. Firstly, let&amp;rsquo;s get the obvious out of the way. It&amp;rsquo;s 2018. Python 2.7 is dead. Long live Python 3!
Getting a Python Environment Up And Running So let&amp;rsquo;s get a nice python 3 environment set up. Don&amp;rsquo;t google python 3, that would be crazy. Use Anaconda. So head here to download it, and pick the Python 3 version, 64 bits.</description></item><item><title>Hidden Treasure</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/gold/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/gold/</guid><description>With the Keva simulation I made, all the blocks are spaced out with room to move. I was curious to see how Blender&amp;rsquo;s engine would cope when the blocks were tightly packed, so, surprise surprise, I made a group of tightly packed cubes and then threw a glass sphere at them.
I randomised the materials of the cubes to add some spice, and fiddled around with simulation speed to get a slow motion section of the simulation.</description></item><item><title>The Tower of Two Blocks</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/keva/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/keva/</guid><description>Seeing KEVA simulations always makes my day brighter, so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d make a small one myself. This one has a series of very light wood blocks set on top some very heavy metal blocks as the base. Two steel balls are shot at the structure, and if you watch the video you can probably guess which of them is solid and which is simply a thin shell over a hollow interior!</description></item><item><title>Solar System Size Scale</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/planets/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/planets/</guid><description>{% include youtube.html url=&amp;ldquo;https://www.youtube.com/embed/JNPACDLSCTY)
This was a scene in which I learnt a lot, not just about compositing. Lots of fiddling with materials, mapping and textures to get the rocky planets working.
And then even more fiddling for the Gas Giants, to try and get that characteristic atmospheric effect along the boundary of the planet surface.
Setting up Saturn&amp;rsquo;s ring was a pain with the UV mapping, but eventually got it working!</description></item><item><title>Coloured Smoke</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/colorsmoke/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/colorsmoke/</guid><description>So I wanted to see how the soft body physics worked. So alright, lets just drop a ball. But a bouncing ball is boring, so lets squash it completely. And because I could, why not have particles emit when the bottom of the ball impacts and have them shoot out.
And then because that was still dull, what if we tie the velocity of the smoke into its colour, and have it that the more dense the smoke is, the more it glows and emits light.</description></item><item><title>Gas Explosion</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/explosion/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/explosion/</guid><description>It turns out that smoke simulations both take far, far longer than rigid body simulations, but also take up a lot of disk space as well. So I might have accidentally filled my main C drive on which Windows lives and had all sort of complaints come screetching out of the operating systems.
In this sim I was just trying to figure out how the volumetic shaders worked, such that I could get a two stage explosion with thick, greasy smoke.</description></item><item><title>Glowing Galton Board</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/galton/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/galton/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been years since I last tried out 3D modelling and simulations. And given how crushing my PhD workload is at this point in time, I realised I needed something on the side to distract me so that my project didn&amp;rsquo;t consume all of my life.
So, after seeing the constant posts about Blender on Reddits /r/simulated sub, I decided to give it a go. Following the current hot topic (so that if anything went wrong there would be plenty of people able to help out), I decided to go with a classic Galton board simulation.</description></item><item><title>readr 2017</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/readr/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/readr/</guid><description>Nearing the tail end of the year I got a wonderful opportunity to expand the work I had been doing with my coding workshops to also take them to the 2017 readr retreat. readr - a research education and development retreat - is open to all undergraduate physics students in Australia, not just astrophysics students.
I had to trim a lot of content as I went from a whole day workshop to a three hour block with breaks included.</description></item><item><title>Code Workshop</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/codeworkshop/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/codeworkshop/</guid><description>The idea to run a code workshop was born at the 2016 CAASTRO Annual Retreat. Fiona and I were talking to Elaine about the problems we have had with the self-taught style of coding the most astronomers work with, specifically the lack of structure, documentation and testing that so often accompanies astronomical projects and packages.
To fix this, we volunteered to run a code workshop, with a focus on teaching the astronomical community better coding standards, better practises, giving them better tools and better resources.</description></item><item><title>Desert Caves Map</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/map-caves/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/map-caves/</guid><description>Presenting, some desert caves, cave system, lava basin, dubiously engineered bridges, and small encampment! The idea for this one was after climbing down the hole in the previous map you would end up in the top right corner of this map.
Once again, following the style of Mark Bowen&amp;rsquo;s maps over at Blue Sword Games.
So, for this map, here are the outlines and grid versions:
And because the lava is very visually strong, if you want the play area to be more of the focus than the lava, use this image:</description></item><item><title>Desert Camp Map</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/map-camp/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/map-camp/</guid><description>Presenting, a desert camp, with included outcrops, interior cave and hole of mystery!
Once again, following the style of Mark Bowen&amp;rsquo;s maps over at Blue Sword Games, my second desert map.
I decided I wanted the map to have a few potential uses.
Make camp, and be ambused from outside, and use the cave choke point to hold them off. Have creatures ascend from the hole and attack the camp from inside the cave.</description></item><item><title>Desert Canyon Map</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/map-canyon/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/map-canyon/</guid><description>Presenting, a desert canyon, with included creek, small rock pillars, and larger overhanging boulder, for your consideration! Feel free to use it, modify it, whatever you want.
I&amp;rsquo;ve recently been collecting maps for potential use in some upcoming campaign, and I absolutely love the art style of Mark Bowen&amp;rsquo;s maps over at Blue Sword Games.
I highly recommend checking it out!
So I&amp;rsquo;ve been following his map making progress, and decided that - given I want more maps than are available - I should make some to fill in the blanks for the current scaffold.</description></item><item><title>Making Taipan's Logo</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/taipan/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/taipan/</guid><description>I think a good way to not get burnt out coding and doing math 24/7 a day is to do some more creative work to break the monotony.
Or perhaps I am simply bad at saying &amp;ldquo;No!&amp;rdquo;
The moral of the story is that I took over makign the Taipan logo for the Taipan survey. The original art was all done in green, and I thought - given the lack of green colouring in many astronomical surveys, and given the snake is vaguely green(ish brown), sure, sounds good!</description></item><item><title>Physics in the Pub</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/pub/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/pub/</guid><description>Physics in the Pub came to Brisbane! With the esteemed Dr Phil Dooley as MC for the night, we had a great evening of eight physics acts. Whilst I trying to impress the sheer scale and significance of supernovae on the audience, I was definitely not the star of the show that night!
Chris Mesiku sang a reggae song about $$E=mc^2$$ and Einstein. Phil himself sang a cover of Nirvana about particle physics and light.</description></item><item><title>Battle of the Brains</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/botb/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/botb/</guid><description>As part of The Science Nation&amp;rsquo;s National Science Week set of activities, I was given the opportunity to participate in Battle of the Brains! Andrew Stephenson hosted the event, and kept the six guest scientists neatly in line throughout the event.
We set up on stage, I of course didn&amp;rsquo;t speak into the microphone correctly, and an audience member came up and adjusted it mid-sentence to much laughter.
It was a great night where I got nearly every question wrong!</description></item><item><title>What is OzDES?</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/ozdes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/ozdes/</guid><description>Sometimes I think I get a big bogged down, lost in a maze of code that I used to be the master of before losing my bearing. At times like this, it is prudent to take a step back, to let the maze untangle itself slowly whilst one focuses on other tasks.
Or at least, that is my excuse for picking up side work. In the latest installment of &amp;ldquo;No, I don&amp;rsquo;t have results from my PhD yet,&amp;rdquo; I present the following post on OzDES, its purpose, goals and how it goes about fulfilling them.</description></item><item><title>Visiting Chicago</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/chicago/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/chicago/</guid><description>Once again escaping the Australian winter, I found myself residing in the temperate Bay area. But I was still cold. And so to Chicago I went&amp;hellip; coincidentally, this was at the same time as a DES collaboration meeting.
This visit now marks my greatest journey east into the US. I would have liked to go to New York and visit the city, just to make that statement incorrect, but alas, neither time nor money can be spared for such an adventure.</description></item><item><title>Pint of Science 2017</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/pint/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/pint/</guid><description>During the week of the 14th of May there were a host of Pint of Science events presented in Brisbane. Josh and I did one together - Josh presented a talk Dark matter, what&amp;rsquo;s the matter?, where he talked about the dark universe, and potential candidates for dark matter. I gave a talk The Brightest Fireworks in the Universe - on supernovae, their lives, deaths and role in the universe.</description></item><item><title>Making a utility knife</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/knife/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/knife/</guid><description>For a while now I&amp;rsquo;ve been meaning to see if I can make something a bit more useful than my normal projects, and what could be more useful than a knife? Well, a lot of things, but most things are simply too difficult and require too many tools I don&amp;rsquo;t have!
So, in preparation built a gas forge with tons of help from the guys at QMAC, and then built a simply filing jig to help me out.</description></item><item><title>ScopeTV Guest Scientist</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/scope/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/scope/</guid><description>Every now and then ScopeTV has a space focused episode, and they look up some local scientists to help present the content for one of their episodes. Janie and I were asked if we wanted to participate in an episode focused on the size and scale of the solar system, and obviously we thought it was a great idea, so we jumped on it!
I&amp;rsquo;m sure you&amp;rsquo;ve seen similar demonstrations - start with the sun a huge ball that you can barely carry, and work your way down to the other planets at physically accurate (albeit scaled down) distances.</description></item><item><title>Famelab 2017</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/famelab/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/famelab/</guid><description>Famelab is a science communication challenge where PhD students have three minutes, no slides, no video and one prop - if they so choose - to share your thesis work to a live audience!
I prepared a short segment on supernovae and their role in the universe. But before the night itself, we had a short segement with Rebecca Levingston on ABC&amp;rsquo;s Saturday Breakfast radio. It was my first radio spot, and I admit I was definitely not as eloquent as I wanted!</description></item><item><title>Refractorium</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/refractorium/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/refractorium/</guid><description>Click here to run the simulator in your browser. I was browsing Reddit&amp;rsquo;s Simulated subreddit one afternoon and came across a nice GPU voxel fluid animation. Whilst reading up how it was engineered, I stumbled onto a project by Benedikt Bitterli called Tantalum.
It was a GPU accelerated 2D light transport simulator, and I spent at least an hour playing around with it and producing some beautiful caustics. But with Tantalum, you can only control the position and angle of the light source - the rest of the scene was static.</description></item><item><title>Making bismuth crystals</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/bismuth/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/bismuth/</guid><description>Josh Calcino and I were in Japan on a holiday recently, and we spent a fair bit of time in some of the larger crystal shops they had in Kyoto - we both collected crystals when we were younger. We saw some beautiful pieces of bismuth, and I came close to buying some.
Instead, we decided to buy some raw bismuth when we got back home and make the crystals ourselves!</description></item><item><title>Making a Moon Mosaic</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/moon/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/moon/</guid><description>I was at the Dark Energy Survey conference in December when I met an overachieving student. Three years in, and already using the telescope at the University of Sussex to do additional projects, including a moon mosaic.
Jessica, the student in question, had never made a mosaic before. Luckily, I had done it once or twice for past work for Gemini, and so I offered to help. Three hundred images I received of the moon.</description></item><item><title>Japan Winter Holiday</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/japan/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/japan/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s good to get away sometimes.
Especially good if you make sure you don&amp;rsquo;t bring a laptop - no sneaky working during a holiday!
So in January 2017, I went to Japan. First stop, Mt Fuji.
After Fuji, straight to Kyoto. We went to a few of the shrines, the Silver and Golden Palaces, and the Fushimi Inari Shrine.
I didn&amp;rsquo;t quite realise how big the Fushimi Inari Shrine was - its not just one or two arches, there are kilometers of them.</description></item><item><title>An Evening with Dr Lisa Randall</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/lisa/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/lisa/</guid><description>In November 2016, Lisa Randall gave an Australian tour in the big cities. As normal for ThinkInc events, they had a local scientist give an introductory talk to warm up the audience.
I decided to give a brief talk about the current state of physics, and gave a brief explanation of the physics behind the Hubble Space Telescope, the Large Hadron Collider, eLISA, LIGO and a few other great experiments.</description></item><item><title>Uluru Astronomer in Residence</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/uluru/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/uluru/</guid><description>I highly recommend this experience to all other CAASTRO students. I was only at Ayers Rock Resort for a week and enjoyed myself immensely. The time you have to talk to the general public, play educational games with the kids, answer interesting questions at the AstroTours and take your own pictures of the night sky makes it a great experience.
I was an emergency replacement, hence why I went for one week and not two, however one week was plenty of time to settle into a comfortable routine focused on public outreach.</description></item><item><title>Survey Visualiser</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/surveyvis/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/surveyvis/</guid><description>I was making a poster for the CAASTRO annual retreat on my BAO work, and realised what it really needed was a nice comparison of the WiggleZ survey compared to other more local surveys, to highlight the redshift depth of WiggleZ in comparison to other surveys of the same period, such as 2dF.
And because I am a stubborn fool, I decided to extend what I did to the general case.</description></item><item><title>ChainConsumer</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/chainconsumer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/chainconsumer/</guid><description>I was working with some chains one day and wanted to plot different cosmologies against each other, and realised that they had different parameters. Unfortunately, this meant that the library I was using couldn&amp;rsquo;t handle the task, so I wrote my own!
If you want to know more and see plenty of examples see the online documentation here.
The API is fairly straightforward I hope, with a simple example shown below.</description></item><item><title>LBNL - California</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/california/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/california/</guid><description>In the Australian summer of 2016 I went to study at Lawrence Berkeley National Labs for a couple of months with Alex Kim, working on my Bayesian model for supernova cosmology.
It was a very productive time, but that isn&amp;rsquo;t what this page is about; this page is about what I got up to outside of work.
The first thing to do when near San Francisco is to go to the Golden Gate Bridge.</description></item><item><title>Get Lit; Atlassian Ship-It</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/getlit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/getlit/</guid><description>Thanks to the wonderful Kate Gunn, CAASTRO managed to participated in one of Atlassian&amp;rsquo;s Ship-It hackathons. I joined the team, along with Bonnie, Steven, Anais, Richard to make the CAASTRO counterpart, with Atlassian providing two staff members, Jason and Ivor in case we needed some heavy software lifting done. The project idea and all the initial hard work was put in by Steven - we wanted to create a better way to search for scientific papers, given that Google doesn&amp;rsquo;t work, and NASA&amp;rsquo;s ADS system is a bit&amp;hellip; rough.</description></item><item><title>Gemini - La Serena, Chile</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/gemini/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/gemini/</guid><description>Part One: The drafting They shipped us off December 8th. Three students sent out to the Gemini telescope in La Serena, Chile, to see what they could make of the situation. To see if they could survive.
I remember it like it was last just last month.
By some coincidence, it was. Exactly. I&amp;rsquo;m writing this on the 8th of January, at 5pm, after finishing a day of work.
This is us.</description></item><item><title>Detecting Globular Clusters</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/globular/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/globular/</guid><description>In my time over at Gemini in La Serena, I worked on a project to distinguish globular clusters from stars. The globular clusters (GCs) were located in the giant elliptical galaxy Maffei 1, which - whilst being very close to us - requires looking through the middle of our galaxy.
You do not want this.
The dust extinction was through the roof. I used the SDFRED data reduction pipeline to process images from the Subaru telescope, giving me the output image below.</description></item><item><title>WiggleZ 2D BAO</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/bao/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/bao/</guid><description>Shall we just jump right into it? The slightly wiggles you can see around $$k=0.1 \rm{h/Mpc}$$ below, when transformed into a correlation function via the Spherical Hankel transformation, turn into that big peak in the right hand plot. As you may have guessed, said &amp;ldquo;big peak&amp;rdquo; is the oscillation of interest. Put simply, it represents a characteristic separation at which there is an overdensity of matter in the universe. And its of interest because this peak has existed since the first galaxies formed, and so we can use it as a standard ruler.</description></item><item><title>Kubo Oscillator</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/kubo/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/kubo/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ll be honest: this post was made just to show of one of my favourite plots. I&amp;rsquo;ll put it at the end, because without an introduction it really doesn&amp;rsquo;t make too much sense.
Firstly, a terrifying brief (and thus completely inaccurate) introduction to stochastic systems: A stochastic system is one in which the outcome of an individual system is unpredictable due to the effect of randomness.
Brownian motion (the motion of a particle being jostled around by other particles) is the classic example of this.</description></item><item><title>Overland Track - Tasmania</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/tasmania/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/tasmania/</guid><description>After uni was over one year, Julia told me she was thinking of doing the overland track in Tasmania. I had heard good things about the track, and so I decided to tag along!
I got some army rations off my mate Chris, and bought a ton of food from the store, loaded up some clothes and tools, threw them in my hiking back pack, and off we went.
The initial climb and day was marred by wet weather, but still offered some great views.</description></item><item><title>Marz</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/marz/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/marz/</guid><description>Marz was a program I first started coding for my undergraduate software engineering thesis. The OzDES team was spending too much time manually redshifting spectra and wanted some improvements to the workflow done. I could either improve Runz (the software used at the time), or create something from scratch.
Guess which one I picked?
After lots of work, hassle and one side arguments with my computer, I managed to actually get something usable!</description></item><item><title>European Holiday</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/europe/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/europe/</guid><description>Its hard to condense down such a big trip into less than a small book, but here goes. Started in London, went to Paris &amp;amp; Nice. Travelled down to Rome, patted a lot of stray cats in the colosseum. Went to Monaco, and then to Munich (which was the best). Munich to the Rhine valley, and form there to the Netherlands.
Definitely am going to go back, especially to Germany and the Netherlands, once I have some time and money.</description></item><item><title>DJ Board</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/dj/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/dj/</guid><description>My first team project was to make a pseudo-satellite. Two years later, better equipped, I was hoping the second project would be to built the rocket. Instead, we got a DJ board. People said I had unrealistically high expectations.
Maybe so.
The challenge of the DJ board was not conceptual, it was to be able to do it all on the tiny processor they gave us, which had essentially no memory.</description></item><item><title>Laser Satellite</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/satellite/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/satellite/</guid><description>This was my first proper team project. Myself, Jeevan, Kiaran and David, tasked to built a device which, whilst suspended from a single thin wire, would be able to detected infrared sources, target them, and then fire a laser back at them to hit a bullseye underneath.
In other words, an awesome project.
Like all good satellites, you try and keep mechanical design simple. Less moving parts means less points of failure.</description></item><item><title>The Most Useless Machine</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/box/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/box/</guid><description>The year before this, I created a thick paper mache wrapper around a present to make it more interesting to unwrap. So in 2011 I decided to do a take on the &amp;ldquo;Most Useless Machine Ever&amp;rdquo; - a box that&amp;rsquo;s sole function is to flip a switch back to its off position when a user flicks it on.
{% include youtube.html url=&amp;ldquo;https://www.youtube.com/embed/2LKnORvwsoI)
Mechanically, this is simple, the flick just needs to be connected to a DC motor switch, such that either side of the switch changes the voltage across the motor.</description></item><item><title>Mood Bottle</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/bottle/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/bottle/</guid><description>The image you see was sourced from a similar Instructibles that I recommend you check out.
Unfortunately, I can find no images of my own creation. It was made in 2011, in the basement of my grandparent&amp;rsquo;s house. The pictures I took were on an old phone, long since gone.
So, I&amp;rsquo;ll simply explain what I did, and hope I can find actual images in the future.
The recipe goes as follows:</description></item><item><title>The Blue Planet</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/planet/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/planet/</guid><description>I created this image using a ton of brushes, layers, stacking and this texture.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Strike</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/lightning/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/lightning/</guid><description>This photoshop challenge was for me to try and figure out the basics of photomanipulation. I started with a bunch of images and textures, and turned them into what you see below.
Stocks sourced from
Water Outcrop Lightning Clouds Clouds Clouds Tower</description></item><item><title>Computer Case</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/computer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/computer/</guid><description>Every now and then, when I think work may be lulling, I try and pick this hobby back up.
And every single time I finish refamiliarising myself with 3DS, sometimes crops up, and I don&amp;rsquo;t come back to it for a year.
Here is the last time I managed to get something properly tangible. From 2009 I believe. The original files are long lost to computer failure. All that is left are these images, rendered out quickly at low resolution abut three quarters of the way through the design.</description></item></channel></rss>