<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>lgbt on Samuel Hinton</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tags/lgbt/</link><description>Recent content in lgbt on Samuel Hinton</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tags/lgbt/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Review of Andrew Rowe's Arcane Ascension Series: hard magic done right</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/arcane_ascension/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/arcane_ascension/</guid><description>My rating is for the series as a whole as of writing. It&amp;rsquo;s amazing. I&amp;rsquo;ll make sure this review focuses on Book One: Sufficiently Advanced Magic.
Corin Cadence is one of my favourite main characters in all of fantasy. He is, as I image many of us think, how we would approach being a person in a magical world. Analytically. Carefully. Exploitively.
So here&amp;rsquo;s the plot - you get powers (attunements) ostensibly from the goddess, via blessings you receive in the spires.</description></item><item><title>A review of RavensDagger's 'Cinnamon Bun'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/cinnamon_bun/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/cinnamon_bun/</guid><description>As readers of this genre know, LitRPG worlds can be a depressing, harrowing, and cut-throat place. Half of the MC&amp;rsquo;s I&amp;rsquo;ve read in other works get ahead because this suits them just fine. They&amp;rsquo;re happy to fight, happy to get their hands dirty, happy to shake the system up. In many ways, that&amp;rsquo;s part of the escapism. Having power.
Cinnamon Bun has a slightly different take. The world is less apocalyptic in fashion, and our main character, Broccoli Bunch, just wants to go on cool adventures and make friends.</description></item><item><title>A Review of Tobias Begley's progression fantasy work 'The Enchanter'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/enchanter/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/enchanter/</guid><description>Let&amp;rsquo;s get the obvious out the way and let me expand on the description above. If you&amp;rsquo;ve read the Arcane Ascension series and loved Corin&amp;rsquo;s approach to life, just save yourself some time, click the amazon link above, and go and get this book. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t, but you&amp;rsquo;ve read Mother of Learning and appreciated Zorian there, same comment.
Alright, let&amp;rsquo;s start with a spoiler-free summary. Our MC, Evander Tailor, is gifted.</description></item><item><title>A review of Michael Nwanolue's 'The Tower Unbroken'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/tower_unbroken/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/tower_unbroken/</guid><description>I do like me a good cultivation story, and so when I asked for some recommendations and someone pointed out that there is a little-known work featuring African-inspired cultivation, I put it to the top of my list.
And here we are!
The Tower Unbroken follows Somadina&amp;rsquo;s journey from his village out into the wider world. He starts off as the lowliest rank of cultivator, or dibias as they are called in this setting.</description></item></channel></rss>