<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>system-apocalypse on Samuel Hinton</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tags/system-apocalypse/</link><description>Recent content in system-apocalypse on Samuel Hinton</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tags/system-apocalypse/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Review of Matt Dinniman's Dungeon Crawler Carl. Officially my favourite LitRPG.</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/dungeon_crawler_carl/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/dungeon_crawler_carl/</guid><description>Dungeon Crawler Carl opens with something reminiscent of Hitchhiker&amp;rsquo;s Guide to the Galaxy. Earth is being mined for minerals, and those that survived the initial population purge become participants in the universe&amp;rsquo;s most popular show, as they progress through a deadly dungeon run by an insane AI to either try and survive or beat the dungeon and win back their planet.
Now that is a fun premise.
Carl enters the dungeon with Princess Donut, a prize-winning cat.</description></item><item><title>A Review of J. R. Mathews's 'Jakes Magical Market', a fun LitRPG apocalypse romb with a card based system.</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/jakes_magical_market/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/jakes_magical_market/</guid><description>Before I picked up this book, I must have seen Jake&amp;rsquo;s Magical Market recommended a dozen times on the /r/ProgressionFantasy subreddit. It even got a shoutout from Bryce O&amp;rsquo;Connor, and then, after about ten more people told me to read it, I pulled the trigger, added it to my Kindle, and then I read the entire thing&amp;mdash;all eight hundred pages&amp;mdash;in a single weekend.
So yeah, I thought it was pretty good.</description></item><item><title>A review of Maxime J. Durand's 'The Perfect Run'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/perfect_run/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/perfect_run/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a quite a few years since the Alchemist distributed Elixirs into the world, each which grant a unique super power. Since then, modern civilisation has collapsed, because giving some people phenomenal power tends to go badly a lot of the time. Quicksave begins the book searching for his childhood friend, Len, and determined to go through every chapter in his life with a perfect run. Which, as you might have guessed from the hero name, is possible thanks to his ability to set a checkpoint in time he can revert to on death.</description></item><item><title>A Review of Noret Flood's 'The Legend of Randidly Ghosthound', a great take on system takeover LitRPG.</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/randidly_ghosthound/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/randidly_ghosthound/</guid><description>Note: I&amp;rsquo;ve read the Amazon Book One, and then Royal Road chapters up to around Chapter 300 (ie many books worth). This review uses all of the content I&amp;rsquo;ve read, but I&amp;rsquo;ll make sure to separate book vs royal road if you&amp;rsquo;re thinking of buying. Actually, scrap that, just buy the first book, its great, and then continue on RR if you want.
So let&amp;rsquo;s begin with the basic premise. Earth is taken over by the System, and it becomes an effective post-apocalypse LitRPG adventure, which is fairly normal for the genre.</description></item><item><title>A Review of Zogarth's LitRPG 'The Primal Hunter'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/primal_hunter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/primal_hunter/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m just going to come out and say it. If you&amp;rsquo;ve read Defiance of the Fall and enjoyed it, you will love The Primal Hunter. It has a similar premise, similar (minimal) base-building and progression, but with better characters and less deus ex machina.
Now, to be fair, the author gets away with a lot on the social side of characterisation by making the main character incredibly anti-social, and then befriending a pair of (sentient) birds.</description></item><item><title>A Review of 'Defiance of the Fall', a system-apocalypse LitRPG / cultivation hybrid.</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/defiance_of_the_fall/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/defiance_of_the_fall/</guid><description>As of the time of writing this review, I have read all four books on KU, and a further 200 chapters on RR, up to and including the time skip.
So Defiance of the Fall did hook me in, and the author is great at leaving each chapter with a teaser, cliffhanger, or something to get you thinking &amp;ldquo;Okay, just one more.&amp;rdquo; It had the same vibes as when I&amp;rsquo;m playing Civilisation, and it&amp;rsquo;s why I ended up reading several million words before I put the story down.</description></item></channel></rss>