<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>companion on Samuel Hinton</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tags/companion/</link><description>Recent content in companion on Samuel Hinton</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tags/companion/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Review of Will Wight's Cradle Series: The King of Progression Fantasy</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/cradle/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/cradle/</guid><description>Cradle is going to be tough to write a review for, because I don&amp;rsquo;t want to sound too biased, despite my love for the series.
I&amp;rsquo;ll focus upon the first few books here (Unsouled, Soulsmith, Blackflame) and try to keep spoilers for the rest of the series locked away in my heart.
The story follows a young man hailing from one of the clans of Sacred Valley. This is Lindon. He is, shall we say, unfairly treated by the clan, who believes he has no aptitude for the spiritual arts.</description></item><item><title>Reflections on my own 'Soul Relic'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/soul_relic/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/soul_relic/</guid><description>Born with an enormous well of power but no way to regenerate it, Raysha will risk anything to fix herself, even if it means venturing into the unknown with nothing but her brother, an enchanted water bottle, and a stubborn attitude.
Without the ability to cultivate aeon from the world, Raysha has been treated like an outcast her whole life. While she has to ration her power drop-by-drop, others use it as commonly as breathing.</description></item><item><title>A Review of Matt Dinniman's Dungeon Crawler Carl. Officially my favourite LitRPG.</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/dungeon_crawler_carl/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/dungeon_crawler_carl/</guid><description>Dungeon Crawler Carl opens with something reminiscent of Hitchhiker&amp;rsquo;s Guide to the Galaxy. Earth is being mined for minerals, and those that survived the initial population purge become participants in the universe&amp;rsquo;s most popular show, as they progress through a deadly dungeon run by an insane AI to either try and survive or beat the dungeon and win back their planet.
Now that is a fun premise.
Carl enters the dungeon with Princess Donut, a prize-winning cat.</description></item><item><title>A review of J.R. Mathews's 'Portal to Nova Roma'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/nova_roma/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/nova_roma/</guid><description>Blurb To find peace, Alexander must first embrace war.
After tragically losing the only person he ever cared about, Alexander, a rogue artificial intelligence, opens a portal to an alternate dimension to escape his grief.
Scanning trillions of different dimensions, Alexander finally finds a world that is reminiscent of the only time he was ever happy, back when he could play virtual reality games with his only friend. He doesn&amp;rsquo;t know why, or how, such a world exists, but he doesn&amp;rsquo;t care.</description></item><item><title>A Review of Actus' 'My Best Friend is an Eldritch Horror.'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/best_friend_eldritch_horror/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/best_friend_eldritch_horror/</guid><description>As of writing this review, I&amp;rsquo;ve read all three published books in the series.
Blurb Damien nearly ended the world. Now, his mistake might be the only thing that can save it.
Good things come to those who wait. Damien Vale didn’t, and he ended up bound to an Eldritch creature from beyond the reaches of space. It has lived since the dawn of time, seen the world born and destroyed countless times, and wants to be called Henry.</description></item><item><title>A review of J.L. Mullins' 'Millenial Mage'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/millenial_mage/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/millenial_mage/</guid><description>As of writing this review, I&amp;rsquo;ve read all 224 published chapters.
Blurb The world is wild, untamed. Humanity thrives, but only in isolated, well defended cities, ever shrinking as the wilds slowly reclaim all that was taken. The most capable magic users are raised up as Mages to serve mankind, further their cause, and defend them over the course of millennia.
Tala is freshly graduated from the magic academy and determined to make her own way in the world.</description></item><item><title>A Review of Honour Rae's 'All The Skills'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/all_the_skills/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/all_the_skills/</guid><description>As of the time of writing this review, I have read the available chapters (chapter 30 in book two or so).
Blurb The most Arthur could hope for was to someday earn a trash-tier spell card. When fate grants him a Master of Skills card, he&amp;rsquo;s thrust into a world of opportunity and danger.
To survive and grow strong, Arthur must learn skills. All the skills.
Thoughts Damn, that blurb is light, isn&amp;rsquo;t it?</description></item><item><title>A Review of C. Mantis' 'The Path of Ascension', a sci-fi wuxia novel with a staggering range of powers and power divides.</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/path_ascension/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/path_ascension/</guid><description>This was another read courtesy of recommendations from /r/ProgressionFantasy. It&amp;rsquo;s only on Royal Road (at the time of writing), but I hope it reaches a wider audience soon when the author has a chance to go back and package it all up nicely.
The Path of Ascension follows the journey of our tragically orphaned MC, Matt. Matt&amp;rsquo;s parents were killed in a rift break. If you&amp;rsquo;ve read Solo Levelling or many other rift/portal/dunegon based novels, this is fairly standard.</description></item><item><title>A review of Harmon Cooper's 'The World According to Dragons'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/the_world_according_to_dragons/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/the_world_according_to_dragons/</guid><description>Blurb An infamous relic hunter. A legendary dragon. The journey of a lifetime.
Twillo lies bleeding out in a volcanic desert. Towering over him is a snarling red wolf, death only seconds away.
Right as his vision is going black, a mysterious voice offers Twillo a chance at survival.
Do you agree to bind souls?
It is the voice of a dragon, one that hasn&amp;rsquo;t been seen for hundreds of years.</description></item><item><title>A review of Nicoli Gonnella's 'Unbound' series</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/unbound/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/unbound/</guid><description>Blurb A New World. A Thousand Threats. Welcome to The Continent.
Felix&amp;rsquo;s life on Earth had become a series of dead-end jobs, ruined relationships, and rotating apartments smaller than most postage stamps. By all accounts, even his own, he was a coward. Too afraid to move forward, to take risks. Yet when given the chance to choose between risking his life or walking away from a deadly encounter, he didn&amp;rsquo;t hesitate.</description></item></channel></rss>