<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Book Reviews on Samuel Hinton</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/</link><description>Recent content in Book Reviews on Samuel Hinton</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Review of Will Wight's Cradle Series: The King of Progression Fantasy</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/cradle/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/cradle/</guid><description>Cradle is going to be tough to write a review for, because I don&amp;rsquo;t want to sound too biased, despite my love for the series.
I&amp;rsquo;ll focus upon the first few books here (Unsouled, Soulsmith, Blackflame) and try to keep spoilers for the rest of the series locked away in my heart.
The story follows a young man hailing from one of the clans of Sacred Valley. This is Lindon. He is, shall we say, unfairly treated by the clan, who believes he has no aptitude for the spiritual arts.</description></item><item><title>A Review of nobody13's Mother of Learning. Time loops with a smart protagonist, done so very, very right.</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/mother_of_learning/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/mother_of_learning/</guid><description>I grew up on the Belgariad, graduated through Harry Potter to the Wheel of Time, conquered Malazan, was crushed by the Farseer Trilogy, and generally docked my ship at every fantasy port I could find.
Then I was recommended to read Mother of Learning. It was my first serial novel. And despite its 800k words, I read it in a week.
And then I read it again.
So many books I&amp;rsquo;ve read fumble the ending or the rising tension.</description></item><item><title>A Review of Bryce O'Connor's Iron Prince. Scifi progression on actual digital steroids."</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/iron_prince/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/iron_prince/</guid><description>I normally approach scifi with skepticism. I studied astrophysics, and physics is a harsh mistress that is all to easy to try and abuse in works of science fiction. There&amp;rsquo;s one surefire way around this - magical tech. Or in this case, alien tech that is so advanced it might as well be magic. And with the soft scifi setting established, this allows Bryce to draw the best from fantasy, the best from LitRPG levelling, and combine them to make one of the best progression fantasy stories I have read in years.</description></item><item><title>A Review of Andrew Rowe's Arcane Ascension Series: hard magic done right</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/arcane_ascension/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/arcane_ascension/</guid><description>My rating is for the series as a whole as of writing. It&amp;rsquo;s amazing. I&amp;rsquo;ll make sure this review focuses on Book One: Sufficiently Advanced Magic.
Corin Cadence is one of my favourite main characters in all of fantasy. He is, as I image many of us think, how we would approach being a person in a magical world. Analytically. Carefully. Exploitively.
So here&amp;rsquo;s the plot - you get powers (attunements) ostensibly from the goddess, via blessings you receive in the spires.</description></item><item><title>Reflections on my own 'Soul Relic'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/soul_relic/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/soul_relic/</guid><description>Born with an enormous well of power but no way to regenerate it, Raysha will risk anything to fix herself, even if it means venturing into the unknown with nothing but her brother, an enchanted water bottle, and a stubborn attitude.
Without the ability to cultivate aeon from the world, Raysha has been treated like an outcast her whole life. While she has to ration her power drop-by-drop, others use it as commonly as breathing.</description></item><item><title>A Review of Phil Tucker's Bastion. It's great.</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/bastion/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/bastion/</guid><description>Many progression fantasy series start with a similar pattern. An unfortunate, downtrodden, or unlucky individual is wronged, usually in an academic or sect environment, and then they claw their way through the classes, pushing themselves into excellence.
Bastion opens similarly, and I was preparing myself for a bit of &amp;lsquo;more of the same&amp;rsquo;. When the Chancellor starts explaining a points system for Academic progression through the Gauntlet (aka dungeon / spire / magical testing realm) a spark of worry lit inside me.</description></item><item><title>A Review of John Bierce's Mage Errant Series. A fun ride with a likeable cast.</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/mage_errant/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/mage_errant/</guid><description>This review focuses on first volume. As of writing I&amp;rsquo;ve read all five released books and those flavour my opinion.
Hugh of Emblin is both a horrific and talented student at Skyhold Academy.
He is anxious, I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure he is depressed, and ultimately he is just not vibing about the state of the world and his own abilities.
Luckily, he has some great friends to help pick him up and support him.</description></item><item><title>A review of J.M. Clarke's 'Mark of the Fool'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/mark_of_the_fool/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/mark_of_the_fool/</guid><description>As of writing this review, I have read the KU release and up to chapter 200, which is about half-way through the available chapters.
So here&amp;rsquo;s the premise: Alex Roth is one of five chosen Heroes that need to defeat a reoccurring villain: The Ravener. Alex, however, is the Fool. His Mark, instead of making him a combat savant, powerful spellcaster, etc, makes him really great at learning things that are outside of combat and spellcasting&amp;hellip; but will actively interfere with his abilities if they are not.</description></item><item><title>A review of Naomi Novik's Scholomance Series</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/scholomance/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/scholomance/</guid><description>I didn&amp;rsquo;t expect to read a book from the perspective of an emotional teenage girl and love every page.
And yet, here we are.
So, premise time. In this world, there are magical people, and not magical people (they&amp;rsquo;re not called muggles though). Raising a magical kid is hard, because there are a whole host of creatures, called maleficaria (or mals) which love that sweet mana inside the kids, and will eat them all up.</description></item><item><title>A Review of Matt Dinniman's Dungeon Crawler Carl. Officially my favourite LitRPG.</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/dungeon_crawler_carl/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/dungeon_crawler_carl/</guid><description>Dungeon Crawler Carl opens with something reminiscent of Hitchhiker&amp;rsquo;s Guide to the Galaxy. Earth is being mined for minerals, and those that survived the initial population purge become participants in the universe&amp;rsquo;s most popular show, as they progress through a deadly dungeon run by an insane AI to either try and survive or beat the dungeon and win back their planet.
Now that is a fun premise.
Carl enters the dungeon with Princess Donut, a prize-winning cat.</description></item><item><title>A Review of Selkie Myth's series 'Beneath the Dragoneye Moons'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/beneath_the_dragons_eye_moons/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/beneath_the_dragons_eye_moons/</guid><description>As of writing this review, I&amp;rsquo;ve read everything published, which is books one through to nine in the series.
Blurb Elaine is ripped from this world to Pallos, a land of unlimited possibilities made real by a grand System governing classes, skills, and magic.
An ideal society? What is this, a fantasy novel?
Adventures? Right this way!
A Grand quest? Nah.
Friends and loot? Heck yes!
Humans are the top dog?</description></item><item><title>A review of Sarah Lin's 'The Weirkey Chronicles'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/weirkey/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/weirkey/</guid><description>As of writing this, I have read all five released books, and will be picking up the next whenever it comes out!
Our MC, Theo, has spent decades searching for a way back into the magical realms of the Nine Worlds. After a bitter life with no success, he eventually finds his way back, only to confront the fact that the ideals of his younger self are only a distant memory to the man he now is.</description></item><item><title>A review of Rob J. Hayes' 'Titan Hoppers'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/titan_hoppers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/titan_hoppers/</guid><description>Blurb Courage Iro will shatter the Gates of Power to protect his fleet.
Born talentless, Iro has all but resigned himself to a life of drudgery, watching his sister hop across to the massive space titan for supplies. But when the titan explodes and his sister is killed, Iro finds a new determination to take her place. He’s not about to let weakness prevent him.
When the fleet encounters a new titan, filled with powerful monsters, deadly traps, and mysterious cloaked figures, Iro is the first to spontaneously manifest a new talent.</description></item><item><title>A review of J.R. Mathews's 'Portal to Nova Roma'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/nova_roma/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/nova_roma/</guid><description>Blurb To find peace, Alexander must first embrace war.
After tragically losing the only person he ever cared about, Alexander, a rogue artificial intelligence, opens a portal to an alternate dimension to escape his grief.
Scanning trillions of different dimensions, Alexander finally finds a world that is reminiscent of the only time he was ever happy, back when he could play virtual reality games with his only friend. He doesn&amp;rsquo;t know why, or how, such a world exists, but he doesn&amp;rsquo;t care.</description></item><item><title>A Review of CasualFarmer's Cultivation novel 'Beware of Chicken'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/beware_of_chicken/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/beware_of_chicken/</guid><description>As of writing this review, I have read all 212 published chapters on Royal Road.
I saw this series recommended a few times on various groups and subreddits, but I always put it off because the name of the series didn&amp;rsquo;t exactly give me details about what it was about. The tidal wave of support for the work pushed me over the edge, so I picked it up&amp;hellip; and it turns out that was a great decision.</description></item><item><title>A Review of J. R. Mathews's 'Jakes Magical Market', a fun LitRPG apocalypse romb with a card based system.</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/jakes_magical_market/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/jakes_magical_market/</guid><description>Before I picked up this book, I must have seen Jake&amp;rsquo;s Magical Market recommended a dozen times on the /r/ProgressionFantasy subreddit. It even got a shoutout from Bryce O&amp;rsquo;Connor, and then, after about ten more people told me to read it, I pulled the trigger, added it to my Kindle, and then I read the entire thing&amp;mdash;all eight hundred pages&amp;mdash;in a single weekend.
So yeah, I thought it was pretty good.</description></item><item><title>A Review of Actus' 'My Best Friend is an Eldritch Horror.'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/best_friend_eldritch_horror/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/best_friend_eldritch_horror/</guid><description>As of writing this review, I&amp;rsquo;ve read all three published books in the series.
Blurb Damien nearly ended the world. Now, his mistake might be the only thing that can save it.
Good things come to those who wait. Damien Vale didn’t, and he ended up bound to an Eldritch creature from beyond the reaches of space. It has lived since the dawn of time, seen the world born and destroyed countless times, and wants to be called Henry.</description></item><item><title>A Review of zechamp's 'DMG=MA: A Rolling Stone LitRPG'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/rolling_stone/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/rolling_stone/</guid><description>Blurb By a stroke of fate, a stone gains sentience and sets out on a grand quest to touch grass.
However, the system forgot to change its stats from their [Metric] values to the appropriate [Str, Int, Dex] values.
Things escalate. Fast.
Features:
Cultivation Jade Beauties Numbers go up (Ridiculously up. All of them) Most balanced protagonist of all time (is round, so is balanced) Thoughts As you might have guessed, I&amp;rsquo;ve read quite a few LitRPG, cutivation, and PF series.</description></item><item><title>A review of Rhaegar's 'Azarinth Healer'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/azarinth_healer/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/azarinth_healer/</guid><description>Blurb Ilea likes punching things. And eating.
Unfortunately, there aren’t too many career options for hungry brawlers. Instead, the plan is to quit her crappy fast-food job, go to college, and become a fully functioning member of society. Essentially - a fate worse than death.
So maybe it&amp;rsquo;s lucky that she wakes up one day in a strange world where a bunch of fantasy monsters are trying to kill her&amp;hellip;?</description></item><item><title>A review of Striker's 'Virtuous Sons'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/virtuous_sons/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/virtuous_sons/</guid><description>Blurb Lio Aetos is the Young Aristocrat and heir apparent to a legendary Greek sect, a prodigious talent born and bred for glory.
Solus is a slave, a disgraced patrician from the fallen city of Rome with nothing to his name.
They&amp;rsquo;re as different as the East is from the West. Yet both of them hunger—to cast off the threads of Fate they’ve been given. To reach for a higher purpose.</description></item><item><title>A review of RavensDagger's 'Cinnamon Bun'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/cinnamon_bun/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/cinnamon_bun/</guid><description>As readers of this genre know, LitRPG worlds can be a depressing, harrowing, and cut-throat place. Half of the MC&amp;rsquo;s I&amp;rsquo;ve read in other works get ahead because this suits them just fine. They&amp;rsquo;re happy to fight, happy to get their hands dirty, happy to shake the system up. In many ways, that&amp;rsquo;s part of the escapism. Having power.
Cinnamon Bun has a slightly different take. The world is less apocalyptic in fashion, and our main character, Broccoli Bunch, just wants to go on cool adventures and make friends.</description></item><item><title>A review of Alec Huston's 'Umbral Storm'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/umbral_storm/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/umbral_storm/</guid><description>Blurb A thousand years ago the Heart of the World was shattered, its fragments scattered across the lands. In the chaos that followed, martial orders arose to gather these shards, for it was found that great powers were granted when these pieces were bonded to the flesh of the chosen. These are the Sharded Few, warriors imbued with the divine energies that once coursed through the Heart, and driven to absorb enough fragments to claim godhood.</description></item><item><title>A Review of Tobias Begley's progression fantasy work 'The Enchanter'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/enchanter/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/enchanter/</guid><description>Let&amp;rsquo;s get the obvious out the way and let me expand on the description above. If you&amp;rsquo;ve read the Arcane Ascension series and loved Corin&amp;rsquo;s approach to life, just save yourself some time, click the amazon link above, and go and get this book. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t, but you&amp;rsquo;ve read Mother of Learning and appreciated Zorian there, same comment.
Alright, let&amp;rsquo;s start with a spoiler-free summary. Our MC, Evander Tailor, is gifted.</description></item><item><title>A Review of Andrew Rowes's How to Defeat a Demon King in Ten Easy Steps. Hilarious love letter to Zelda.</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/how_to_defeat_a_demon_king_in_ten_easy_steps/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/how_to_defeat_a_demon_king_in_ten_easy_steps/</guid><description>Let&amp;rsquo;s preface this real quick: this book is a short and fun read. It is not a sweeping fantasy series, it is not a classic zero-to-hero progression fantasy. It is a love letter to Zelda and other games, making fun of many video game tropes by highlighting just how ridiculous and obvious many are.
The main character finds a way to inventively use their class (A Bag Mage) to break various game systems.</description></item><item><title>A review of T.J. Reynold's 'Seventh Bridge to the Heavens'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/seventh_bridge_to_the_heavens/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/seventh_bridge_to_the_heavens/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m writing this review after reading book one, I&amp;rsquo;ll grab book two once it&amp;rsquo;s out and update this page.
For those wanting to get straight into action and cultivation, don&amp;rsquo;t skip over this book. The first small arc sets up the main character, the world, and the cultures in it wonderfully.
The story follows the Quiet Luca, a soldier whose core didn&amp;rsquo;t awaken, who served in the squad of stone-bending cultivators.</description></item><item><title>A review of Maxime J. Durand's 'The Perfect Run'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/perfect_run/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/perfect_run/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a quite a few years since the Alchemist distributed Elixirs into the world, each which grant a unique super power. Since then, modern civilisation has collapsed, because giving some people phenomenal power tends to go badly a lot of the time. Quicksave begins the book searching for his childhood friend, Len, and determined to go through every chapter in his life with a perfect run. Which, as you might have guessed from the hero name, is possible thanks to his ability to set a checkpoint in time he can revert to on death.</description></item><item><title>A Review of Dakota Krout's Completionist Chronicles and Ritualist from a grumpy LitRPG reader</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/completionist_chronicles/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/completionist_chronicles/</guid><description>Completionist Chronicles is set in the same universe as Divine Dungeon. Or more so, it&amp;rsquo;s set inside the Dungeon, with a weird tie into modern-day Earth. I&amp;rsquo;ll focus this write-up on the first book, Ritualist.
Let&amp;rsquo;s get that out of the way - the book has a weird opening. It&amp;rsquo;s the end of the world, and President Elon [Musk] encourages everyone to start a new life in a new world before vanishing into thin air (transported into the dungeon&amp;rsquo;s constructed LitRPG world).</description></item><item><title>A review of J.L. Mullins' 'Millenial Mage'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/millenial_mage/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/millenial_mage/</guid><description>As of writing this review, I&amp;rsquo;ve read all 224 published chapters.
Blurb The world is wild, untamed. Humanity thrives, but only in isolated, well defended cities, ever shrinking as the wilds slowly reclaim all that was taken. The most capable magic users are raised up as Mages to serve mankind, further their cause, and defend them over the course of millennia.
Tala is freshly graduated from the magic academy and determined to make her own way in the world.</description></item><item><title>A Review of Louis Kalman's 'Desolada'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/desolada/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/desolada/</guid><description>As of the time of writing this review, I have read the available book: A Blade Through Time.
Blurb A young man with magical gifts is caught in an immortal battle between demons and demigods in the first book of this grimdark fantasy series.
Leones Ansteri was only sixteen when they came to kill him for the heresies his father had committed against the Archons—the mighty demigods who keep the peace in the Civilized Lands and prevent the evil Goetia from enslaving all of humanity.</description></item><item><title>A Review of Avitue's 'And (N)one Shall Remain'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/and_none_shall_remain/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/and_none_shall_remain/</guid><description>As of the time of writing this review, I have read the available chapters (chapter 40).
Blurb Two Lives, Two Souls, Both forced down into their roles,
One in the Light, One in the Dark, As the Fates portend,
One to uphold, one to turn over the Mores,
Would they Save the World, or Bring it to its End?
A story where things might not be what they seem like.</description></item><item><title>A Review of Honour Rae's 'All The Skills'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/all_the_skills/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/all_the_skills/</guid><description>As of the time of writing this review, I have read the available chapters (chapter 30 in book two or so).
Blurb The most Arthur could hope for was to someday earn a trash-tier spell card. When fate grants him a Master of Skills card, he&amp;rsquo;s thrust into a world of opportunity and danger.
To survive and grow strong, Arthur must learn skills. All the skills.
Thoughts Damn, that blurb is light, isn&amp;rsquo;t it?</description></item><item><title>A Review of Jamie Kojola's 'Odyssey of the Ethereal'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/odyssey_of_the_ethereal/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/odyssey_of_the_ethereal/</guid><description>As of the time of writing this review, I have read the available chapters (chapter 31).
Blurb Aesca Lampi was a skilled MMO player and raid leader, but she never could have predicted the turn her life would take when she died and was reborn as Aetheria, a chosen hero tasked with overthrowing the Goddess of Misery and bringing hope to the suffering world of Grief. Armed with the power of regeneration and a fierce determination, Aetheria sets out to climb the Ten Towers and fulfill her destiny.</description></item><item><title>A Review of C. Mantis' 'The Path of Ascension', a sci-fi wuxia novel with a staggering range of powers and power divides.</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/path_ascension/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/path_ascension/</guid><description>This was another read courtesy of recommendations from /r/ProgressionFantasy. It&amp;rsquo;s only on Royal Road (at the time of writing), but I hope it reaches a wider audience soon when the author has a chance to go back and package it all up nicely.
The Path of Ascension follows the journey of our tragically orphaned MC, Matt. Matt&amp;rsquo;s parents were killed in a rift break. If you&amp;rsquo;ve read Solo Levelling or many other rift/portal/dunegon based novels, this is fairly standard.</description></item><item><title>A review of Momo's 'Martial Peak'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/martial_peak/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/martial_peak/</guid><description>As of writing this review, I have read &amp;gt;1500 chapters of the manhua.
Blurb The journey to the martial peak is a lonely, solitary and long one. In the face of adversity, you must survive and remain unyielding. Only then can you break through and continue on your journey to become the strongest. Sky Tower tests its disciples in the harshest ways to prepare them for this journey. One day the lowly sweeper Yang Kai managed to obtain a black book, setting him on the road to the peak of the martial world.</description></item><item><title>A review of Zamil Akhtar's Lightblade</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/lightblade/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/lightblade/</guid><description>Disclosure: I received this book in advance and without cost in exchange for an honest review. Counter-disclosure: I already pay for KU, so I would have been able to read it for &amp;lsquo;free&amp;rsquo; anyway.
Initially, the premise of this book seemed super intense. Lightblades obviously give you some Star Wars vibes, the magic system is focused around different wavelengths of light, which gives me Lightbringer vibes, and then the focus on dreams, time-dilation, and the existential question &amp;ldquo;Is this the real world&amp;rdquo; combine Inception and the Matrix.</description></item><item><title>A review of Harmon Cooper's 'The World According to Dragons'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/the_world_according_to_dragons/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/the_world_according_to_dragons/</guid><description>Blurb An infamous relic hunter. A legendary dragon. The journey of a lifetime.
Twillo lies bleeding out in a volcanic desert. Towering over him is a snarling red wolf, death only seconds away.
Right as his vision is going black, a mysterious voice offers Twillo a chance at survival.
Do you agree to bind souls?
It is the voice of a dragon, one that hasn&amp;rsquo;t been seen for hundreds of years.</description></item><item><title>A review of KamikazePotato's 'An Outcast In Another World'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/outcast_in_another_world/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/outcast_in_another_world/</guid><description>This review was written after I had read all three published books. I&amp;rsquo;m waiting on the Kindle version instead of reading on RR so I can give the author my money.
If you liked HWFWM, Defiance of the Fall, Primal Hunter, or Randidly, you&amp;rsquo;ll like this series.
Initially, I was worried when the starting chapters felt very close to both DoT and Primal Hunter. Young white man in a forest with dangerous beasts&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;ve read that few too many times for it to still hold the magic it originally held with me.</description></item><item><title>A review of K.T. Hanna's 'Somnia Online'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/somnia/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/somnia/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m writing this review as of reading the first three books. I&amp;rsquo;ll update it when I finish the series at a later date.
Somnia Online follows the journey of Wren, her best friend Harlow, and their guild, Fable. The premise, at the start, is simple. Wren&amp;rsquo;s mother is the lead designer for a massive vrmmo game, which offers unparalleled immersive via a headset which reads your brainwaves. Except, of course, the game is really just a test bed for the development for the games AI and the headset technology, which is funded by the military.</description></item><item><title>A Review of Noret Flood's 'The Legend of Randidly Ghosthound', a great take on system takeover LitRPG.</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/randidly_ghosthound/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/randidly_ghosthound/</guid><description>Note: I&amp;rsquo;ve read the Amazon Book One, and then Royal Road chapters up to around Chapter 300 (ie many books worth). This review uses all of the content I&amp;rsquo;ve read, but I&amp;rsquo;ll make sure to separate book vs royal road if you&amp;rsquo;re thinking of buying. Actually, scrap that, just buy the first book, its great, and then continue on RR if you want.
So let&amp;rsquo;s begin with the basic premise. Earth is taken over by the System, and it becomes an effective post-apocalypse LitRPG adventure, which is fairly normal for the genre.</description></item><item><title>A Review of Chris Fox's Shattered Gods series. A great new entry into progression fantasy.</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/shattered_gods/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/shattered_gods/</guid><description>In the book, you follow the adventures of Xal. Xal is a child of the dims, an oppressed group of people feared by the ruling class and used as cannon fodder. Xal gets conscripted and sent to tie in the trash legion, and the adventures of this legion, plus the Academy afterwards, show him progressing in power and being inducted into the wider political landscape, wherein he has very few friends and a great many enemies.</description></item><item><title>A Review of Dakota Krout's Divine Dungeon Series.</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/divine_dungeon/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/divine_dungeon/</guid><description>This is another series I&amp;rsquo;ve read which I got instantly hooked on with a great premise, only to feel a bit let down at the conclusion many books later.
That said, I&amp;rsquo;ve read this series more than once, so it must be doing something right!
The Divine Dungeon series was my introduction to dungeon-core novels, and for that, I thank you, Dakota Krout. What this means is you follow the development of a sentient dungeon rather than a human character for most of the series.</description></item><item><title>A review of J. McCoy's 'RE: Monarch'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/remonarch/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/remonarch/</guid><description>Blurb To save the kingdom, he&amp;rsquo;ll have to stop his own murder&amp;hellip;
It’s hard to be a drunken idiot when the world keeps burning down around you. Cairn, the charming-yet-utterly-irresponsible heir to the Uskarrion throne, is all too happy to toss the crown aside. But an invasion, conspiracy, and rise of a terrifying villain result in his untimely death.
Then, Cairn reawakens. It&amp;rsquo;s a decade earlier and he&amp;rsquo;s in his childhood body.</description></item><item><title>A review of Davis Ashura's 'The Eternal Ephemera'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/eternal_ephemera/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/eternal_ephemera/</guid><description>As of writing this review, I have read Blood of a Novice, and received a copy as an ARC reader.
Blurb Cam Folde will shake the very fabric of creation&amp;hellip; or see all his hopes turn to ash.
The son of the town drunk, Cam never figured on letting his family name hold him down. He always strove to dream bigger, to fight for something better, to achieve more than what everyone else expected of him.</description></item><item><title>A review of Michael G. Manning's 'Art of the Adept'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/art_of_the_adept/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/art_of_the_adept/</guid><description>What a roller coaster this read was. Our plot follows Will, who awakens his magic when healing a young boys infection. He is sent to live with his grandfather (of sorts), who becomes a slow and painful magical tutelage, laced with acerbic dialogue and insults around every corner. The dynamic between the two is a joy to read. Eventually, the plot moves on, Will has to spread his wings. As to why, and when, and how, I won&amp;rsquo;t say, because it all falls under spoiler territory.</description></item><item><title>A Review of Jame A. Hunter's Rogue Dungeon. Light-hearted fun.</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/rogue_dungeon/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/rogue_dungeon/</guid><description>Review based on reading the first three books: Rogue Dungeon, Civil War, and Troll Nation.
Roark von Graf lives in a fantasy world, trying to overthrow a tyrant. By weird magic, he is teleported into an Earth video game into a troll&amp;rsquo;s body, and his goal is to get back to his world with enough power to overthrow the tyrant.
It&amp;rsquo;s a weird premise, having the MC not be a normal Earthman, but still having them inhabit an Earth video game where player characters are regular people.</description></item><item><title>A Review of Travis Bagwell's Awaken Online. A necromancer MC games the system as much as he can.</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/awaken_online/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/awaken_online/</guid><description>Disclaimer: the thoughts in this review come from reading the first seven books of the series. The series is ongoing.
To kick things off, if you like overpowered main characters and don&amp;rsquo;t mind game systems or balances that blatantly favour the protagonist, you&amp;rsquo;ll enjoy this series a lot.
If you&amp;rsquo;re on the fence, I&amp;rsquo;d highly recommend reading at least the first book. It&amp;rsquo;s definitely the best of the ones that I&amp;rsquo;ve read so far.</description></item><item><title>A Review of Shirtaloon's He Who Fights With Monsters, a great LitRPG with an opinionated protagonist.</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/hwfwm/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/hwfwm/</guid><description>Jason, our MC, is simultaneously this series greatest strengths and greatest weakness.
Transported to a magical world, Jason is thrown into some truly unfortunate circumstances right off the bat. Weirdly there&amp;rsquo;s very little detail given about Jason and his past life, apart from a few vague comments about it not exactly being ideal (I mean, he was Australian, just like me, so points for that), but there&amp;rsquo;s no time to dwell on that as Jason struggles to survive against a host of organisations, beasts, and eventually eldritch horrors.</description></item><item><title>A Review of Zogarth's LitRPG 'The Primal Hunter'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/primal_hunter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/primal_hunter/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m just going to come out and say it. If you&amp;rsquo;ve read Defiance of the Fall and enjoyed it, you will love The Primal Hunter. It has a similar premise, similar (minimal) base-building and progression, but with better characters and less deus ex machina.
Now, to be fair, the author gets away with a lot on the social side of characterisation by making the main character incredibly anti-social, and then befriending a pair of (sentient) birds.</description></item><item><title>A review of Benjamin Kerei's 'Oh Great! I was Reincarnated as a Farmer'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/reincarnated_as_a_farmer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/reincarnated_as_a_farmer/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m writing this review after reading book one, I&amp;rsquo;ll grab book two once it&amp;rsquo;s out and update this page.
The premise of the book is fairly simple. Through some unfortunate accident, the MC (Arnold) is taken from Earth and his job as a semi-pro gamer, and reincarnated in the body of a farmer. The world has levels and a class based system (without it being a &amp;lsquo;capital S&amp;rsquo; system), and classes can&amp;rsquo;t be changed.</description></item><item><title>A Review of Sarah Lin's The Brightest Shadow - great subversion of a genre trope.</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/brightest_shadow/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/brightest_shadow/</guid><description>Disclaimer: the thoughts in this review come from reading only the first book of the series. I have not read &amp;lsquo;A Hollow Mountain&amp;rsquo;, yet.
I enjoyed the read of The Brightest Shadow a few weeks ago during my end of year holiday. I&amp;rsquo;d been slowly making my way through the novel for a month or so before that, as I initially struggled with the slower pacing of the work. In that way, it reminds me a lot of A Thousand Li (in that I struggled with the slice-of-life plodding along).</description></item><item><title>A Review of Andrew Seiple's Threadbare. Adorable, unique, and fascinating.</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/threadbare/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/threadbare/</guid><description>This review focuses on the trilogy as a whole, not subsequent entries.
I will admit to some skepticism when I read the original premise - the main character is a stuffed bear.
But, in a fit of whimsy, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d give it a shot.
This was, as it turns out, a wonderful decision.
Threadbare follows the journey of the eponymous bear&amp;rsquo;s quest to try and find and save the daughter of his creator and his best friend - Cecelia Gearheart.</description></item><item><title>A Review of Yrsillar's Forge of Destiny</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/forge_of_destiny/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/forge_of_destiny/</guid><description>Forge of Destiny starts like many cultivation novels. Plucky young girl from the streets, Ling Qi, has the talent and joins the Sect of Argent Peak. She then struggles to rise up in the inner rankings of the Sect. It has your normal progression systems, spiritual pills, removing impurities, it has moves and techniques, a vide cast of characters, but at the end of the day I wasn&amp;rsquo;t drawn in.</description></item><item><title>A Review of 'Defiance of the Fall', a system-apocalypse LitRPG / cultivation hybrid.</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/defiance_of_the_fall/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/defiance_of_the_fall/</guid><description>As of the time of writing this review, I have read all four books on KU, and a further 200 chapters on RR, up to and including the time skip.
So Defiance of the Fall did hook me in, and the author is great at leaving each chapter with a teaser, cliffhanger, or something to get you thinking &amp;ldquo;Okay, just one more.&amp;rdquo; It had the same vibes as when I&amp;rsquo;m playing Civilisation, and it&amp;rsquo;s why I ended up reading several million words before I put the story down.</description></item><item><title>A review of Michael Nwanolue's 'The Tower Unbroken'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/tower_unbroken/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/tower_unbroken/</guid><description>I do like me a good cultivation story, and so when I asked for some recommendations and someone pointed out that there is a little-known work featuring African-inspired cultivation, I put it to the top of my list.
And here we are!
The Tower Unbroken follows Somadina&amp;rsquo;s journey from his village out into the wider world. He starts off as the lowliest rank of cultivator, or dibias as they are called in this setting.</description></item><item><title>A physicist reviews Dominic Stal's 'The Last Physicist'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/last_physicist/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/last_physicist/</guid><description>For those coming here from reddit or similar, I&amp;rsquo;ll come clean. I had high expectations for this book. As a physicist myself, a book about a physicist using the scientific method to put some hard rules to magic and delve into the mechanics had me almost giddy with excitement. So I dove into this book, and, I&amp;rsquo;ll be frank, came away disappointed.
The book follows the MC, Will. In another fun coincidence, Will works at Fermilab in Chicago.</description></item><item><title>A review of Samer Rabadi's 'Eight'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/eight/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/eight/</guid><description>Blurb Life’s tough when you’re trapped in an eight-year-old body on another world.
His name is Eight. Not really, but that’s what the System decided after a slip of the tongue. One moment, he was stepping out the office door on the way home, and the next waking up on a hillside below a town wall. Oh, and the gate guard drove him off, because he thought Eight was a monster.</description></item><item><title>Tao Wong's A Thousand Li - classical cultivation doled out sparingly</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/thousand_li/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/thousand_li/</guid><description>Disclaimer: Due to Tao Wong filing infringement notices against LitRPG authors for using &amp;ldquo;System&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Apocalypse&amp;rdquo;, I&amp;rsquo;m not continuing with this series. There are plenty of authors who add positively to this community that I can support instead of someone who tries to tear it down.
I had heard great things about this series, and A Thousand Li is a staple on the cultivation and progression fantasy reading lists. So take this review with a grain of salt, that obviously my take here may not be reflective of the wider community.</description></item><item><title>A Review of Chugong's Solo Levelling - an engaging take on the genre.</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/solo_levelling/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/solo_levelling/</guid><description>Note: this review is based off the novel. I have heard the manhua doesn&amp;rsquo;t have many of the issues I&amp;rsquo;ve pointed out and recommend reading that instead.
Here&amp;rsquo;s the rough premise of Solo Levelling. The world was all normal, but now dungeon gates open, and teams of hunters have to enter, clear the dungeon and kill its boss. This will ensure the gates close. If they don&amp;rsquo;t close it in a week, the dungeon monsters can escape.</description></item><item><title>A Review of Brent Weeks' Lightbringer Series. Such a promising beginning with such an awful ending.</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/lightbringer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/lightbringer/</guid><description>This review will have some light spoilers.
The first three books of this series were amazing. Watching Kip, our main character, be bought from his destroyed village to the Chromeria, train with the Blackguard, develop his chromaturgy fantastic. Watching Gavin* build the Brightwater Wall in the face of the oncoming army of the Color Prince, gripping. Koios White Oak and her growth out of the Blackguard, superb.
The world-building was unique, deep enough to engage, but simple enough to grasp quickly.</description></item><item><title>A Review of Aleron Kong's Chaos Seeds Series: A tale of the luckiest man in the world</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/chaos_seeds/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/chaos_seeds/</guid><description>Is the Chaos Seeds series a fun read?
For sure.
Is it sensible? Is it serious? Is it consistent?
No.
If you don&amp;rsquo;t care about that and just want a light-hearted, fun read, maybe this series is for you.
Me, I thought that I don&amp;rsquo;t need anything series. Damn, I finished Malazan and I need a multi-year palate cleanser to get over the cauldron of tragedy in that series. However, I almost put down this series a few times.</description></item><item><title>A Review of Andries Louws' The Dao of Magic. A strange blend of pop references and ridiculously overpowered protagonists</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/dao_magic/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/dao_magic/</guid><description>I link to the Amazon publication, however, I read the Royal Road version. If there have been future substantial changes to the series since I read it, this review may not be accurate.
Drew, originally from Earth, has spent a thousand years or so cultivating on another world. He goes to ascend, but, oh no, something goes wrong, and he is send to a different world instead, to start from scratch.</description></item></channel></rss>