<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>outreach on Samuel Hinton</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tags/outreach/</link><description>Recent content in outreach on Samuel Hinton</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tags/outreach/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Datascience Pipelines</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/dsgo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/dsgo/</guid><description>Due to COVID-19 lots of conferences have moved online in 2020. DatascienceGo is one of those conferences, and I was invited to give a workshop on datascience pipelines. This invite comes off the back of some discussions and media about my role in the COVID-19 Critical Care Consortium and creating their data processing pipeline, which has been a challenging project.
For the workshop, I thought it best to try and generalise the content slightly, and instead of talking about all the different things you can do to data and the headaches we&amp;rsquo;ve had to deal with, to instead talk about machine learning and how you can add tracking and logging to your processes super simply using the amazing mlflow library.</description></item><item><title>SDS Podcast - Pipelines</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/sds_pipelines/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/sds_pipelines/</guid><description>Shifting away from astrophysics briefly, I talk about my experience as a lead data analyst for the COVID-19 Critical Care Consortium, and my role with them to create a data pipeline to unify, standardise and merge data from a billion different forms across multiple research projects into something that actually has value for statistical analysis and machine learning.
Listen to the entire chat here, or grab the summary on pipelines from the (yet another) super pretty infographic below from the SDS team!</description></item><item><title>Science Friction</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/sciencefriction/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/sciencefriction/</guid><description>During the early days of the COVID-19 outburst I was recruited into the COVID-19 Critical Care Consortium (then called ECMOCARD) as the lead data analyst, responsible for setting up a data reduction and cleaning pipeline for the consortium, in addition to producing reports, graphs and dashboards for clinical staff and consortium members.
I had a chat with Natasha Mitchell about how this all came about, its relations to astronomy and more in an episode of Science Friction.</description></item><item><title>SDS Podcast - Hypothesis Testing</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/sds_hypothesis/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/sds_hypothesis/</guid><description>I like to rant about a lot of things. Many of those things include abuses of statistics, p-hacking, improper hypotheses and sensationalist media. Listen to the entire rant here, or grab the summary of how to formulate a proper hypothesis from the pretty infographic below!</description></item><item><title>LINO19</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/lindau/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/lindau/</guid><description>In the winter of 2019 I was one of the lucky students chosen to represent Australia and participate in the 2019 Lindau Nobel Laureates Meeting. The topics of the year were awesome - cosmology, gravitational waves and laser physics. What a lineup.
So here is the Australian contingent, in a very sunny lineup outside the meeting venue. We requested slight cloud cover. It was not supplied.
Inside, the hall was amazing.</description></item><item><title>Coding@Home</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/codingathome/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/codingathome/</guid><description>During the school shutdown during the COVID-19 outbreak in Australia, Education Queensland partnered with Channel 10 to produce the Coding@Home series - a series of episodes available for free on TenPlay about introducing code, concepts and all the ways you can use coding in your life.
I reached out about my experiences with coding in astrophysics, and we recorded a short segment focused on machine learning, and how it has improved the lives of the average astronomer by a huge amount.</description></item><item><title>Pint of Science 2019</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/pint19/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/pint19/</guid><description>I did Pint of Science originally in 2017 and had a blast. For 2018, I was stranded on a beach in Fiji and unable to participate. But for 2019, I was all in!
And because the original talk seemed to go down so well, I decided to try and challenge myself a bit more by picking a topic far harder for a general audience to visualise. I decided to talk about Baryon Acoustic Oscillations - frozen sound waves in space.</description></item><item><title>Probably Science Podcast</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/probablyscience/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/probablyscience/</guid><description>It turns out when you throw three comedians together on stage its super hard to keep up with the banter! I was the guest scientist invite on the amazing Probably Science podcast.
The episode should be live right now, so give it a listen, especially if you have a love for koalas.</description></item><item><title>BrisScience Lecture</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/brissicence/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/brissicence/</guid><description>In November I gave one of the monthly public lectures for UQ&amp;rsquo;s BrisScience event. We had a good little chat for the hour, first going over the history of the universe.
Fourteen minutes for fourteen billion years of cosmic history, sounds doable, right? Well, you need context to appreciate the second half of the talk.
That second half was then a very short introduction to dark energy and dark matter. What they might be, why we believe so strongly that they exist</description></item><item><title>Astronomy at Gumdale</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/gumdale/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/gumdale/</guid><description>Astronomy is great fun. So is coding. At least to me. But, I was invited to talk at Gumdale State School, I decided that it would be good to spread the good message out there and drum up some enthusiasm for space, science and STEM in general.
I think the trick with younger students is to constantly ask questions and get input, because talking for an hour at them will either put them to sleep or make them so restless you might as well not be talking, so that&amp;rsquo;s what I did.</description></item><item><title>readr 2017</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/readr/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/readr/</guid><description>Nearing the tail end of the year I got a wonderful opportunity to expand the work I had been doing with my coding workshops to also take them to the 2017 readr retreat. readr - a research education and development retreat - is open to all undergraduate physics students in Australia, not just astrophysics students.
I had to trim a lot of content as I went from a whole day workshop to a three hour block with breaks included.</description></item><item><title>Code Workshop</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/codeworkshop/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/codeworkshop/</guid><description>The idea to run a code workshop was born at the 2016 CAASTRO Annual Retreat. Fiona and I were talking to Elaine about the problems we have had with the self-taught style of coding the most astronomers work with, specifically the lack of structure, documentation and testing that so often accompanies astronomical projects and packages.
To fix this, we volunteered to run a code workshop, with a focus on teaching the astronomical community better coding standards, better practises, giving them better tools and better resources.</description></item><item><title>Physics in the Pub</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/pub/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/pub/</guid><description>Physics in the Pub came to Brisbane! With the esteemed Dr Phil Dooley as MC for the night, we had a great evening of eight physics acts. Whilst I trying to impress the sheer scale and significance of supernovae on the audience, I was definitely not the star of the show that night!
Chris Mesiku sang a reggae song about $$E=mc^2$$ and Einstein. Phil himself sang a cover of Nirvana about particle physics and light.</description></item><item><title>Battle of the Brains</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/botb/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/botb/</guid><description>As part of The Science Nation&amp;rsquo;s National Science Week set of activities, I was given the opportunity to participate in Battle of the Brains! Andrew Stephenson hosted the event, and kept the six guest scientists neatly in line throughout the event.
We set up on stage, I of course didn&amp;rsquo;t speak into the microphone correctly, and an audience member came up and adjusted it mid-sentence to much laughter.
It was a great night where I got nearly every question wrong!</description></item><item><title>Pint of Science 2017</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/pint/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/pint/</guid><description>During the week of the 14th of May there were a host of Pint of Science events presented in Brisbane. Josh and I did one together - Josh presented a talk Dark matter, what&amp;rsquo;s the matter?, where he talked about the dark universe, and potential candidates for dark matter. I gave a talk The Brightest Fireworks in the Universe - on supernovae, their lives, deaths and role in the universe.</description></item><item><title>ScopeTV Guest Scientist</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/scope/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/scope/</guid><description>Every now and then ScopeTV has a space focused episode, and they look up some local scientists to help present the content for one of their episodes. Janie and I were asked if we wanted to participate in an episode focused on the size and scale of the solar system, and obviously we thought it was a great idea, so we jumped on it!
I&amp;rsquo;m sure you&amp;rsquo;ve seen similar demonstrations - start with the sun a huge ball that you can barely carry, and work your way down to the other planets at physically accurate (albeit scaled down) distances.</description></item><item><title>Famelab 2017</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/famelab/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/famelab/</guid><description>Famelab is a science communication challenge where PhD students have three minutes, no slides, no video and one prop - if they so choose - to share your thesis work to a live audience!
I prepared a short segment on supernovae and their role in the universe. But before the night itself, we had a short segement with Rebecca Levingston on ABC&amp;rsquo;s Saturday Breakfast radio. It was my first radio spot, and I admit I was definitely not as eloquent as I wanted!</description></item><item><title>An Evening with Dr Lisa Randall</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/lisa/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/lisa/</guid><description>In November 2016, Lisa Randall gave an Australian tour in the big cities. As normal for ThinkInc events, they had a local scientist give an introductory talk to warm up the audience.
I decided to give a brief talk about the current state of physics, and gave a brief explanation of the physics behind the Hubble Space Telescope, the Large Hadron Collider, eLISA, LIGO and a few other great experiments.</description></item><item><title>Uluru Astronomer in Residence</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/uluru/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/uluru/</guid><description>I highly recommend this experience to all other CAASTRO students. I was only at Ayers Rock Resort for a week and enjoyed myself immensely. The time you have to talk to the general public, play educational games with the kids, answer interesting questions at the AstroTours and take your own pictures of the night sky makes it a great experience.
I was an emergency replacement, hence why I went for one week and not two, however one week was plenty of time to settle into a comfortable routine focused on public outreach.</description></item></channel></rss>