<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>travel on Samuel Hinton</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tags/travel/</link><description>Recent content in travel on Samuel Hinton</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tags/travel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A weekend in Scotland</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/scotland/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/scotland/</guid><description>After many, many months in lockdown, Kirrilee and I managed to finally get away for a short break.
Given that country borders are still closed (and at this point we&amp;rsquo;re still waiting for a vaccine) the options were fairly limited. However, Scotland has been on both of our lists for a long time, so we decided to head up North and visit the Isle of Skye.
After a long train to Edinburg we picked up a rental car and start the rush to our AirBnB before it got completely dark.</description></item><item><title>SIEF Berlin</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/siefberlin/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/siefberlin/</guid><description>After the Lindau Nobel Laureate Meeting all the Australian delegates packed up shop, jumped on a train and headed to Berlin. It was time for our industry tour, courtesy of the Science and Industry Endowment Fund in Australia.
There&amp;rsquo;s one main takeaway here, its that actually providing proper funding to research has some amazing benefits.
I digress. I don&amp;rsquo;t have too much to say in here apart from how great it was to see so many labs in so many areas, all working towards scientific and technological progress.</description></item><item><title>Europe Strikes Back</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/europe2019/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/europe2019/</guid><description>The Zurich Introduction In a move which will surprise noone, we begin in Zurich. Unbeknown to us, it turns out that the very day we arrived in Zurich was the day they were hosting a gay pride march. Predictably, we found out about this at 5pm. After the march. Sigh.
But of course, once the official march ends, the real party begins, and there were concerts, a drag show, tons of food and general revelry.</description></item><item><title>Return to Cradle Mountain</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/tasmania_2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/tasmania_2/</guid><description>The last time I went to Tasmania I did the Overland track.
And I was not prepared. No water-proof gear, no thick jackets, just my stubbornness. Which, as it turns out, cannot keep you warm.
So this time I cam prepared. Totally waterproof jacket. A down jacket. A merinio wool jacket! All the stops. And it was worth it. From Hobart we drove to Wineglass bay, whic was a series of ups and down designed to swell your thighs to impressive sizes.</description></item><item><title>Cosmology on Safari</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/southafrica/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/southafrica/</guid><description>Every two years the amazing Cosmology on Safari conference is held.
And in 2019 I was lucky enough to not only go, but present a topic clear to my heart. My own research!
Not to miss out on the opportunity to see a bit more of Africa given I was flying over anyway, I also did a small camping trip through South Africa. And Botswana. And Zimbabwe. Only dipped my toes into Namibia though.</description></item><item><title>Visiting Chicago</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/chicago/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/chicago/</guid><description>Once again escaping the Australian winter, I found myself residing in the temperate Bay area. But I was still cold. And so to Chicago I went&amp;hellip; coincidentally, this was at the same time as a DES collaboration meeting.
This visit now marks my greatest journey east into the US. I would have liked to go to New York and visit the city, just to make that statement incorrect, but alas, neither time nor money can be spared for such an adventure.</description></item><item><title>Japan Winter Holiday</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/japan/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/japan/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s good to get away sometimes.
Especially good if you make sure you don&amp;rsquo;t bring a laptop - no sneaky working during a holiday!
So in January 2017, I went to Japan. First stop, Mt Fuji.
After Fuji, straight to Kyoto. We went to a few of the shrines, the Silver and Golden Palaces, and the Fushimi Inari Shrine.
I didn&amp;rsquo;t quite realise how big the Fushimi Inari Shrine was - its not just one or two arches, there are kilometers of them.</description></item><item><title>LBNL - California</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/california/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/california/</guid><description>In the Australian summer of 2016 I went to study at Lawrence Berkeley National Labs for a couple of months with Alex Kim, working on my Bayesian model for supernova cosmology.
It was a very productive time, but that isn&amp;rsquo;t what this page is about; this page is about what I got up to outside of work.
The first thing to do when near San Francisco is to go to the Golden Gate Bridge.</description></item><item><title>Gemini - La Serena, Chile</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/gemini/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/gemini/</guid><description>Part One: The drafting They shipped us off December 8th. Three students sent out to the Gemini telescope in La Serena, Chile, to see what they could make of the situation. To see if they could survive.
I remember it like it was last just last month.
By some coincidence, it was. Exactly. I&amp;rsquo;m writing this on the 8th of January, at 5pm, after finishing a day of work.
This is us.</description></item><item><title>Overland Track - Tasmania</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/tasmania/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/tasmania/</guid><description>After uni was over one year, Julia told me she was thinking of doing the overland track in Tasmania. I had heard good things about the track, and so I decided to tag along!
I got some army rations off my mate Chris, and bought a ton of food from the store, loaded up some clothes and tools, threw them in my hiking back pack, and off we went.
The initial climb and day was marred by wet weather, but still offered some great views.</description></item><item><title>European Holiday</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/europe/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/europe/</guid><description>Its hard to condense down such a big trip into less than a small book, but here goes. Started in London, went to Paris &amp;amp; Nice. Travelled down to Rome, patted a lot of stray cats in the colosseum. Went to Monaco, and then to Munich (which was the best). Munich to the Rhine valley, and form there to the Netherlands.
Definitely am going to go back, especially to Germany and the Netherlands, once I have some time and money.</description></item></channel></rss>