<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>sci-fi on Samuel Hinton</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tags/sci-fi/</link><description>Recent content in sci-fi on Samuel Hinton</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tags/sci-fi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Review of Bryce O'Connor's Iron Prince. Scifi progression on actual digital steroids."</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/iron_prince/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/iron_prince/</guid><description>I normally approach scifi with skepticism. I studied astrophysics, and physics is a harsh mistress that is all to easy to try and abuse in works of science fiction. There&amp;rsquo;s one surefire way around this - magical tech. Or in this case, alien tech that is so advanced it might as well be magic. And with the soft scifi setting established, this allows Bryce to draw the best from fantasy, the best from LitRPG levelling, and combine them to make one of the best progression fantasy stories I have read in years.</description></item><item><title>A review of Rob J. Hayes' 'Titan Hoppers'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/titan_hoppers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/titan_hoppers/</guid><description>Blurb Courage Iro will shatter the Gates of Power to protect his fleet.
Born talentless, Iro has all but resigned himself to a life of drudgery, watching his sister hop across to the massive space titan for supplies. But when the titan explodes and his sister is killed, Iro finds a new determination to take her place. He’s not about to let weakness prevent him.
When the fleet encounters a new titan, filled with powerful monsters, deadly traps, and mysterious cloaked figures, Iro is the first to spontaneously manifest a new talent.</description></item><item><title>A Review of C. Mantis' 'The Path of Ascension', a sci-fi wuxia novel with a staggering range of powers and power divides.</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/path_ascension/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/path_ascension/</guid><description>This was another read courtesy of recommendations from /r/ProgressionFantasy. It&amp;rsquo;s only on Royal Road (at the time of writing), but I hope it reaches a wider audience soon when the author has a chance to go back and package it all up nicely.
The Path of Ascension follows the journey of our tragically orphaned MC, Matt. Matt&amp;rsquo;s parents were killed in a rift break. If you&amp;rsquo;ve read Solo Levelling or many other rift/portal/dunegon based novels, this is fairly standard.</description></item><item><title>A review of Zamil Akhtar's Lightblade</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/lightblade/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/lightblade/</guid><description>Disclosure: I received this book in advance and without cost in exchange for an honest review. Counter-disclosure: I already pay for KU, so I would have been able to read it for &amp;lsquo;free&amp;rsquo; anyway.
Initially, the premise of this book seemed super intense. Lightblades obviously give you some Star Wars vibes, the magic system is focused around different wavelengths of light, which gives me Lightbringer vibes, and then the focus on dreams, time-dilation, and the existential question &amp;ldquo;Is this the real world&amp;rdquo; combine Inception and the Matrix.</description></item></channel></rss>