<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>hard-magic on Samuel Hinton</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tags/hard-magic/</link><description>Recent content in hard-magic on Samuel Hinton</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tags/hard-magic/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Review of Andrew Rowe's Arcane Ascension Series: hard magic done right</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/arcane_ascension/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/arcane_ascension/</guid><description>My rating is for the series as a whole as of writing. It&amp;rsquo;s amazing. I&amp;rsquo;ll make sure this review focuses on Book One: Sufficiently Advanced Magic.
Corin Cadence is one of my favourite main characters in all of fantasy. He is, as I image many of us think, how we would approach being a person in a magical world. Analytically. Carefully. Exploitively.
So here&amp;rsquo;s the plot - you get powers (attunements) ostensibly from the goddess, via blessings you receive in the spires.</description></item><item><title>Reflections on my own 'Soul Relic'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/soul_relic/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/soul_relic/</guid><description>Born with an enormous well of power but no way to regenerate it, Raysha will risk anything to fix herself, even if it means venturing into the unknown with nothing but her brother, an enchanted water bottle, and a stubborn attitude.
Without the ability to cultivate aeon from the world, Raysha has been treated like an outcast her whole life. While she has to ration her power drop-by-drop, others use it as commonly as breathing.</description></item><item><title>A review of J.M. Clarke's 'Mark of the Fool'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/mark_of_the_fool/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/mark_of_the_fool/</guid><description>As of writing this review, I have read the KU release and up to chapter 200, which is about half-way through the available chapters.
So here&amp;rsquo;s the premise: Alex Roth is one of five chosen Heroes that need to defeat a reoccurring villain: The Ravener. Alex, however, is the Fool. His Mark, instead of making him a combat savant, powerful spellcaster, etc, makes him really great at learning things that are outside of combat and spellcasting&amp;hellip; but will actively interfere with his abilities if they are not.</description></item><item><title>A review of Sarah Lin's 'The Weirkey Chronicles'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/weirkey/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/weirkey/</guid><description>As of writing this, I have read all five released books, and will be picking up the next whenever it comes out!
Our MC, Theo, has spent decades searching for a way back into the magical realms of the Nine Worlds. After a bitter life with no success, he eventually finds his way back, only to confront the fact that the ideals of his younger self are only a distant memory to the man he now is.</description></item><item><title>A Review of Tobias Begley's progression fantasy work 'The Enchanter'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/enchanter/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/enchanter/</guid><description>Let&amp;rsquo;s get the obvious out the way and let me expand on the description above. If you&amp;rsquo;ve read the Arcane Ascension series and loved Corin&amp;rsquo;s approach to life, just save yourself some time, click the amazon link above, and go and get this book. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t, but you&amp;rsquo;ve read Mother of Learning and appreciated Zorian there, same comment.
Alright, let&amp;rsquo;s start with a spoiler-free summary. Our MC, Evander Tailor, is gifted.</description></item><item><title>A review of Davis Ashura's 'The Eternal Ephemera'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/eternal_ephemera/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/eternal_ephemera/</guid><description>As of writing this review, I have read Blood of a Novice, and received a copy as an ARC reader.
Blurb Cam Folde will shake the very fabric of creation&amp;hellip; or see all his hopes turn to ash.
The son of the town drunk, Cam never figured on letting his family name hold him down. He always strove to dream bigger, to fight for something better, to achieve more than what everyone else expected of him.</description></item><item><title>A Review of Brent Weeks' Lightbringer Series. Such a promising beginning with such an awful ending.</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/lightbringer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/lightbringer/</guid><description>This review will have some light spoilers.
The first three books of this series were amazing. Watching Kip, our main character, be bought from his destroyed village to the Chromeria, train with the Blackguard, develop his chromaturgy fantastic. Watching Gavin* build the Brightwater Wall in the face of the oncoming army of the Color Prince, gripping. Koios White Oak and her growth out of the Blackguard, superb.
The world-building was unique, deep enough to engage, but simple enough to grasp quickly.</description></item></channel></rss>