<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>time-loops on Samuel Hinton</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tags/time-loops/</link><description>Recent content in time-loops on Samuel Hinton</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tags/time-loops/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Review of nobody13's Mother of Learning. Time loops with a smart protagonist, done so very, very right.</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/mother_of_learning/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/mother_of_learning/</guid><description>I grew up on the Belgariad, graduated through Harry Potter to the Wheel of Time, conquered Malazan, was crushed by the Farseer Trilogy, and generally docked my ship at every fantasy port I could find.
Then I was recommended to read Mother of Learning. It was my first serial novel. And despite its 800k words, I read it in a week.
And then I read it again.
So many books I&amp;rsquo;ve read fumble the ending or the rising tension.</description></item><item><title>A review of Maxime J. Durand's 'The Perfect Run'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/perfect_run/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/perfect_run/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a quite a few years since the Alchemist distributed Elixirs into the world, each which grant a unique super power. Since then, modern civilisation has collapsed, because giving some people phenomenal power tends to go badly a lot of the time. Quicksave begins the book searching for his childhood friend, Len, and determined to go through every chapter in his life with a perfect run. Which, as you might have guessed from the hero name, is possible thanks to his ability to set a checkpoint in time he can revert to on death.</description></item><item><title>A Review of Louis Kalman's 'Desolada'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/desolada/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/desolada/</guid><description>As of the time of writing this review, I have read the available book: A Blade Through Time.
Blurb A young man with magical gifts is caught in an immortal battle between demons and demigods in the first book of this grimdark fantasy series.
Leones Ansteri was only sixteen when they came to kill him for the heresies his father had committed against the Archons—the mighty demigods who keep the peace in the Civilized Lands and prevent the evil Goetia from enslaving all of humanity.</description></item><item><title>A review of J. McCoy's 'RE: Monarch'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/remonarch/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/remonarch/</guid><description>Blurb To save the kingdom, he&amp;rsquo;ll have to stop his own murder&amp;hellip;
It’s hard to be a drunken idiot when the world keeps burning down around you. Cairn, the charming-yet-utterly-irresponsible heir to the Uskarrion throne, is all too happy to toss the crown aside. But an invasion, conspiracy, and rise of a terrifying villain result in his untimely death.
Then, Cairn reawakens. It&amp;rsquo;s a decade earlier and he&amp;rsquo;s in his childhood body.</description></item></channel></rss>