<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>cultivation on Samuel Hinton</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tags/cultivation/</link><description>Recent content in cultivation on Samuel Hinton</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tags/cultivation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Review of Will Wight's Cradle Series: The King of Progression Fantasy</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/cradle/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/cradle/</guid><description>Cradle is going to be tough to write a review for, because I don&amp;rsquo;t want to sound too biased, despite my love for the series.
I&amp;rsquo;ll focus upon the first few books here (Unsouled, Soulsmith, Blackflame) and try to keep spoilers for the rest of the series locked away in my heart.
The story follows a young man hailing from one of the clans of Sacred Valley. This is Lindon. He is, shall we say, unfairly treated by the clan, who believes he has no aptitude for the spiritual arts.</description></item><item><title>Reflections on my own 'Soul Relic'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/soul_relic/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/soul_relic/</guid><description>Born with an enormous well of power but no way to regenerate it, Raysha will risk anything to fix herself, even if it means venturing into the unknown with nothing but her brother, an enchanted water bottle, and a stubborn attitude.
Without the ability to cultivate aeon from the world, Raysha has been treated like an outcast her whole life. While she has to ration her power drop-by-drop, others use it as commonly as breathing.</description></item><item><title>A Review of Phil Tucker's Bastion. It's great.</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/bastion/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/bastion/</guid><description>Many progression fantasy series start with a similar pattern. An unfortunate, downtrodden, or unlucky individual is wronged, usually in an academic or sect environment, and then they claw their way through the classes, pushing themselves into excellence.
Bastion opens similarly, and I was preparing myself for a bit of &amp;lsquo;more of the same&amp;rsquo;. When the Chancellor starts explaining a points system for Academic progression through the Gauntlet (aka dungeon / spire / magical testing realm) a spark of worry lit inside me.</description></item><item><title>A review of Sarah Lin's 'The Weirkey Chronicles'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/weirkey/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/weirkey/</guid><description>As of writing this, I have read all five released books, and will be picking up the next whenever it comes out!
Our MC, Theo, has spent decades searching for a way back into the magical realms of the Nine Worlds. After a bitter life with no success, he eventually finds his way back, only to confront the fact that the ideals of his younger self are only a distant memory to the man he now is.</description></item><item><title>A Review of CasualFarmer's Cultivation novel 'Beware of Chicken'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/beware_of_chicken/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/beware_of_chicken/</guid><description>As of writing this review, I have read all 212 published chapters on Royal Road.
I saw this series recommended a few times on various groups and subreddits, but I always put it off because the name of the series didn&amp;rsquo;t exactly give me details about what it was about. The tidal wave of support for the work pushed me over the edge, so I picked it up&amp;hellip; and it turns out that was a great decision.</description></item><item><title>A Review of zechamp's 'DMG=MA: A Rolling Stone LitRPG'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/rolling_stone/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/rolling_stone/</guid><description>Blurb By a stroke of fate, a stone gains sentience and sets out on a grand quest to touch grass.
However, the system forgot to change its stats from their [Metric] values to the appropriate [Str, Int, Dex] values.
Things escalate. Fast.
Features:
Cultivation Jade Beauties Numbers go up (Ridiculously up. All of them) Most balanced protagonist of all time (is round, so is balanced) Thoughts As you might have guessed, I&amp;rsquo;ve read quite a few LitRPG, cutivation, and PF series.</description></item><item><title>A review of Striker's 'Virtuous Sons'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/virtuous_sons/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/virtuous_sons/</guid><description>Blurb Lio Aetos is the Young Aristocrat and heir apparent to a legendary Greek sect, a prodigious talent born and bred for glory.
Solus is a slave, a disgraced patrician from the fallen city of Rome with nothing to his name.
They&amp;rsquo;re as different as the East is from the West. Yet both of them hunger—to cast off the threads of Fate they’ve been given. To reach for a higher purpose.</description></item><item><title>A review of Alec Huston's 'Umbral Storm'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/umbral_storm/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/umbral_storm/</guid><description>Blurb A thousand years ago the Heart of the World was shattered, its fragments scattered across the lands. In the chaos that followed, martial orders arose to gather these shards, for it was found that great powers were granted when these pieces were bonded to the flesh of the chosen. These are the Sharded Few, warriors imbued with the divine energies that once coursed through the Heart, and driven to absorb enough fragments to claim godhood.</description></item><item><title>A review of T.J. Reynold's 'Seventh Bridge to the Heavens'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/seventh_bridge_to_the_heavens/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/seventh_bridge_to_the_heavens/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m writing this review after reading book one, I&amp;rsquo;ll grab book two once it&amp;rsquo;s out and update this page.
For those wanting to get straight into action and cultivation, don&amp;rsquo;t skip over this book. The first small arc sets up the main character, the world, and the cultures in it wonderfully.
The story follows the Quiet Luca, a soldier whose core didn&amp;rsquo;t awaken, who served in the squad of stone-bending cultivators.</description></item><item><title>A Review of C. Mantis' 'The Path of Ascension', a sci-fi wuxia novel with a staggering range of powers and power divides.</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/path_ascension/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/path_ascension/</guid><description>This was another read courtesy of recommendations from /r/ProgressionFantasy. It&amp;rsquo;s only on Royal Road (at the time of writing), but I hope it reaches a wider audience soon when the author has a chance to go back and package it all up nicely.
The Path of Ascension follows the journey of our tragically orphaned MC, Matt. Matt&amp;rsquo;s parents were killed in a rift break. If you&amp;rsquo;ve read Solo Levelling or many other rift/portal/dunegon based novels, this is fairly standard.</description></item><item><title>A review of Momo's 'Martial Peak'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/martial_peak/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/martial_peak/</guid><description>As of writing this review, I have read &amp;gt;1500 chapters of the manhua.
Blurb The journey to the martial peak is a lonely, solitary and long one. In the face of adversity, you must survive and remain unyielding. Only then can you break through and continue on your journey to become the strongest. Sky Tower tests its disciples in the harshest ways to prepare them for this journey. One day the lowly sweeper Yang Kai managed to obtain a black book, setting him on the road to the peak of the martial world.</description></item><item><title>A review of Harmon Cooper's 'The World According to Dragons'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/the_world_according_to_dragons/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/the_world_according_to_dragons/</guid><description>Blurb An infamous relic hunter. A legendary dragon. The journey of a lifetime.
Twillo lies bleeding out in a volcanic desert. Towering over him is a snarling red wolf, death only seconds away.
Right as his vision is going black, a mysterious voice offers Twillo a chance at survival.
Do you agree to bind souls?
It is the voice of a dragon, one that hasn&amp;rsquo;t been seen for hundreds of years.</description></item><item><title>A review of Davis Ashura's 'The Eternal Ephemera'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/eternal_ephemera/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/eternal_ephemera/</guid><description>As of writing this review, I have read Blood of a Novice, and received a copy as an ARC reader.
Blurb Cam Folde will shake the very fabric of creation&amp;hellip; or see all his hopes turn to ash.
The son of the town drunk, Cam never figured on letting his family name hold him down. He always strove to dream bigger, to fight for something better, to achieve more than what everyone else expected of him.</description></item><item><title>A Review of Sarah Lin's The Brightest Shadow - great subversion of a genre trope.</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/brightest_shadow/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/brightest_shadow/</guid><description>Disclaimer: the thoughts in this review come from reading only the first book of the series. I have not read &amp;lsquo;A Hollow Mountain&amp;rsquo;, yet.
I enjoyed the read of The Brightest Shadow a few weeks ago during my end of year holiday. I&amp;rsquo;d been slowly making my way through the novel for a month or so before that, as I initially struggled with the slower pacing of the work. In that way, it reminds me a lot of A Thousand Li (in that I struggled with the slice-of-life plodding along).</description></item><item><title>A Review of Yrsillar's Forge of Destiny</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/forge_of_destiny/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/forge_of_destiny/</guid><description>Forge of Destiny starts like many cultivation novels. Plucky young girl from the streets, Ling Qi, has the talent and joins the Sect of Argent Peak. She then struggles to rise up in the inner rankings of the Sect. It has your normal progression systems, spiritual pills, removing impurities, it has moves and techniques, a vide cast of characters, but at the end of the day I wasn&amp;rsquo;t drawn in.</description></item><item><title>A review of Michael Nwanolue's 'The Tower Unbroken'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/tower_unbroken/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/tower_unbroken/</guid><description>I do like me a good cultivation story, and so when I asked for some recommendations and someone pointed out that there is a little-known work featuring African-inspired cultivation, I put it to the top of my list.
And here we are!
The Tower Unbroken follows Somadina&amp;rsquo;s journey from his village out into the wider world. He starts off as the lowliest rank of cultivator, or dibias as they are called in this setting.</description></item><item><title>Tao Wong's A Thousand Li - classical cultivation doled out sparingly</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/thousand_li/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/thousand_li/</guid><description>Disclaimer: Due to Tao Wong filing infringement notices against LitRPG authors for using &amp;ldquo;System&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Apocalypse&amp;rdquo;, I&amp;rsquo;m not continuing with this series. There are plenty of authors who add positively to this community that I can support instead of someone who tries to tear it down.
I had heard great things about this series, and A Thousand Li is a staple on the cultivation and progression fantasy reading lists. So take this review with a grain of salt, that obviously my take here may not be reflective of the wider community.</description></item><item><title>A Review of Andries Louws' The Dao of Magic. A strange blend of pop references and ridiculously overpowered protagonists</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/dao_magic/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/dao_magic/</guid><description>I link to the Amazon publication, however, I read the Royal Road version. If there have been future substantial changes to the series since I read it, this review may not be accurate.
Drew, originally from Earth, has spent a thousand years or so cultivating on another world. He goes to ascend, but, oh no, something goes wrong, and he is send to a different world instead, to start from scratch.</description></item></channel></rss>