<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>writing on Samuel Hinton</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tags/writing/</link><description>Recent content in writing on Samuel Hinton</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tags/writing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Scion of Storms Art</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/darian_nexus/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/darian_nexus/</guid><description>I commissioned a settings piece from the amazing Richard Lay and I cannot stress how amazing it is.
Hosting it here so you can grab a higher resolution version if you want it than will be in the Kindle publication.</description></item><item><title>Cover Animations</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/cover_animations/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/cover_animations/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve wanted to animate my book cover for a while, but unsure about the best way to go about it. Some websites claim to do it for you using AI, but you have to pay for access, and are they good? Others offer it as a service, but prices range from $10USD into the hundreds, so would an expensive animation be worth the investment? Is there any real difference in what you&amp;rsquo;d get?</description></item><item><title>Scion of Storms Prologue</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/scion_of_storms_prologue/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/scion_of_storms_prologue/</guid><description>Manifestation, Book Two, is now in editing! To celebrate, I&amp;rsquo;m posting the prologue for all!
The Stormwall raged.
Lightning boomed from the black clouds above and thundered down into the gaping mouth of the maelstrom. An exposed claw of glass rising from the exposed seabed exploded as the strike connected.
Applicant Theolatos sat hidden on the floor of the ocean in a bubble of air held up solely by his will, undisturbed by the massive whirlpool only a stone&amp;rsquo;s throw away.</description></item><item><title>Lessons Learnt from Self Publishing</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/publishing_a_novel/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/publishing_a_novel/</guid><description>While writing up Soul Relic, I reached out to a lot of authors for their advice in getting the novel off the ground.
Thanks to John Bierce, Bryce O&amp;rsquo;Connor, Phil Tucker, J.R. Mathews, Tobias Begley, Travis M. Riddle, and everyone I&amp;rsquo;ve also pestered on reddit.
Some of this is obvious, others not as much. Here&amp;rsquo;s a rough timeline of how I would go about things if I had to start over.</description></item><item><title>Soul Relic Prologue</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/soul_relic_prologue/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/soul_relic_prologue/</guid><description>Set on the continent of Rhodus, the Soul Relic series follows Raysha as she grapples with her broken soul and inability to effectively channel the spiritual force of aeon. In a world where those who advance in the spiritual arts enough are regarded as gods, living without this ability means living at the bottom of society.
Not a place Raysha wants to remain.
Atareus looked down at the god weeping piteously by his feet.</description></item><item><title>The Continent of Rhodus</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/rhodus/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/rhodus/</guid><description>The continent of Rhodus is the main setting for my work Soul Relic.
The story begins in Hayet village in the nation of Darius, which you can find in the lower-left corner of the map. This is still a work in progress, and I might tweak or change things as times go on.
The resolution is quite high, so feel free to zoom in if you have the touchscreen for it.</description></item></channel></rss>