<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>python on Samuel Hinton</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tags/python/</link><description>Recent content in python on Samuel Hinton</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tags/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Datascience Pipelines</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/dsgo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/dsgo/</guid><description>Due to COVID-19 lots of conferences have moved online in 2020. DatascienceGo is one of those conferences, and I was invited to give a workshop on datascience pipelines. This invite comes off the back of some discussions and media about my role in the COVID-19 Critical Care Consortium and creating their data processing pipeline, which has been a challenging project.
For the workshop, I thought it best to try and generalise the content slightly, and instead of talking about all the different things you can do to data and the headaches we&amp;rsquo;ve had to deal with, to instead talk about machine learning and how you can add tracking and logging to your processes super simply using the amazing mlflow library.</description></item><item><title>SDS Podcast - Pipelines</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/sds_pipelines/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/sds_pipelines/</guid><description>Shifting away from astrophysics briefly, I talk about my experience as a lead data analyst for the COVID-19 Critical Care Consortium, and my role with them to create a data pipeline to unify, standardise and merge data from a billion different forms across multiple research projects into something that actually has value for statistical analysis and machine learning.
Listen to the entire chat here, or grab the summary on pipelines from the (yet another) super pretty infographic below from the SDS team!</description></item><item><title>Science Friction</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/sciencefriction/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/sciencefriction/</guid><description>During the early days of the COVID-19 outburst I was recruited into the COVID-19 Critical Care Consortium (then called ECMOCARD) as the lead data analyst, responsible for setting up a data reduction and cleaning pipeline for the consortium, in addition to producing reports, graphs and dashboards for clinical staff and consortium members.
I had a chat with Natasha Mitchell about how this all came about, its relations to astronomy and more in an episode of Science Friction.</description></item><item><title>Barry: BAO Model Comparison</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/barry/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/barry/</guid><description>BAO models are a dime a dozen these days. With multiple theroetical frameworks to start from (standard perturbation theory, Lagranian perturbation theory, effective field theory, etc), and with different models implemented to account for different physical effects, the phase space of viable BAO models is huge.
And this poses a problem for those of us wanting to utilise BAO models. How do we effectively compare them and their performance on a robust set of numerical simulations?</description></item><item><title>SDS Podcast - Hypothesis Testing</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/sds_hypothesis/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/sds_hypothesis/</guid><description>I like to rant about a lot of things. Many of those things include abuses of statistics, p-hacking, improper hypotheses and sensationalist media. Listen to the entire rant here, or grab the summary of how to formulate a proper hypothesis from the pretty infographic below!</description></item><item><title>Neural Style Transfer</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/ducky/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/ducky/</guid><description>I normally suck at giving presents. Horrifically. Probably because I&amp;rsquo;m a nightmare to buy for - I hate useless gifts. Ornaments, decorations&amp;hellip; &amp;ldquo;things&amp;rdquo; which aren&amp;rsquo;t functional.
It&amp;rsquo;s all clutter.
And because I don&amp;rsquo;t like receiving it, I don&amp;rsquo;t give it. Which means the struggle is always for a functional gift. But not this time! My sister has a cat called Ducky. Now, Ducky may not like me very much (breaks my heart), but Ali sure likes Ducky.</description></item><item><title>Steve: A model for supernova cosmology</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/steve/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/steve/</guid><description>As surveys discover greater numbers of supernova, our analyses become limited by systematics rather than data. Hierarchical Bayesian models are perfect for incorporating subtle effects into our model, and so I made one to do just that.
Supernova cosmology works because Type Ia supernova represent standardisable candles. That is, with a few factors taken into account, they are essentially all the same brightness. Which means, if we see two supernovae, and one is four times dimmer than the other, it must be twice as far away.</description></item><item><title>Setting up a scientific python environment</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/anaconda/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/anaconda/</guid><description>This writeup is primarily for the students of PHYS3080 at UQ, however it should be generally applicable. Firstly, let&amp;rsquo;s get the obvious out of the way. It&amp;rsquo;s 2018. Python 2.7 is dead. Long live Python 3!
Getting a Python Environment Up And Running So let&amp;rsquo;s get a nice python 3 environment set up. Don&amp;rsquo;t google python 3, that would be crazy. Use Anaconda. So head here to download it, and pick the Python 3 version, 64 bits.</description></item><item><title>Survey Visualiser</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/surveyvis/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/surveyvis/</guid><description>I was making a poster for the CAASTRO annual retreat on my BAO work, and realised what it really needed was a nice comparison of the WiggleZ survey compared to other more local surveys, to highlight the redshift depth of WiggleZ in comparison to other surveys of the same period, such as 2dF.
And because I am a stubborn fool, I decided to extend what I did to the general case.</description></item><item><title>ChainConsumer</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/chainconsumer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/chainconsumer/</guid><description>I was working with some chains one day and wanted to plot different cosmologies against each other, and realised that they had different parameters. Unfortunately, this meant that the library I was using couldn&amp;rsquo;t handle the task, so I wrote my own!
If you want to know more and see plenty of examples see the online documentation here.
The API is fairly straightforward I hope, with a simple example shown below.</description></item><item><title>Get Lit; Atlassian Ship-It</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/getlit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/getlit/</guid><description>Thanks to the wonderful Kate Gunn, CAASTRO managed to participated in one of Atlassian&amp;rsquo;s Ship-It hackathons. I joined the team, along with Bonnie, Steven, Anais, Richard to make the CAASTRO counterpart, with Atlassian providing two staff members, Jason and Ivor in case we needed some heavy software lifting done. The project idea and all the initial hard work was put in by Steven - we wanted to create a better way to search for scientific papers, given that Google doesn&amp;rsquo;t work, and NASA&amp;rsquo;s ADS system is a bit&amp;hellip; rough.</description></item><item><title>Detecting Globular Clusters</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/globular/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/globular/</guid><description>In my time over at Gemini in La Serena, I worked on a project to distinguish globular clusters from stars. The globular clusters (GCs) were located in the giant elliptical galaxy Maffei 1, which - whilst being very close to us - requires looking through the middle of our galaxy.
You do not want this.
The dust extinction was through the roof. I used the SDFRED data reduction pipeline to process images from the Subaru telescope, giving me the output image below.</description></item><item><title>WiggleZ 2D BAO</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/bao/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/bao/</guid><description>Shall we just jump right into it? The slightly wiggles you can see around $$k=0.1 \rm{h/Mpc}$$ below, when transformed into a correlation function via the Spherical Hankel transformation, turn into that big peak in the right hand plot. As you may have guessed, said &amp;ldquo;big peak&amp;rdquo; is the oscillation of interest. Put simply, it represents a characteristic separation at which there is an overdensity of matter in the universe. And its of interest because this peak has existed since the first galaxies formed, and so we can use it as a standard ruler.</description></item></channel></rss>