<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>small-author on Samuel Hinton</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tags/small-author/</link><description>Recent content in small-author on Samuel Hinton</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tags/small-author/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Reflections on my own 'Soul Relic'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/soul_relic/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/soul_relic/</guid><description>Born with an enormous well of power but no way to regenerate it, Raysha will risk anything to fix herself, even if it means venturing into the unknown with nothing but her brother, an enchanted water bottle, and a stubborn attitude.
Without the ability to cultivate aeon from the world, Raysha has been treated like an outcast her whole life. While she has to ration her power drop-by-drop, others use it as commonly as breathing.</description></item><item><title>A Review of Tobias Begley's progression fantasy work 'The Enchanter'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/enchanter/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/enchanter/</guid><description>Let&amp;rsquo;s get the obvious out the way and let me expand on the description above. If you&amp;rsquo;ve read the Arcane Ascension series and loved Corin&amp;rsquo;s approach to life, just save yourself some time, click the amazon link above, and go and get this book. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t, but you&amp;rsquo;ve read Mother of Learning and appreciated Zorian there, same comment.
Alright, let&amp;rsquo;s start with a spoiler-free summary. Our MC, Evander Tailor, is gifted.</description></item><item><title>A review of Zamil Akhtar's Lightblade</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/lightblade/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/lightblade/</guid><description>Disclosure: I received this book in advance and without cost in exchange for an honest review. Counter-disclosure: I already pay for KU, so I would have been able to read it for &amp;lsquo;free&amp;rsquo; anyway.
Initially, the premise of this book seemed super intense. Lightblades obviously give you some Star Wars vibes, the magic system is focused around different wavelengths of light, which gives me Lightbringer vibes, and then the focus on dreams, time-dilation, and the existential question &amp;ldquo;Is this the real world&amp;rdquo; combine Inception and the Matrix.</description></item><item><title>A review of K.T. Hanna's 'Somnia Online'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/somnia/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/somnia/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m writing this review as of reading the first three books. I&amp;rsquo;ll update it when I finish the series at a later date.
Somnia Online follows the journey of Wren, her best friend Harlow, and their guild, Fable. The premise, at the start, is simple. Wren&amp;rsquo;s mother is the lead designer for a massive vrmmo game, which offers unparalleled immersive via a headset which reads your brainwaves. Except, of course, the game is really just a test bed for the development for the games AI and the headset technology, which is funded by the military.</description></item><item><title>A Review of Chris Fox's Shattered Gods series. A great new entry into progression fantasy.</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/shattered_gods/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/shattered_gods/</guid><description>In the book, you follow the adventures of Xal. Xal is a child of the dims, an oppressed group of people feared by the ruling class and used as cannon fodder. Xal gets conscripted and sent to tie in the trash legion, and the adventures of this legion, plus the Academy afterwards, show him progressing in power and being inducted into the wider political landscape, wherein he has very few friends and a great many enemies.</description></item><item><title>A Review of Andrew Seiple's Threadbare. Adorable, unique, and fascinating.</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/threadbare/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/threadbare/</guid><description>This review focuses on the trilogy as a whole, not subsequent entries.
I will admit to some skepticism when I read the original premise - the main character is a stuffed bear.
But, in a fit of whimsy, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d give it a shot.
This was, as it turns out, a wonderful decision.
Threadbare follows the journey of the eponymous bear&amp;rsquo;s quest to try and find and save the daughter of his creator and his best friend - Cecelia Gearheart.</description></item><item><title>A review of Michael Nwanolue's 'The Tower Unbroken'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/tower_unbroken/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/tower_unbroken/</guid><description>I do like me a good cultivation story, and so when I asked for some recommendations and someone pointed out that there is a little-known work featuring African-inspired cultivation, I put it to the top of my list.
And here we are!
The Tower Unbroken follows Somadina&amp;rsquo;s journey from his village out into the wider world. He starts off as the lowliest rank of cultivator, or dibias as they are called in this setting.</description></item><item><title>A physicist reviews Dominic Stal's 'The Last Physicist'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/last_physicist/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/last_physicist/</guid><description>For those coming here from reddit or similar, I&amp;rsquo;ll come clean. I had high expectations for this book. As a physicist myself, a book about a physicist using the scientific method to put some hard rules to magic and delve into the mechanics had me almost giddy with excitement. So I dove into this book, and, I&amp;rsquo;ll be frank, came away disappointed.
The book follows the MC, Will. In another fun coincidence, Will works at Fermilab in Chicago.</description></item></channel></rss>