<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>creative on Samuel Hinton</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tags/creative/</link><description>Recent content in creative on Samuel Hinton</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tags/creative/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Neural Style Transfer</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/ducky/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/ducky/</guid><description>I normally suck at giving presents. Horrifically. Probably because I&amp;rsquo;m a nightmare to buy for - I hate useless gifts. Ornaments, decorations&amp;hellip; &amp;ldquo;things&amp;rdquo; which aren&amp;rsquo;t functional.
It&amp;rsquo;s all clutter.
And because I don&amp;rsquo;t like receiving it, I don&amp;rsquo;t give it. Which means the struggle is always for a functional gift. But not this time! My sister has a cat called Ducky. Now, Ducky may not like me very much (breaks my heart), but Ali sure likes Ducky.</description></item><item><title>Hidden Treasure</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/gold/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/gold/</guid><description>With the Keva simulation I made, all the blocks are spaced out with room to move. I was curious to see how Blender&amp;rsquo;s engine would cope when the blocks were tightly packed, so, surprise surprise, I made a group of tightly packed cubes and then threw a glass sphere at them.
I randomised the materials of the cubes to add some spice, and fiddled around with simulation speed to get a slow motion section of the simulation.</description></item><item><title>The Tower of Two Blocks</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/keva/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/keva/</guid><description>Seeing KEVA simulations always makes my day brighter, so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d make a small one myself. This one has a series of very light wood blocks set on top some very heavy metal blocks as the base. Two steel balls are shot at the structure, and if you watch the video you can probably guess which of them is solid and which is simply a thin shell over a hollow interior!</description></item><item><title>Solar System Size Scale</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/planets/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/planets/</guid><description>{% include youtube.html url=&amp;ldquo;https://www.youtube.com/embed/JNPACDLSCTY)
This was a scene in which I learnt a lot, not just about compositing. Lots of fiddling with materials, mapping and textures to get the rocky planets working.
And then even more fiddling for the Gas Giants, to try and get that characteristic atmospheric effect along the boundary of the planet surface.
Setting up Saturn&amp;rsquo;s ring was a pain with the UV mapping, but eventually got it working!</description></item><item><title>Coloured Smoke</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/colorsmoke/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/colorsmoke/</guid><description>So I wanted to see how the soft body physics worked. So alright, lets just drop a ball. But a bouncing ball is boring, so lets squash it completely. And because I could, why not have particles emit when the bottom of the ball impacts and have them shoot out.
And then because that was still dull, what if we tie the velocity of the smoke into its colour, and have it that the more dense the smoke is, the more it glows and emits light.</description></item><item><title>Gas Explosion</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/explosion/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/explosion/</guid><description>It turns out that smoke simulations both take far, far longer than rigid body simulations, but also take up a lot of disk space as well. So I might have accidentally filled my main C drive on which Windows lives and had all sort of complaints come screetching out of the operating systems.
In this sim I was just trying to figure out how the volumetic shaders worked, such that I could get a two stage explosion with thick, greasy smoke.</description></item><item><title>Glowing Galton Board</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/galton/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/galton/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been years since I last tried out 3D modelling and simulations. And given how crushing my PhD workload is at this point in time, I realised I needed something on the side to distract me so that my project didn&amp;rsquo;t consume all of my life.
So, after seeing the constant posts about Blender on Reddits /r/simulated sub, I decided to give it a go. Following the current hot topic (so that if anything went wrong there would be plenty of people able to help out), I decided to go with a classic Galton board simulation.</description></item><item><title>Desert Caves Map</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/map-caves/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/map-caves/</guid><description>Presenting, some desert caves, cave system, lava basin, dubiously engineered bridges, and small encampment! The idea for this one was after climbing down the hole in the previous map you would end up in the top right corner of this map.
Once again, following the style of Mark Bowen&amp;rsquo;s maps over at Blue Sword Games.
So, for this map, here are the outlines and grid versions:
And because the lava is very visually strong, if you want the play area to be more of the focus than the lava, use this image:</description></item><item><title>Desert Camp Map</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/map-camp/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/map-camp/</guid><description>Presenting, a desert camp, with included outcrops, interior cave and hole of mystery!
Once again, following the style of Mark Bowen&amp;rsquo;s maps over at Blue Sword Games, my second desert map.
I decided I wanted the map to have a few potential uses.
Make camp, and be ambused from outside, and use the cave choke point to hold them off. Have creatures ascend from the hole and attack the camp from inside the cave.</description></item><item><title>Desert Canyon Map</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/map-canyon/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/map-canyon/</guid><description>Presenting, a desert canyon, with included creek, small rock pillars, and larger overhanging boulder, for your consideration! Feel free to use it, modify it, whatever you want.
I&amp;rsquo;ve recently been collecting maps for potential use in some upcoming campaign, and I absolutely love the art style of Mark Bowen&amp;rsquo;s maps over at Blue Sword Games.
I highly recommend checking it out!
So I&amp;rsquo;ve been following his map making progress, and decided that - given I want more maps than are available - I should make some to fill in the blanks for the current scaffold.</description></item><item><title>Making Taipan's Logo</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/taipan/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/taipan/</guid><description>I think a good way to not get burnt out coding and doing math 24/7 a day is to do some more creative work to break the monotony.
Or perhaps I am simply bad at saying &amp;ldquo;No!&amp;rdquo;
The moral of the story is that I took over makign the Taipan logo for the Taipan survey. The original art was all done in green, and I thought - given the lack of green colouring in many astronomical surveys, and given the snake is vaguely green(ish brown), sure, sounds good!</description></item><item><title>What is OzDES?</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/ozdes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/ozdes/</guid><description>Sometimes I think I get a big bogged down, lost in a maze of code that I used to be the master of before losing my bearing. At times like this, it is prudent to take a step back, to let the maze untangle itself slowly whilst one focuses on other tasks.
Or at least, that is my excuse for picking up side work. In the latest installment of &amp;ldquo;No, I don&amp;rsquo;t have results from my PhD yet,&amp;rdquo; I present the following post on OzDES, its purpose, goals and how it goes about fulfilling them.</description></item><item><title>Making a utility knife</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/knife/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/knife/</guid><description>For a while now I&amp;rsquo;ve been meaning to see if I can make something a bit more useful than my normal projects, and what could be more useful than a knife? Well, a lot of things, but most things are simply too difficult and require too many tools I don&amp;rsquo;t have!
So, in preparation built a gas forge with tons of help from the guys at QMAC, and then built a simply filing jig to help me out.</description></item><item><title>Making bismuth crystals</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/bismuth/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/bismuth/</guid><description>Josh Calcino and I were in Japan on a holiday recently, and we spent a fair bit of time in some of the larger crystal shops they had in Kyoto - we both collected crystals when we were younger. We saw some beautiful pieces of bismuth, and I came close to buying some.
Instead, we decided to buy some raw bismuth when we got back home and make the crystals ourselves!</description></item><item><title>Making a Moon Mosaic</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/moon/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/moon/</guid><description>I was at the Dark Energy Survey conference in December when I met an overachieving student. Three years in, and already using the telescope at the University of Sussex to do additional projects, including a moon mosaic.
Jessica, the student in question, had never made a mosaic before. Luckily, I had done it once or twice for past work for Gemini, and so I offered to help. Three hundred images I received of the moon.</description></item><item><title>Kubo Oscillator</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/kubo/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/kubo/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ll be honest: this post was made just to show of one of my favourite plots. I&amp;rsquo;ll put it at the end, because without an introduction it really doesn&amp;rsquo;t make too much sense.
Firstly, a terrifying brief (and thus completely inaccurate) introduction to stochastic systems: A stochastic system is one in which the outcome of an individual system is unpredictable due to the effect of randomness.
Brownian motion (the motion of a particle being jostled around by other particles) is the classic example of this.</description></item><item><title>The Most Useless Machine</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/box/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/box/</guid><description>The year before this, I created a thick paper mache wrapper around a present to make it more interesting to unwrap. So in 2011 I decided to do a take on the &amp;ldquo;Most Useless Machine Ever&amp;rdquo; - a box that&amp;rsquo;s sole function is to flip a switch back to its off position when a user flicks it on.
{% include youtube.html url=&amp;ldquo;https://www.youtube.com/embed/2LKnORvwsoI)
Mechanically, this is simple, the flick just needs to be connected to a DC motor switch, such that either side of the switch changes the voltage across the motor.</description></item><item><title>Mood Bottle</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/bottle/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/bottle/</guid><description>The image you see was sourced from a similar Instructibles that I recommend you check out.
Unfortunately, I can find no images of my own creation. It was made in 2011, in the basement of my grandparent&amp;rsquo;s house. The pictures I took were on an old phone, long since gone.
So, I&amp;rsquo;ll simply explain what I did, and hope I can find actual images in the future.
The recipe goes as follows:</description></item><item><title>The Blue Planet</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/planet/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/planet/</guid><description>I created this image using a ton of brushes, layers, stacking and this texture.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Strike</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/lightning/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/lightning/</guid><description>This photoshop challenge was for me to try and figure out the basics of photomanipulation. I started with a bunch of images and textures, and turned them into what you see below.
Stocks sourced from
Water Outcrop Lightning Clouds Clouds Clouds Tower</description></item></channel></rss>