<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>female-lead on Samuel Hinton</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tags/female-lead/</link><description>Recent content in female-lead on Samuel Hinton</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tags/female-lead/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Reflections on my own 'Soul Relic'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/soul_relic/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/soul_relic/</guid><description>Born with an enormous well of power but no way to regenerate it, Raysha will risk anything to fix herself, even if it means venturing into the unknown with nothing but her brother, an enchanted water bottle, and a stubborn attitude.
Without the ability to cultivate aeon from the world, Raysha has been treated like an outcast her whole life. While she has to ration her power drop-by-drop, others use it as commonly as breathing.</description></item><item><title>A review of Naomi Novik's Scholomance Series</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/scholomance/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/scholomance/</guid><description>I didn&amp;rsquo;t expect to read a book from the perspective of an emotional teenage girl and love every page.
And yet, here we are.
So, premise time. In this world, there are magical people, and not magical people (they&amp;rsquo;re not called muggles though). Raising a magical kid is hard, because there are a whole host of creatures, called maleficaria (or mals) which love that sweet mana inside the kids, and will eat them all up.</description></item><item><title>A review of Rhaegar's 'Azarinth Healer'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/azarinth_healer/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/azarinth_healer/</guid><description>Blurb Ilea likes punching things. And eating.
Unfortunately, there aren’t too many career options for hungry brawlers. Instead, the plan is to quit her crappy fast-food job, go to college, and become a fully functioning member of society. Essentially - a fate worse than death.
So maybe it&amp;rsquo;s lucky that she wakes up one day in a strange world where a bunch of fantasy monsters are trying to kill her&amp;hellip;?</description></item><item><title>A review of RavensDagger's 'Cinnamon Bun'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/cinnamon_bun/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/cinnamon_bun/</guid><description>As readers of this genre know, LitRPG worlds can be a depressing, harrowing, and cut-throat place. Half of the MC&amp;rsquo;s I&amp;rsquo;ve read in other works get ahead because this suits them just fine. They&amp;rsquo;re happy to fight, happy to get their hands dirty, happy to shake the system up. In many ways, that&amp;rsquo;s part of the escapism. Having power.
Cinnamon Bun has a slightly different take. The world is less apocalyptic in fashion, and our main character, Broccoli Bunch, just wants to go on cool adventures and make friends.</description></item><item><title>A review of J.L. Mullins' 'Millenial Mage'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/millenial_mage/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/millenial_mage/</guid><description>As of writing this review, I&amp;rsquo;ve read all 224 published chapters.
Blurb The world is wild, untamed. Humanity thrives, but only in isolated, well defended cities, ever shrinking as the wilds slowly reclaim all that was taken. The most capable magic users are raised up as Mages to serve mankind, further their cause, and defend them over the course of millennia.
Tala is freshly graduated from the magic academy and determined to make her own way in the world.</description></item><item><title>A review of K.T. Hanna's 'Somnia Online'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/somnia/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/somnia/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m writing this review as of reading the first three books. I&amp;rsquo;ll update it when I finish the series at a later date.
Somnia Online follows the journey of Wren, her best friend Harlow, and their guild, Fable. The premise, at the start, is simple. Wren&amp;rsquo;s mother is the lead designer for a massive vrmmo game, which offers unparalleled immersive via a headset which reads your brainwaves. Except, of course, the game is really just a test bed for the development for the games AI and the headset technology, which is funded by the military.</description></item><item><title>A Review of Sarah Lin's The Brightest Shadow - great subversion of a genre trope.</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/brightest_shadow/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/brightest_shadow/</guid><description>Disclaimer: the thoughts in this review come from reading only the first book of the series. I have not read &amp;lsquo;A Hollow Mountain&amp;rsquo;, yet.
I enjoyed the read of The Brightest Shadow a few weeks ago during my end of year holiday. I&amp;rsquo;d been slowly making my way through the novel for a month or so before that, as I initially struggled with the slower pacing of the work. In that way, it reminds me a lot of A Thousand Li (in that I struggled with the slice-of-life plodding along).</description></item><item><title>A Review of Yrsillar's Forge of Destiny</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/forge_of_destiny/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/forge_of_destiny/</guid><description>Forge of Destiny starts like many cultivation novels. Plucky young girl from the streets, Ling Qi, has the talent and joins the Sect of Argent Peak. She then struggles to rise up in the inner rankings of the Sect. It has your normal progression systems, spiritual pills, removing impurities, it has moves and techniques, a vide cast of characters, but at the end of the day I wasn&amp;rsquo;t drawn in.</description></item></channel></rss>