<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>plotting on Samuel Hinton</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tags/plotting/</link><description>Recent content in plotting on Samuel Hinton</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tags/plotting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>RoyalRoad Data Infographic</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tutorials/royalroad/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tutorials/royalroad/</guid><description>For those reading this, I assume you know what Royal Road is. For those may have misclicked: it&amp;rsquo;s a website where authors publish web serials, generally a chapter at a time, and generally at a freakishly fast pace (like one chapter a day). It&amp;rsquo;s home to many greats in the Progression Fantasy / LitRPG genre, and I have spent hundreds of hours as a consumer of these serials.
So I decided to try and extract some insights from Royal Road data about how page count, followers, ratings, etc, impact the serials success and patreon conversion.</description></item><item><title>Visualising Patient Contributions for the CCCC</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tutorials/cccc_institutions/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tutorials/cccc_institutions/</guid><description>The COVID-19 Critical Care Consortium is an international collaboration of hundreds of hospital sites from dozens of countries around the world. Our sites have been slowly but steadily gathering data for critical cases of COVID-19 since earlier in the year, and we thought it would be good to show just how international the collaboration is.
To that end, in my role as one of the technical leads (responsible for the data pipeline and ingestion), I created out a simple (and no-risk) data product simply containing a list of our participant sites, and how many patients they have enrolled in our study at a given date.</description></item><item><title>Gource - Visualisating Code Contributions</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tutorials/gource/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tutorials/gource/</guid><description>What is Gource? Gource is a way of visualising your git log, showing users and their contributions creating, modifying and deleting files. When run on my repository that was published under the name &amp;ldquo;Steve&amp;rdquo; (a Hierarchical Bayesian model for supernova cosmology&amp;quot;) and then piped through ffmpeg, this is what we get:
Using gource Its super easy, head to the gource website here and download the version for your operating system.</description></item><item><title>Evolution of US COVID-19 cases</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tutorials/us_covid_evolution/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tutorials/us_covid_evolution/</guid><description>This plot was first inspired by this absolute masterpiece of a visualisation. I was chatting with David Morton about how much work it must have taken (coding up textures, exporting to blender, creating the model, rendering, compositing, loading back into code, annotating, so much work). David then went and created a python only version of the plot, and I decided I&amp;rsquo;d give it a crack too. We&amp;rsquo;ve used the same data, but the transformations, plotting and output are all different.</description></item><item><title>Which Big City has the best Weather?</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tutorials/us_weather/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tutorials/us_weather/</guid><description>Like many people, I might one day be moving to the United States for work. However, I would like to know where I should move too. Where is too hot? Where is it too wet? Where is my little slice of paradise??
This is what we&amp;rsquo;ll be making:
So using the NOAA Global Summary of the Day and the top 25 most populated cities in the US, we&amp;rsquo;ve got enough to make a plot.</description></item><item><title>Plotting US COVID-19 Incidence</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tutorials/us_covid19_growth/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tutorials/us_covid19_growth/</guid><description>One of my favourite subreddits is /r/dataisbeautiful. Today I saw a plot from that sub that was, on first glimpse, beautiful! And full credit to the author for getting the data and presenting it beautifully. However, I had some small issues with it. The first was that it was smoothing over a cumulative window (instead of showing what I think people expect, which is how many people caught COVID-19 on those dates).</description></item><item><title>Visualising with Basemap</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tutorials/desinstitutions/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tutorials/desinstitutions/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m scheduled to give a talk for the Dark Energy Survey - a massive collection of researchers, engineers and institutions working together to try and constrain the nature of Dark Energy. To help give my presentations some pizzaz, I thought it would be nice to visualise the spread of institutions around the world that makes DES the wonderful organisation that it is.
Wheres the data Unfortunately&amp;hellip; I had to collect it by hand.</description></item></channel></rss>