<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>magic-school on Samuel Hinton</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tags/magic-school/</link><description>Recent content in magic-school on Samuel Hinton</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tags/magic-school/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Review of nobody13's Mother of Learning. Time loops with a smart protagonist, done so very, very right.</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/mother_of_learning/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/mother_of_learning/</guid><description>I grew up on the Belgariad, graduated through Harry Potter to the Wheel of Time, conquered Malazan, was crushed by the Farseer Trilogy, and generally docked my ship at every fantasy port I could find.
Then I was recommended to read Mother of Learning. It was my first serial novel. And despite its 800k words, I read it in a week.
And then I read it again.
So many books I&amp;rsquo;ve read fumble the ending or the rising tension.</description></item><item><title>A Review of Bryce O'Connor's Iron Prince. Scifi progression on actual digital steroids."</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/iron_prince/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/iron_prince/</guid><description>I normally approach scifi with skepticism. I studied astrophysics, and physics is a harsh mistress that is all to easy to try and abuse in works of science fiction. There&amp;rsquo;s one surefire way around this - magical tech. Or in this case, alien tech that is so advanced it might as well be magic. And with the soft scifi setting established, this allows Bryce to draw the best from fantasy, the best from LitRPG levelling, and combine them to make one of the best progression fantasy stories I have read in years.</description></item><item><title>A Review of Andrew Rowe's Arcane Ascension Series: hard magic done right</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/arcane_ascension/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/arcane_ascension/</guid><description>My rating is for the series as a whole as of writing. It&amp;rsquo;s amazing. I&amp;rsquo;ll make sure this review focuses on Book One: Sufficiently Advanced Magic.
Corin Cadence is one of my favourite main characters in all of fantasy. He is, as I image many of us think, how we would approach being a person in a magical world. Analytically. Carefully. Exploitively.
So here&amp;rsquo;s the plot - you get powers (attunements) ostensibly from the goddess, via blessings you receive in the spires.</description></item><item><title>A Review of Phil Tucker's Bastion. It's great.</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/bastion/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/bastion/</guid><description>Many progression fantasy series start with a similar pattern. An unfortunate, downtrodden, or unlucky individual is wronged, usually in an academic or sect environment, and then they claw their way through the classes, pushing themselves into excellence.
Bastion opens similarly, and I was preparing myself for a bit of &amp;lsquo;more of the same&amp;rsquo;. When the Chancellor starts explaining a points system for Academic progression through the Gauntlet (aka dungeon / spire / magical testing realm) a spark of worry lit inside me.</description></item><item><title>A Review of John Bierce's Mage Errant Series. A fun ride with a likeable cast.</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/mage_errant/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/mage_errant/</guid><description>This review focuses on first volume. As of writing I&amp;rsquo;ve read all five released books and those flavour my opinion.
Hugh of Emblin is both a horrific and talented student at Skyhold Academy.
He is anxious, I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure he is depressed, and ultimately he is just not vibing about the state of the world and his own abilities.
Luckily, he has some great friends to help pick him up and support him.</description></item><item><title>A review of J.M. Clarke's 'Mark of the Fool'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/mark_of_the_fool/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/mark_of_the_fool/</guid><description>As of writing this review, I have read the KU release and up to chapter 200, which is about half-way through the available chapters.
So here&amp;rsquo;s the premise: Alex Roth is one of five chosen Heroes that need to defeat a reoccurring villain: The Ravener. Alex, however, is the Fool. His Mark, instead of making him a combat savant, powerful spellcaster, etc, makes him really great at learning things that are outside of combat and spellcasting&amp;hellip; but will actively interfere with his abilities if they are not.</description></item><item><title>A review of Naomi Novik's Scholomance Series</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/scholomance/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/scholomance/</guid><description>I didn&amp;rsquo;t expect to read a book from the perspective of an emotional teenage girl and love every page.
And yet, here we are.
So, premise time. In this world, there are magical people, and not magical people (they&amp;rsquo;re not called muggles though). Raising a magical kid is hard, because there are a whole host of creatures, called maleficaria (or mals) which love that sweet mana inside the kids, and will eat them all up.</description></item><item><title>A Review of Selkie Myth's series 'Beneath the Dragoneye Moons'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/beneath_the_dragons_eye_moons/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/beneath_the_dragons_eye_moons/</guid><description>As of writing this review, I&amp;rsquo;ve read everything published, which is books one through to nine in the series.
Blurb Elaine is ripped from this world to Pallos, a land of unlimited possibilities made real by a grand System governing classes, skills, and magic.
An ideal society? What is this, a fantasy novel?
Adventures? Right this way!
A Grand quest? Nah.
Friends and loot? Heck yes!
Humans are the top dog?</description></item><item><title>A review of Rob J. Hayes' 'Titan Hoppers'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/titan_hoppers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/titan_hoppers/</guid><description>Blurb Courage Iro will shatter the Gates of Power to protect his fleet.
Born talentless, Iro has all but resigned himself to a life of drudgery, watching his sister hop across to the massive space titan for supplies. But when the titan explodes and his sister is killed, Iro finds a new determination to take her place. He’s not about to let weakness prevent him.
When the fleet encounters a new titan, filled with powerful monsters, deadly traps, and mysterious cloaked figures, Iro is the first to spontaneously manifest a new talent.</description></item><item><title>A Review of Actus' 'My Best Friend is an Eldritch Horror.'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/best_friend_eldritch_horror/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/best_friend_eldritch_horror/</guid><description>As of writing this review, I&amp;rsquo;ve read all three published books in the series.
Blurb Damien nearly ended the world. Now, his mistake might be the only thing that can save it.
Good things come to those who wait. Damien Vale didn’t, and he ended up bound to an Eldritch creature from beyond the reaches of space. It has lived since the dawn of time, seen the world born and destroyed countless times, and wants to be called Henry.</description></item><item><title>A review of Alec Huston's 'Umbral Storm'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/umbral_storm/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/umbral_storm/</guid><description>Blurb A thousand years ago the Heart of the World was shattered, its fragments scattered across the lands. In the chaos that followed, martial orders arose to gather these shards, for it was found that great powers were granted when these pieces were bonded to the flesh of the chosen. These are the Sharded Few, warriors imbued with the divine energies that once coursed through the Heart, and driven to absorb enough fragments to claim godhood.</description></item><item><title>A Review of Tobias Begley's progression fantasy work 'The Enchanter'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/enchanter/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/enchanter/</guid><description>Let&amp;rsquo;s get the obvious out the way and let me expand on the description above. If you&amp;rsquo;ve read the Arcane Ascension series and loved Corin&amp;rsquo;s approach to life, just save yourself some time, click the amazon link above, and go and get this book. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t, but you&amp;rsquo;ve read Mother of Learning and appreciated Zorian there, same comment.
Alright, let&amp;rsquo;s start with a spoiler-free summary. Our MC, Evander Tailor, is gifted.</description></item><item><title>A review of Davis Ashura's 'The Eternal Ephemera'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/eternal_ephemera/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/eternal_ephemera/</guid><description>As of writing this review, I have read Blood of a Novice, and received a copy as an ARC reader.
Blurb Cam Folde will shake the very fabric of creation&amp;hellip; or see all his hopes turn to ash.
The son of the town drunk, Cam never figured on letting his family name hold him down. He always strove to dream bigger, to fight for something better, to achieve more than what everyone else expected of him.</description></item><item><title>A Review of Chris Fox's Shattered Gods series. A great new entry into progression fantasy.</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/shattered_gods/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/shattered_gods/</guid><description>In the book, you follow the adventures of Xal. Xal is a child of the dims, an oppressed group of people feared by the ruling class and used as cannon fodder. Xal gets conscripted and sent to tie in the trash legion, and the adventures of this legion, plus the Academy afterwards, show him progressing in power and being inducted into the wider political landscape, wherein he has very few friends and a great many enemies.</description></item><item><title>A review of Michael G. Manning's 'Art of the Adept'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/art_of_the_adept/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/art_of_the_adept/</guid><description>What a roller coaster this read was. Our plot follows Will, who awakens his magic when healing a young boys infection. He is sent to live with his grandfather (of sorts), who becomes a slow and painful magical tutelage, laced with acerbic dialogue and insults around every corner. The dynamic between the two is a joy to read. Eventually, the plot moves on, Will has to spread his wings. As to why, and when, and how, I won&amp;rsquo;t say, because it all falls under spoiler territory.</description></item><item><title>A Review of Yrsillar's Forge of Destiny</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/forge_of_destiny/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/forge_of_destiny/</guid><description>Forge of Destiny starts like many cultivation novels. Plucky young girl from the streets, Ling Qi, has the talent and joins the Sect of Argent Peak. She then struggles to rise up in the inner rankings of the Sect. It has your normal progression systems, spiritual pills, removing impurities, it has moves and techniques, a vide cast of characters, but at the end of the day I wasn&amp;rsquo;t drawn in.</description></item><item><title>Tao Wong's A Thousand Li - classical cultivation doled out sparingly</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/thousand_li/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/thousand_li/</guid><description>Disclaimer: Due to Tao Wong filing infringement notices against LitRPG authors for using &amp;ldquo;System&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Apocalypse&amp;rdquo;, I&amp;rsquo;m not continuing with this series. There are plenty of authors who add positively to this community that I can support instead of someone who tries to tear it down.
I had heard great things about this series, and A Thousand Li is a staple on the cultivation and progression fantasy reading lists. So take this review with a grain of salt, that obviously my take here may not be reflective of the wider community.</description></item></channel></rss>