<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>finished on Samuel Hinton</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tags/finished/</link><description>Recent content in finished on Samuel Hinton</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tags/finished/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Review of nobody13's Mother of Learning. Time loops with a smart protagonist, done so very, very right.</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/mother_of_learning/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/mother_of_learning/</guid><description>I grew up on the Belgariad, graduated through Harry Potter to the Wheel of Time, conquered Malazan, was crushed by the Farseer Trilogy, and generally docked my ship at every fantasy port I could find.
Then I was recommended to read Mother of Learning. It was my first serial novel. And despite its 800k words, I read it in a week.
And then I read it again.
So many books I&amp;rsquo;ve read fumble the ending or the rising tension.</description></item><item><title>A review of Naomi Novik's Scholomance Series</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/scholomance/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/scholomance/</guid><description>I didn&amp;rsquo;t expect to read a book from the perspective of an emotional teenage girl and love every page.
And yet, here we are.
So, premise time. In this world, there are magical people, and not magical people (they&amp;rsquo;re not called muggles though). Raising a magical kid is hard, because there are a whole host of creatures, called maleficaria (or mals) which love that sweet mana inside the kids, and will eat them all up.</description></item><item><title>A Review of Andrew Rowes's How to Defeat a Demon King in Ten Easy Steps. Hilarious love letter to Zelda.</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/how_to_defeat_a_demon_king_in_ten_easy_steps/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/how_to_defeat_a_demon_king_in_ten_easy_steps/</guid><description>Let&amp;rsquo;s preface this real quick: this book is a short and fun read. It is not a sweeping fantasy series, it is not a classic zero-to-hero progression fantasy. It is a love letter to Zelda and other games, making fun of many video game tropes by highlighting just how ridiculous and obvious many are.
The main character finds a way to inventively use their class (A Bag Mage) to break various game systems.</description></item><item><title>A review of Maxime J. Durand's 'The Perfect Run'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/perfect_run/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/perfect_run/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a quite a few years since the Alchemist distributed Elixirs into the world, each which grant a unique super power. Since then, modern civilisation has collapsed, because giving some people phenomenal power tends to go badly a lot of the time. Quicksave begins the book searching for his childhood friend, Len, and determined to go through every chapter in his life with a perfect run. Which, as you might have guessed from the hero name, is possible thanks to his ability to set a checkpoint in time he can revert to on death.</description></item><item><title>A review of Michael G. Manning's 'Art of the Adept'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/art_of_the_adept/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/art_of_the_adept/</guid><description>What a roller coaster this read was. Our plot follows Will, who awakens his magic when healing a young boys infection. He is sent to live with his grandfather (of sorts), who becomes a slow and painful magical tutelage, laced with acerbic dialogue and insults around every corner. The dynamic between the two is a joy to read. Eventually, the plot moves on, Will has to spread his wings. As to why, and when, and how, I won&amp;rsquo;t say, because it all falls under spoiler territory.</description></item><item><title>A review of Momo's 'Martial Peak'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/martial_peak/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/martial_peak/</guid><description>As of writing this review, I have read &amp;gt;1500 chapters of the manhua.
Blurb The journey to the martial peak is a lonely, solitary and long one. In the face of adversity, you must survive and remain unyielding. Only then can you break through and continue on your journey to become the strongest. Sky Tower tests its disciples in the harshest ways to prepare them for this journey. One day the lowly sweeper Yang Kai managed to obtain a black book, setting him on the road to the peak of the martial world.</description></item><item><title>A review of K.T. Hanna's 'Somnia Online'</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/somnia/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/somnia/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m writing this review as of reading the first three books. I&amp;rsquo;ll update it when I finish the series at a later date.
Somnia Online follows the journey of Wren, her best friend Harlow, and their guild, Fable. The premise, at the start, is simple. Wren&amp;rsquo;s mother is the lead designer for a massive vrmmo game, which offers unparalleled immersive via a headset which reads your brainwaves. Except, of course, the game is really just a test bed for the development for the games AI and the headset technology, which is funded by the military.</description></item><item><title>A Review of Dakota Krout's Divine Dungeon Series.</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/divine_dungeon/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/divine_dungeon/</guid><description>This is another series I&amp;rsquo;ve read which I got instantly hooked on with a great premise, only to feel a bit let down at the conclusion many books later.
That said, I&amp;rsquo;ve read this series more than once, so it must be doing something right!
The Divine Dungeon series was my introduction to dungeon-core novels, and for that, I thank you, Dakota Krout. What this means is you follow the development of a sentient dungeon rather than a human character for most of the series.</description></item><item><title>A Review of Andrew Seiple's Threadbare. Adorable, unique, and fascinating.</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/threadbare/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/threadbare/</guid><description>This review focuses on the trilogy as a whole, not subsequent entries.
I will admit to some skepticism when I read the original premise - the main character is a stuffed bear.
But, in a fit of whimsy, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d give it a shot.
This was, as it turns out, a wonderful decision.
Threadbare follows the journey of the eponymous bear&amp;rsquo;s quest to try and find and save the daughter of his creator and his best friend - Cecelia Gearheart.</description></item><item><title>A Review of Chugong's Solo Levelling - an engaging take on the genre.</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/solo_levelling/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/solo_levelling/</guid><description>Note: this review is based off the novel. I have heard the manhua doesn&amp;rsquo;t have many of the issues I&amp;rsquo;ve pointed out and recommend reading that instead.
Here&amp;rsquo;s the rough premise of Solo Levelling. The world was all normal, but now dungeon gates open, and teams of hunters have to enter, clear the dungeon and kill its boss. This will ensure the gates close. If they don&amp;rsquo;t close it in a week, the dungeon monsters can escape.</description></item><item><title>A Review of Brent Weeks' Lightbringer Series. Such a promising beginning with such an awful ending.</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/lightbringer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/reviews/lightbringer/</guid><description>This review will have some light spoilers.
The first three books of this series were amazing. Watching Kip, our main character, be bought from his destroyed village to the Chromeria, train with the Blackguard, develop his chromaturgy fantastic. Watching Gavin* build the Brightwater Wall in the face of the oncoming army of the Color Prince, gripping. Koios White Oak and her growth out of the Blackguard, superb.
The world-building was unique, deep enough to engage, but simple enough to grasp quickly.</description></item></channel></rss>