<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>project on Samuel Hinton</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tags/project/</link><description>Recent content in project on Samuel Hinton</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cosmiccoding.com.au/tags/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Barry: BAO Model Comparison</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/barry/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/barry/</guid><description>BAO models are a dime a dozen these days. With multiple theroetical frameworks to start from (standard perturbation theory, Lagranian perturbation theory, effective field theory, etc), and with different models implemented to account for different physical effects, the phase space of viable BAO models is huge.
And this poses a problem for those of us wanting to utilise BAO models. How do we effectively compare them and their performance on a robust set of numerical simulations?</description></item><item><title>Space Birthdays</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/spacebirthdays/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/spacebirthdays/</guid><description>Click here to demo it. The Python in Astronomy 2019 conference was I think the best I&amp;rsquo;ve ever been to. Not because of the food or location, but because of the &amp;lsquo;unconference&amp;rsquo; sessions and the hacking that we get to do.
I wandered around during a lot of the hacks, spread between the code review hack, the MCMC exploration hack, attempting to get PRISM to run, and then also working with a group on getting a website to look at your space birthdays.</description></item><item><title>Steve: A model for supernova cosmology</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/steve/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/steve/</guid><description>As surveys discover greater numbers of supernova, our analyses become limited by systematics rather than data. Hierarchical Bayesian models are perfect for incorporating subtle effects into our model, and so I made one to do just that.
Supernova cosmology works because Type Ia supernova represent standardisable candles. That is, with a few factors taken into account, they are essentially all the same brightness. Which means, if we see two supernovae, and one is four times dimmer than the other, it must be twice as far away.</description></item><item><title>Refractorium</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/refractorium/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/refractorium/</guid><description>Click here to run the simulator in your browser. I was browsing Reddit&amp;rsquo;s Simulated subreddit one afternoon and came across a nice GPU voxel fluid animation. Whilst reading up how it was engineered, I stumbled onto a project by Benedikt Bitterli called Tantalum.
It was a GPU accelerated 2D light transport simulator, and I spent at least an hour playing around with it and producing some beautiful caustics. But with Tantalum, you can only control the position and angle of the light source - the rest of the scene was static.</description></item><item><title>Survey Visualiser</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/surveyvis/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/surveyvis/</guid><description>I was making a poster for the CAASTRO annual retreat on my BAO work, and realised what it really needed was a nice comparison of the WiggleZ survey compared to other more local surveys, to highlight the redshift depth of WiggleZ in comparison to other surveys of the same period, such as 2dF.
And because I am a stubborn fool, I decided to extend what I did to the general case.</description></item><item><title>ChainConsumer</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/chainconsumer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/chainconsumer/</guid><description>I was working with some chains one day and wanted to plot different cosmologies against each other, and realised that they had different parameters. Unfortunately, this meant that the library I was using couldn&amp;rsquo;t handle the task, so I wrote my own!
If you want to know more and see plenty of examples see the online documentation here.
The API is fairly straightforward I hope, with a simple example shown below.</description></item><item><title>Detecting Globular Clusters</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/globular/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/globular/</guid><description>In my time over at Gemini in La Serena, I worked on a project to distinguish globular clusters from stars. The globular clusters (GCs) were located in the giant elliptical galaxy Maffei 1, which - whilst being very close to us - requires looking through the middle of our galaxy.
You do not want this.
The dust extinction was through the roof. I used the SDFRED data reduction pipeline to process images from the Subaru telescope, giving me the output image below.</description></item><item><title>WiggleZ 2D BAO</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/bao/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/bao/</guid><description>Shall we just jump right into it? The slightly wiggles you can see around $$k=0.1 \rm{h/Mpc}$$ below, when transformed into a correlation function via the Spherical Hankel transformation, turn into that big peak in the right hand plot. As you may have guessed, said &amp;ldquo;big peak&amp;rdquo; is the oscillation of interest. Put simply, it represents a characteristic separation at which there is an overdensity of matter in the universe. And its of interest because this peak has existed since the first galaxies formed, and so we can use it as a standard ruler.</description></item><item><title>Marz</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/marz/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/marz/</guid><description>Marz was a program I first started coding for my undergraduate software engineering thesis. The OzDES team was spending too much time manually redshifting spectra and wanted some improvements to the workflow done. I could either improve Runz (the software used at the time), or create something from scratch.
Guess which one I picked?
After lots of work, hassle and one side arguments with my computer, I managed to actually get something usable!</description></item><item><title>DJ Board</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/dj/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/dj/</guid><description>My first team project was to make a pseudo-satellite. Two years later, better equipped, I was hoping the second project would be to built the rocket. Instead, we got a DJ board. People said I had unrealistically high expectations.
Maybe so.
The challenge of the DJ board was not conceptual, it was to be able to do it all on the tiny processor they gave us, which had essentially no memory.</description></item><item><title>Laser Satellite</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/satellite/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/satellite/</guid><description>This was my first proper team project. Myself, Jeevan, Kiaran and David, tasked to built a device which, whilst suspended from a single thin wire, would be able to detected infrared sources, target them, and then fire a laser back at them to hit a bullseye underneath.
In other words, an awesome project.
Like all good satellites, you try and keep mechanical design simple. Less moving parts means less points of failure.</description></item><item><title>Computer Case</title><link>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/computer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cosmiccoding.com.au/blogs/computer/</guid><description>Every now and then, when I think work may be lulling, I try and pick this hobby back up.
And every single time I finish refamiliarising myself with 3DS, sometimes crops up, and I don&amp;rsquo;t come back to it for a year.
Here is the last time I managed to get something properly tangible. From 2009 I believe. The original files are long lost to computer failure. All that is left are these images, rendered out quickly at low resolution abut three quarters of the way through the design.</description></item></channel></rss>